THREE WISHES FOR
CINDERELLA
You put that back!
Of course...
Cinderella!
And the King will arrive
any minute!
Hurry up,
you slow-coaches!
Wait!
The King will arrive any minute
and nothing is prepared.
Hurry up!
What will the King think about us.
Don't soil your slippers,
and mind
you don't catch cold!
Pick it up and get out!
I don't know why I keep you!
Good boy.
I've brought you some sugar.
It's only three years
since daddy gave you to me!
I'd just love to take you
on a ride again,
but you know we are not allowed.
Everybody is excited,
they're expecting the King.
I'll come again
when I've finished my work.
Are they coming?
Hänschen!
Can you see them?
No!
Not a soul to be seen, madam!
Come and tell me as soon as
they appear below the forest!
Cinderella again, I bet!
You'll be the death of me,
silly fool!
Who did it?
The dish was cracked anyway, ma'am.
You' re not answering
my question!
It was I, mother,
please forgive me!
Rosi, everything prepared?
The meat, yes...
Chicken, wine, fruit...
Yes, madam, everything.
To please such guests
is quite a problem.
So see you don't spoil
anything.
I really don't know
if you' re so clumsy
or if you do it on purpose.
Some legacy your father left
me in you...
Like father like...
You leave daddy alone!
He has left you the whole farm!
How dare you speak to me
like that!
Did you hear that?
Kindly remember!
Gone are the times your father
took you to the forest,
riding and shooting
like a boy!
I am the mistress here now...
And keep away from that horse!
Give it to me!
Pick them apart by lunch-time
and then come and apologize!
I'll bring you down
a peg or two!
And woe betide you
if I catch sight of you
when the King is here!
Don't get all upset,
that's just grimy Cinderella!
Thanks, Cinderella...
I'll help you!
And leave me here alone?
Well, my girl, a step-mother is
always a step-mother...
But her Dora wasn't Daddy's,
and he loved her!
Dear friends...
The peas onto the basket,
the ashes into the pail...
...how good of you!
Looking for a lick, Pussy?
No, you can't go in now!
Can you manage than much?
Of course you can!
The gentry not arrived yet, Cinderella?
How did you know it is me?
I didn't, but Nikolaus did.
Knows you a mile off...
Why aren't you watching out
for royalty with the others?
I'm not to...
And I prefer being here anyway.
Not even curious to see the Prince?
I saw him last year...
When they stopped on the way
to the castle.
And did you like him?
Nikolaus is my favourite...
They' re coming!
Here they are!
Be good, children!
Everything all right, Dora dear?
Mind you show me the Prince!
Where are you off to, Silly-Billy?
You little poacher!
Go and welcome the King!
You know ve can't go hunting any more!
Nikolaus and I'll be right
back, sorun along!
Rosie!
Looking after my treasures?!
Nikolaus is calling me...
We have so little time, you see!
Quickly...
Bow low, and don't forget-smile!
All the time!
Where is the Prince, tutor?
And Carl and Willi?
I don't know, your Highness.
I was giving them a lecture
on elegant manners,
and in the forest
the gentleman disappeared...
Find them!
And blame them!
Wait I'll blame them myself!
Are your shooting skills gone?
Look...
Follow her...
There!
Let us surround her.
I will go this way, you take the right.
And you take the left.
Is that her?
There's none other here!
This is just a girl!
A fluffy chicken.
Look, she has claws!
Needs some klapps on her ass,
if you ask me!
That's what she can have!
None of that.
Stupid boys!
We will get you,
you cheeky girl!
You will not get me so easily.
Men!
Jump off, he'll throw you!
She'll break her neck!
This will come to a bad end.
Crazy girl!
We must find her!
Go back to your master!
Such a wildcat!
She deserves beating.
More a medal, gentlemen!
For putting one over on us!
Your Highness...
Your studies, Highness!
I can hardly express
how we looked forward
to your coming -
and her Highness the Queen
and also his Highness, the Prince...
and the whole entourage, and so on.
We thank you.
Dear Dora her could hardly sleep...
The Prince is not with you this time?
Oh yes...
Nature studies have detained
him on the way...
Pity...
All year we looked forward
to your stopping here
on the way to the castle.
I even had a dream...
that your royal Highness
invited us to the ball...
Dora and myself...
That your Highness smiled
at Dora and said:
Do come, my dear,
we shall be pleased to see you.
We shall be pleased to see you.
Our pleasure...
Thank you for the refreshment.
Yes, yes...
On our way!
This is an inexpressible honour for us!
That's in the bag...
And who knows, amongst all
those noblemen
someone might notice you...
Maybe even the Prince himself!
Why not?
Carrying on like a little boy!
At your age I was...
...carrying the burdens
of a ruler!
You'll come down a peg or two
when we get you married!
That's tamed other rebels!
I honour your experience...
Hadn't we better talk this over at home?
I hoped you would devote yourselves
to the study of diplomacy and
court etiquette...
We try not to waste a minute!
But studies are a demanding business!
Where have you left your tutor?
He must have wandered off again...
Stop!
Are those just threats
or does he really want me to marry?
This time he really means it.
A roll of fine line, gold thread,
velvet, thirty ells, in dark blue...
I don't want velvet,
I want satin!
The velvet is for me, Dora.
And forty ells of the best
satin in sky blue.
That's not enough.
Get fifty, then.
Oh, and wide gold braid.
And silver buckles for my
slippers!
Tell the dressmaker you'll
fetch her day after tomorrow.
Don't forget anything!
Yes.
Cinderella, you'll freeze!
Did the mistress make you...
Who else?
And what shall I get you in town?
A tiara and pearls and
a robe with a train!
I can just see them both persuading me
to go to the ball with them...
Surely you wouldn't cry for that...
If I could, I'd bring you
whatever you wished...
Honestly, I would...
Well then bring me the first thing,
that hits you on the nose!
All right, then!
The Lady at Sparrow accepted
our invitation?
Indeed, the messenger has just arrived!
And the Princess of Rosestone?
Definitely coming with both daughters,
Miss Liza and Miss Loulou.
The younger one's
at least thirty!
She is a year younger
than you, and very sweet!
Which you are not!
And the Baron's widow
from Krakau?
She promised to bring
all three daughters.
I thought it was to be a ball,
but this looks more like a man-hunt!
Your impertinence is unseemly!
I apologize for my frankness,
but I was brought up to speak
the truth.
May I leave?
You'll first hear me out!
I had no idea the family
council would take so long.
The tutor and my friends
are waiting,
may I dismiss them?
What was so important...?
We were to study history...
then I was to have suffered
a lesson in etiquette and
witty conversation...
History? Conversation?
Aren't you shooting fun of me?
Shoot-fun-how could I?
Here you are...
Horses away...!
Why the cross-bows, then?
Call that study?
Of course he doesn't want to
marry,
fooling round on a horse
all day with cross bows!
Horse and cross-bows?
How's that?
Come and see!
Gentlemen, I'm responsible
for you,
your studies,
state interests
I don't understand...
Don't forget to practice
dance-steps,
so you don't
cut a sorry figure!
Remember, I at your age...
...danced through three pairs
of slippers at a ball!
Really?
Before we mer, of course...
But you apologized that
it was the first time
you were dancing,
when you trod on my feet.
That is nothing to brag of to a son...
My dear, he takes after you...
in all the important things!
No!
Yes!
After the dancing lesson,
some conversation!
Ah, conversation...
Your Highness,
I have decided, that you will ask for
my hand in marriage.
Do you agree?
No, my beautiful Countess.
I honour your ancien family
and your great beauty,
but my heart belongs forever
to hunting, shooting and riding.
So the wedding-is no go.
Or as the poet says:
No rain from that cloud!
Or as that kid said:
When the cows come home!
Look...
Gentlemen!
We' re off!
What about your studies?!
My dear girl,
I nearly forgot!
Like a spider's web...
Stand back...
turn round!
And you hurry!
Look, Cinderella,
they hit the tip of my nose
just as I dreamt
I was off to your wedding...
What did you give her?
Show me!
Nice present!
Like for a squirrel!
The bodice...
Mummy, you forgot the lace!
And a new necklace!
And earrings!
Mumy, you can't send
a this man to buy cloth!
That's true...
We'll go to town ourselves.
Yes, Ma'am.
Put the horse to
the buggy!
Would you like to come to
town with us, Cinderella?
You'd only scare people off!
Stop staring!
Sveep up properly!
I said properly, understand?
Stop that at once!
Be a good boy...
Wait here, I'll go and see Rosie...
You lucky thing,
flying where you want to...
I'd so like to see where he goes...
But how can I, like this?
All this is mine?
Don't be afraid of me!
This was all inside the nut!
Ho do I look, Silly-Billy?
The first shot!
Great, one more bird of prey
and your Highness is
the King of the Hunt!
The King awards this
precious ring
to the huntsman who first
shoots down a bird of prey!
Good luck.
First shot!
Second shot!
Third!
Your turn, Prince!
Too high
Whose arrow is it?
Highness!
It was me, forgive me.
Who are you?
I thought you do not want to fire!
Quite an ordinary one.
Do we continue with the hunt?
The best marksman has shown
us his art -
the ring!
It is yours by rights!
Or can you do better still?
I am sorry that you are cross...
Do you see those cones at the tip?
Would you dare?
Here any bit of a girl can do that.
My horse!
Did a young hunter go this way?
Why?
Did he or did he not?
No, far and wide nothing but
a fluffy kitten,
a cheeky kid!
Come on down!
You come up!
We've met before, haven't we?
You'd have to remind me where!
Here in the wood, you little lizzard!
You won't escape today!
Where is he?
Where?
She'll tell us!
Where's she gone to?
Who?
That girl,
we couldn't catch last time.
Pass the buttons, Cinderella!
Cinderella, the silver thread!
Cinderella, the necklace!
Come on!
I want the carpet out,
right up to the sleigh!
Yes, m' am.
Well?
Lovely...
Just beautiful, Dora dear...
My hat!
Would you like to come
with us to the ball?
Say, would you?
I know you wouldn't take me inside.
But could I just have a peep...
through the window?
And who'll do the cleaning here?
I'd get it all done by morning.
If you haven't enough to do
... there!
I want it all gone
when we' re back!
The lentils picked
from the corn!
I'lltell you
how many times I danced
with the Prince!
Hold my train!
You'd better hold it yourself.
I could soil it.
Don't be sad,
I'll dance with you after supper.
You go and get us something to eat!
Your word is my command, Highness!
You' re sorry you can't go, aren't you?
I know...
But I can't help you.
It'lltake me a week to pick
these apart...
...you've come to help me?
The corn into the basket,
lentils into the bowl!
What would I have done without you.
Thank you!
Daddy always laughed that
I'd ride to my first ball
on Nikolaus, like a Hussar.
And my mummy promised me
a pretty dress,
as pink as
the red evening sky...
And all that's left to me is
Nikolaus.
No, I have lots of other things...
three magic hazel-nuts...
no, only two...
Rosie, do you think...?
How did you get here,
and who saddled you?
The noble Lady of the Black
Forest, with daughter...
Baroness of Shortwood
with grand-daughter...
Lady of Edge
with daughters...
Don't look so sour!
Smile!
I'd like to know which one
you'd be smiling at,
if you had to marry her.
Dad, let's postpone it for a year...
Listen to him!
And this is to be my successor!
Do choose a more convenient
time for quarrelling!
Did you notice how he smiled at you?
I made no such fuss
when I got married!
But you married mummy...
and you force strange girls onto me...
The noble Lady of Gotham with niece...
You'd better give rein
to your temperament on the dance-floor.
I don't care,
you point to one, I'll ask her...
His Highness now asks you
to start the dance.
Music!
Come on, that's impolite!
Look, that pretty blonde
with the blue train...
Or the brunette in yellow...
How can I choose!
I'll choose blindly!
Clumsy girl, you' re so slow!
May I have the pleasure?
I knew nothing of
the Prince's taste, it seems.
Did you come from afar?
The distance was no greater
than my longing to dance
with your Highness!
In spite of my treading
on your toes?
That is an hour for me, Highness.
I would dance with you
till the end of the world.
What courage!
I can land you as much as you like!
I don't make debts, young lady!
You think I should go in?
Shall I, shall I not,
shall I, shall I not...
I shall...
Well, I'll give it a try...
Don't be cross, I'm going!
Mind out!
Have pity on him!
Let him stew a bit.
Out of breath?
I'll have them play something faster.
Have them play what you like!
I've finished dancing!
Go back and dance!
I'd rather fell trees!
All right, start at once!
As you like!
Good evening, your Highness!
Thank you for a wonderful welcome!
I... you see...
I'm sorry, you surprised me...
I thought you were
running out to meet me...
No, I was just running out...
In that case I shan't keep you...
But I don't want to any longer...
May I have the pleasure?
Wouldn't it go better with music?
Why aren't they playing?
Who are you?
Do you want to question me,
or to dance?
Who can it be?
We'll see.
Our boy forgot all about
the trees he wanted to fell!
Look how graceful she is!
Shall I ask her up?
Let her dance a while...
With that clumsy boy of ours?
You may be surprised!
Do you know who it is?
I don't...
Why doesn't she take that veil off?
Probably hiding a big nose!
Take off that veil, then!
Is this my son?
He is only doing what you asked...
But who is she?
You are more impatient than your son.
At least give me a hint!
Why do you want to know?
Because I have just chosen a bride
and I know not who she is...
Not so loud, they are listening!
Let them hear!
I'll call right out into the world...
that I'm in love...
and getting married...!
But you forgot something!
What?
To ask the bride if she wants you!
You'd give me the mitten?
A bit of cheek, what?
Will you have me, or not?
I'll give you a riddle,
and if you guess...
First time: Face smuged with ashes,
but it's no huntsman?
What on earth...
Calm down, you'll find out...
Third time:
A dress embroidered in silver,
but she's not a Princess!
Pity...
Until you know the answer
to my riddle -
Goodbye!
What happened?
Why did she run off?
What if he's fallen in love?
That was your wish.
Without my permission?
I'd like to see that!
You didn't obey your parents either,
and brought me home, my love...
Why aren't they playing?
Play!
Music, please!
Get the horses, quickly!
Open up!
Come on, open up!
What's wrong?
Open up!
What do you want?
We have not come in enmity...
Why, then?
Who is the master of this house?
No master-a mistress!
But she's at the Palace ball
with her daughter!
Staring like an owl -
let him say what he wants!
That beautiful Princess!
Princess?
Here?
She rode in a moment before me!
Let him find his Princess, then!
I don't know if she's a Princess,
but she is beautiful...
and somewhere here I lost her!
We have droves of beauties here Sir!
Just to choose the right one!
Come and make your choice,
you tenderfoot!
Or get out of here!
That's not bad advice, your Highness!
Let's wait till daybreak!
Mornings make for wiser decisions!
What now-at night!
No, I must find her!
I want to see all the girls
of this farmstead!
By what right, Sir?
It's the Prince!
Oh, the Prince... Your Highness...
Every single girl!
Here they are, your Highness!
Now I wonder what you'll do!
She had a veil...
... a rose-pink dress!
Stop!
What's he doing here?
Looking for someone.
...you don't know her face...
... nor her name...
I'll recognize her by the slipper...
The girl whom this slipper fits
will be my wife!
Your foot!
Next!
That's too small even for a doll...
Leave off, you silly fool!
Have they all tried it on?
There's one more here!
You dupe...
Is there really no one other here?
Of course there is,
your Highness - Cinderella!
Yes, Cinderella!
Why hasn't she shown up?
Where can she be?
I haven't seen her all evening!
Cinderella!
She had to pick the corn
from the lentils!
We must find her!
Cinderella!
Come!
Wait here!
Take that rope!
What for?
Do you think she's in there?
Ah, here you are!
Cinderella!
She isn't here, either...
Cinderella, where are you?!
Unsaddle him and rub him down!
Your Highness!
Halt!
So it wasn't a vain search!
I shan't let you go now!
Why did you come here?
To find her!
Why did you search for her?
To ask her to marry me!
What prevents you from doing so?
Unveil her face!
Why?
So I know her!
She is dressed just as at the ball...
the dress, tiara, veil...
Why does she not speak?
After you put a ring on her finger!
Let her try the slipper on!
Let her try the slipper!
Why won't she try on
her own slipper?
She is shy!
Do you want to marry her or not?
After she's tried on the slipper!
Drive off!
He'll follow us, you'll see.
In the end he'll do as I want!
Help me!
Catch hold of my hand...
You are not my bride!
Help me out!
I'm coming, Ma'am!
Do you see anything?
There's something in there...
She can't have disappeared...
Do you hear...?
Cinderella!
Rosie, where have you been?
But this is the last one...
But this is... a wedding dress...
Well?
We should go back...
They'll be worried at the palace...
Your Highness, look!
That is she!
Go on, then...
Go on!
Have you brought my slipper?
I should return the ring
for the King of the Hunt...
But it belongs to you!
So now you know the answer
to my riddle?
Face smudged with ashes,
but it's no chimney-sweep?
That day in the wood,
that bit of a girl!
Hat with a feather
and cross-bow, but it's not hunstman?
That little sharpshooter
was you, too!
Dress embroidered in silver,
but she's no Princess
who is it?
Our Cinderella!
And mine, too...
If you want me?
And there'll be a wedding...
Your Highness,
history lesson is about to begin!