Children, before you hand in your drawings, be sure to sign your name.
But I still don't know where I'm going on holiday!
Vasek, what did you spend an hour drawing? Where are you going with your dad and mom?
Their honeymoon!
Why did you agree to such nonsense?
Going on holiday and not knowing where! What if you forget something you need?
You know what? I'll take everything I need and a bit more!
Lubos hasn't mentioned at all where you're going? At least you'd have an idea!
I have quite an accurate an idea!
I'll lie down on the grass and just sleep. Let Lubos enjoy our little child.
Sleep, you say? And for this you need a new wardrobe?
That's not all! I decided I'll be partying a lot.
No shopping, no cooking, no cleaning! I don't want to even see a kitchen.
~ Oh, you're going to Bermuda?
~ I deserve a bit of a rest!
All year it's just drill at the ballet hall, lots of stress at home and on the stage.
I want to live at last, too!
~ Isn't it perfect?
~ Sure it is! Perfect for a mountain tour!
~ What kind of tour?
~ Oh come on! Where did you meet? In the mountains.
- This year, you met again after eight years...
- ...after nine years.
- ...after nine years, where? In the mountains.
If you're saying Lubos is a snow man, he's not!
~ He was in Prague this spring.
~ He was, a few days.
Only to prepare an expedition to the Alps!
~ And in the meantime, he's poking at the soil under the glacier.
~ So what?
Anna, you know you have a child with a chief of mountain rescue?
But otherwise, Lubos is normal!
If you assume he's going to put you on the train to the mountains, everything's fine.
Definitely not! We wrote to him three times insisting that we're not going to the mountains!
I'm not going to risk he'll turn Vasek into a climber!
~ What about sending Vasek with me to the cottage?
~ Absolutely not!
Do you even understand the situation you're in?
Starting to live with a man after eight years isn't easy.
Especially when you should get married ASAP.
First I'll get to know Lubos! Then I'll think about the wedding!
What about Vasek? The marriage will have to be by the end holidays, before he goes back to school!
~ I've tripped a few times in my life! Now I have to decide properly!
~ Decide?
You're twenty-eight, you have an eight-year-old son, and when his father wants to marry you, you want to "think about it"?
What's to decide? Whether you're in love with him?
That hardly matters, but I just need to know I can rely on him.
Mom, why such a big suitcase? And where did you put those old pants?
Colombo, let that suitcase be.
And tidy up those things!
~ Why should I take those old pants?
~ To be able to climb the mountains.
~ Your father wrote that to you?
~ No, I came up with it myself!
~ What did he write you in the last letter?
~ That's a secret!
~ A great adventure awaits us!
~ Good! Now go wash!
~ Mommy, don't go anywhere!
~ Don't be silly?
~ But I won't be able to fall asleep!
Close your eyes and you can dream that our holiday begins tomorrow!
~ That we're all three together!
~ And when you wake up in the morning...
~ ...Dad's coming! ~ Yeah!
But I can't wait until the morning!
That was the nicest performance of the season!
I know!
Because it was the last!
Bozenka, did I leave the big blue towel lying there?
It's by the mirror or on the couch!
This is a very nice welcome, after 3 months!
Haven't I imagined this moment a hundred times a day?!
I had no idea you would scream so nicely!
~ Why are there are seven beds?
~ Seven climbers!
~ Where are they?
~ Six on the train, and the seventh in the bathroom!
~ You could shower at home!
~ Vasek can't wait to see you!
~ And you can?
Me? What about me? I'll wait for you outside!
There's a bathroom!
You look like you did when you were seventeen!
Back then, I was nineteen and three months. Don't stare at me!
Finish up! I want to be out of here before the climbers get back.
~ Relax, the boys won't be here until the morning!
~ How is it that you're here?
~ Please don't mention it to Vasek! He'd be heartbroken.
~ Wait!
That's why you came early, to tell us you can't go on holiday with us?
No! I thought this night could be more than just the start of a holiday.
Dad! Dad's here!
Three, two, one!
~ Mom's asleep?
~ Like a log, but we'll get her up.
~ Leave that to me!
~ What's the surprise?
~ At the front of the house.
~ Are you packed? ~ I have a backpack.
~ And Mom? ~ She has a whole suitcase.
~ And your climbing gear? Do you have that?
~ Yeah, but don't tell Mom so that she doesn't panic!
~ Do I have to go home?
~ No, but you have to get up.
~ What time is it?
~ Past seven.
~ How did I get home?
~ Don't you remember anything?
There! And for me the three hours were like an eternity without you!
Quiet! Vasek could wake up.
~ Mom, Mom, I got a new bike!
~ Maybe you behaved well.
~ You must have behaved well, too!
~ Why?
~ You got a bike as well!
~ A bike? What for?
~ So that you don't feel jealous.
~ That's what dad says.
What a silly idea to buy bikes before a holiday... do you want to lug them around on the train?
~ No, the train will only take your suitcase.
~ Huge suitcase! ~ What about us?
~ We'll go by bike.
~ Bikes, great!
~ Didn't I tell you?
~ No, you didn't tell me!
And the next time, don't even try. There's no way you two can get me on a bike!
Will there be wilderness?
~ Wilderness for you, paradise for Mom.
~ I'm so curious, I can't wait.
~ If we can ride tomorrow as far as today, we'll be there by the evening.
~ Are you kidding me?
I would also say that real adventure is rather farther.
In the Himalayas. Or in Africa.
~ Adventure is not anywhere. You have to have it in your blood.
~ I have that! ~ Me, too!
This means Mom doesn't have to ride the bike to Africa nor Asia.
Oh now I'm much happier.
People sometimes think the farther away from home you are, the greater the adventure.
~ But the greatest wonders of nature lie close by.
~ Maybe a boar! ~ Maybe.
Being able to look around is the secret of an adventurer!
- Tomorrow I'm looking around a hotel room and getting in a hot bath.
- It's not exactly a hotel...
I don't mind, at least there'll be a bathroom.
I hope you don't expect me to sleep under a tent the whole holidays.
Don't fret! You'll have a room that'll knock your eyes out!
I give up! Put up the tent!
~ I can't! You can't camp in a nature reserve.
~ What do you mean?
~ Are we going to spend the night in a tree?
~ Do you see that light?
~ Do you think they'll let us sleep there?
~ I'll go check it out!
I don't like knocking on strangers' doors.
Go with the flow!
Hello! Hello! Colombo here!
Where are you?
Help me, I can't get out!
~ What are you doing?
~ Lubos, hello!
~ Hey, Dad!
Folks, Krkonos Mountain has fallen! Our boy found his way home!
I came to show you my bride!
Bride? So then, welcome to our home!
Beník, he'll probably be my grandfather!
Make yourself at home... here's the living room and here's the kitchen!
As you can see, here you'll find everything you need!
This was my kingdom! Now it'll be yours!
A practical dresser...
For the second bed, I'll jump into the barn!
A perfect closet!
This is the room that'll make my eyes bug out?
~ You don't like it?
~ Terribly!
I can't be more amazed! I ride like a fool on a bike for two days.
In the tent, ants crawl all over me, and now this? Is this the paradise of yours?
Everything's yet to come! The two of us will be alone here!
~ Can't you ever think of anything else?
~ Right now I just can't think at all!
It's going to be a great holiday!
~ Why doesn't it heat the water?
~ Because the stove doesn't work properly.
~ How doesn't the stove work properly?
~ The chimney's crooked!
~ Why is the chimney crooked?
~ Bloody hell, so much fuss around a bath.
~ Vasek, where are you? Into the house!
~ I hope the boy's not going to bathe in the tub?
~ Here you call *that* a tub?
~ Here, we wash under the pump.
~ So you've got the Middle Ages here.
~ What do you mean?
~ That this place hasn't been cleaned since the 30-year war.
~ Grandpa, look what I found in the loft!
~ I'm not your grandfather!
~ Check out these muscles!
~ Wow, you've got great muscles, Grandpa!
Listen, no boy has called me Grandpa, ever!
~ Why would a stranger boy call you that, Grandpa?
~ Are you not a stranger boy?
I'm yours!
I sure knew how to choose, didn't I?
~ Well, from the whole world, you couldn't have brought a greater treasure.
~ Don't say that!
~ Anna's got as much steam as a locomotive.
~ Keep your compliments and heat up the stove.
Well, I'll have to find the stove first.
~ What do you mean by "grandpa"?
~ Lubos is my dad.
His mom is my bride. No! My mom is his bride.
~ Shut your mouth and be quiet!
~ So you've got to be my grandfather. You see?
~ I'll be like your granddad.
~ Not like. You're already my real granddad!
~ Shut your mouth and be quiet!
~ Do you understand?
~ No!
No worries, Grandpa! The important thing is that you're glad you've got me.
I did wish for a grandson, but a man. Not a sissy!
~ I'm not a sissy.
~ You are! A big one!
Vasek!
You're not a sissy!
Jesus Christ!
What a man! Lubos, he's a great guy!
Lubos, look at the guy!
Dad, stop it! What are you doing?
This isn't a grandfather, it's Herod!
Anna, dear, the moon is full! It will be a beautiful summer night!
I'm here! I saved you a place in bed!
You're a good boy!
~ Don't wake my mom!
~ Why aren't you asleep?
~ I knew you'd come to me!
Just sleep, OK?
Daddy, when I'm thinking about something, I find it hard to sleep! You, too?
~ What are you thinking about now?
~ How to be a climber, when there aren't any mountains.
~ Wait until morning!
~ Are there some mountains around? Hidden somewhere?
~ You'll see!
~ We'll start training in the morning?
~ Maybe now!
~ Really?
~ A proper climber sleeps as soon as he lies down.
~ It's not possible.
If so, the best climber in the world would be our mom!
~ So, the dragon loop! Now you!
~ There once was a princess.
She went to the pond, but a sprite emerged and pulled her under.
It wasn't a sprite, it was a dragon! That is why it's called a dragon loop.
The knot should bind on the left. Now it won't open when you fall.
Come on down! Home!
~ Is it time for breakfast?
~ We'll leave after breakfast.
~ Where are we going?
~ Come on!
~ To the train station!
You've got another suitcase? One arrived this morning with the postman.
Is that kid making a fool out of me?
Of course he is. He takes after you.
~ I told you what I don't want and why and you do the exact opposite!
~ These aren't mountains.
I didn't want to go to the mountains and you take me to a cottage with this rock.
The most beautiful place is where one is born! If I'd known you don't like it here, I'd have been born somewhere else.
I survived the exhausting journey. I survived the room, I survived the grandpa! As I did this unmaintained place.
But you're not going to make a climber out of the boy.
I don't want to worry about him getting killed on a rock. Pack up, we're leaving!
We can't, Mom! Dad told grandpa we'd be here for half the holidays!
From now on, what I say goes!
No, Mom! I'm not leaving Grandpa here! I'm friends with grandpa now.
I always wanted a grandpa. Mommy!
~ For half the holidays?
~ It doesn't matter, seeing how you are.
Listen, you two! You can do what you want on the land below the cottage.
But if I catch you on the rock by the pond... I'm serious!
~ So, deal?
~ You can rely on me! ~ Not me!
~ Well, we're leaving!
~ No!
Me too, you can rely on me!
~ Look, rocks.
~ Pedal!
~ There's a rock!
~ Come on!
There, too!
~ Don't look and speed up.
~ Oh gosh, it's all rocks here!
Speed up!
Dad, wait! We'll just touch the rock, then we'll go!
Don't! Are you trying to get me in trouble?
Dad, I'm made for the rocks!
~ Strength, intellect, agility, that's me.
~ But we promised.
But only about the rock by the pond. About the other rocks, we didn't promise.
Mom doesn't know the shortcut to the village.
You said that a good climber must overcome each obstacle.
~ Do you doubt me?
~ But our barrier is Mom.
I meant struggling against nature, not against your mom.
~ To have the joy of victory.
~ So I'm sure you'll have fun!
Overcoming mom, that's tougher than a 8000 meter climb.
~ Where are you going with that jalopy?
~ To the dispensary.
So that it doesn't break up at the show.
~ It's time for the veterans' parade again?
~ Yeah! And Mána must win!
~ It'll be enough if it charms like last year.
~ What did it win last year?
~ The prize! ~ What?
The very last place!
~ Watch out here, it's bumpy!
~ Don't worry!
~ Why is the rock called the Dragon's Tooth?
~ To scare us.
I'm not scared of the Tooth, but you are scared. Of Mom. Otherwise we would have climbed it.
Do you know what you're asking from me? Do you not feel bad?
Do you know how bad I felt while I had no father like other boys?
~ I have an idea!
~ I know! We'll give mom the silent treatment until she gives in!
~ No!
~ I'll try to get her to lift the ban.
~ Will you do it?
I'll do what I can! But you must leave us alone!
You can rely on me!
Vasek! Vasek, Lubos!
~ Where are the boys?
~ They went shopping!
~ They're still not back yet?
~ They went back. They forgot bread and their backpack!
I'd like to know what they've got on their minds!
If they took a shortcut, we'll be waiting for them with the dinner.
The shortcut will take about three hours. This is a really crazy place.
~ Where are the potatoes? They were here.
~ You mean the week old, mouldy potatoes?
~ I threw them away.
~ There goes our snack, Pepa!
~ What's this?
~ This is Pepa.
~ I scrubbed the entire house.
~ Vasek likes wild boars.
I went around three communal farms to get him.
~ A black pig is rare these days.
~ Mom, can you see it!?
As if three men weren't enough; I have to care for a pig, too. What a Bermuda trip!
Look Pepa, it looks like the poor boy's had no life with that woman.
You'll certainly not have a clue what he longs for!
I know! He'd like a chimpanzee to swing on the chandelier in the bedroom.
I wanted to keep whales when I was his age.
That hardly surprises me. What he didn't inherit from his father, he inherited from you.
And the floor will be scrubbed by one of you. And I guess Pepa won't do it.
That you're a single mother, I don't mind.
Who you got the baby with, I'm not interested. I'll quietly play grandfather.
But in this cottage, what the man says matters! And that man is me.
Anna! Anna!
Anna! Annie! Honey! I have an idea!
~ Where did you come by that?
~ You see that pine! Meet me there in ten minutes.
~ Am I playing hide and seek with you all?
~ No, just me.
Vasek's in the woods with grandpa getting beechnuts! Do you understand?
~ No!
~ I disappeared from them.
~ Are you asking me on a date?
Honey, don't be surprised. I'm a world record beater at 2 kilometers' run.
~ But I have muffins on the stove.
~ What are you thinking about!
That you need something to eat!
No, not here!
~ Mom, help! Mom!
~ This isn't Colombo, it's Juantorena.
Not this way! It'll track in dirt from the barn.
~ What did you promise me?!
~ I didn't know you were persuading Mom.
~ What were you thinking?
~ That you were lost in the woods.
~ Grandpa, can we make Pepa wild?
~ The pig? And why?
~ So that he's wild again.
That would take a lot of work! The whole holiday.
~ If you didn't go to work, could you do it?
~ No! Grandpa has a plan to fulfill.
Pepa's happy he's tame, in the barn.
~ Where are the ants coming from all the time?
~ Grandpa, where do you actually work?
I have three working tools:
a trained body, an obsession to achieve everything in the world, and strong nerves.
~ I can see that!
~ You're a climber?
All the climbers look at me from below! I'm a roofer.
So the rope in the loft's yours?
Come here, Detective, and tell me why is Lubos still running after your mom?
Dad's persuading Mom.
Tonight it'll surely work out. But you'd better come downstairs, we'll go to the pond.
~ I have to wait until Vasek falls asleep.
~ He'll drop off soon, he's pretty tired.
~ Where did you get the sugar?
~ In the shop.
They must be storing goods in an anthill. Maybe next time I'll go there with you.
~ Shut your mouth and come to bed quickly.
~ Not to bed!
~ Can't you hear me? Not another word, let's go!
~ Mom!
When Anna discovers that you climb on the rocks with the kid, she's not staying here an hour.
~ That would make you sad, wouldn't it?
~ No, but what if she takes the kid with her?
We may not ever see him again.
If that's what bothers you, you can just go to bed quickly.
Lubos!
~ Lubos, what did Anna mean by the whale?
~ With what whale?
I always thought I brought up a real man.
~ That if you'd known Anna was expecting your baby, you'd have married her.
~ Of course I would!
That's what I like! Because with a guy who does not care about his child...
~ ...I wouldn't even shake hands.
~ But I didn't know.
I've had enough!
~ I can spank your butt!
~ If you knew how scared I was today.
That I would fall asleep sooner than Mom. But I resisted!
Let me make this clear. At night you don't have to wait for me.
~ I'm cleaning this.
~ What?
~ The sugar!
~ Why?
~ I'm picking out the ants.
~ What kind of idea is that?!
~ I was worried Mom would go shopping with us.
Now that we've just started to... you know what... so that it's not right over.
Oh, come on, silly! Leave the ants alone!
And remember! A real man is fearless.
Oh, so you've already persuaded Mom?
I haven't succeeded yet.
Don't be sad! I'm sure you'll persuade her. I believe in you.
What if I left Anna here with Vasek the whole holidays?
~ You're not taking them with you in August?
~ Anna doesn't want to hear about mountains at all.
~ When I'm on duty, I won't have time for them anyway.
~ And what does Anna say?
~ Nothing, she doesn't know about it, yet.
~ I'm not going to talk her into anything!
You don't have to, especially when you sleep with Vasek for the night.
Oh that's what's on your mind.
~ And when's the wedding, huh?
~ We're still planning it!
~ You're so old fashioned.
~ You two are very modern!
~ You have an eight-year-old child and you're already planning a wedding.
~ We knew each other for ten days, then I left for the Himalayas.
We only met up again this year. We ran into each other at the ski resort.
~ Suddenly I have an eight-year-old boy.
~ Save this story for Vasek.
I just want you to get the boy on paper.
I'll happily adopt my own child. I'll happily get him on paper, I'll even get a stamp! If you sleep with the boy in the kitchen tonight!
I will, after the wedding!
I'll start believing in miracles. Did you see Cinderella here tonight?
~ The Cinderella was me!
~ You picked the ants out of the sugar? Why?
~ So you wouldn't go shopping with us.
~ Why shouldn't I go with you?
~ Vasek thought...
~ No interpreting, I'll listen to the original.
I thought that you could sleep during the day, too. You deserve a rest.
~ We've got us a nice boy, don't you think?
~ Let's go shopping again today, OK, Dad?
~ We can skip it.
~ What about milk? I want milk!
Do you understand that? He's always disliked milk. Listen...
~ are you giving fresh milk to Pepa?
~ No!
~ Dad said that good...
~ Don't wave those hands in the air!
...they must drink a pint of milk a day.
How do you make the boy obey each word you say?
You have a tremendous influence over him.
"Climbers, climbers, climbers...
"don't climb the rock that's very pointy"
"you'll fall on the sand and you won't see your home village anymore"
"doo-dlay-dah."
I hope you remember your promise. No climbing on the rocks.
~ On the rock!
~ No, on the rocks!
~ Today we're not going anywhere.
~ We'll help mother peel potatoes.
~ No, not potatoes! I want milk!
~ I'll drink a whole liter.
~ What if Vasek went shopping alone?
Your father and I could manage, just the two of us.
Anna, you're just great!
If you like peeling potatoes, I might as well go alone.
It won't work! I can't let the boy go alone!
~ No shortcuts back home, we're taking the road.
~ Why not?
Mom didn't lift the ban, so we get commended.
I like praise, don't you? Hey, Mána!
Out of the way! Look out!
~ Does the motor still die frequently?
~ No, now it can't stop.
~ What does Mana do when there's fire?
~ No one knows!
~ Up until yesterday, we climbed the rocks.
~ I thought I could convince Mom easily.
You have to try harder. Look at me, I'll never give up.
Now come back before I get angry. Think about Mom!
~ Why?
~ Why, why... pick the things up.
As of yesterday, we were banned from the rock by the pond.
~ But this morning we're banned from all rocks in the world!
~ My mom always prohibits something.
She never let me look for a dad! Now she's glad to have you!
She'll be happy to see that I'm as able as you.
~ You know what I see? A sly fox!
~ Where?
~ Right in front of me!
I'm taking more rope.
Now, Vasek, remember what I said. Three solid points of contact!
On your toes!
Higher, higher. Careful now! Hands up!
Now pick up the loop!
Hold on with your left hand and with the right one loosen the knot.
Good! Like that!
It won't work at the bottom, go over the top. There's a pocket above you.
You can grab it on the right now. That's right!
Switch your hands! Now go around the corner.
Come on! Good! Dude!
Lubos, a double fracture! His ribs in a cast.
~ Hovorka's in the hospital.
~ Where?
~ I don't know! CLIMBER MEETING AT RISK STOP ...
~ COME ASAP, STOP
~ When?
~ I'm not gonna bring it all the way up to you.
~ What happened, Dad?
~ Well, buddy, that's the punishment.
You know what I wish? That I could have those eight years back.
~ Vasek didn't have a very great childhood with me.
~ Finally something reasonable. I'll tell you something, too...
I always thought you were irresponsible! Now I know that you keep your word.
I keep checking the rock by the pond every hour. I suspected you unfairly.
~ I'm not saying a thing.
~ Explain how you got back all right...
while Vasek and Grandpa were chasing a wild boar?
Because the only wild boar is our grandpa!
But when you go shopping, someone always comes back with torn pants!
~ And you always come back so tired.
~ What's wrong with Vasek?
~ Nothing! He fell asleep!
~ Nothing? You say it just like that?
We've been waiting a long time for this moment. And you'd just talk to me!
~ You wanted to say something to me.
~ Later! This is important!
~ I see. That's why we only see each other at lunch and dinner.
~ And breakfast.
I know. You must force yourself so much to do all the silly stuff with our boy.
I don't have to force myself at all.
Damnit! How do they do this in other families?
They must have a special training or something.
~ I guess they have a grandpa who keeps office hours.
~ What are you doing, Dad?
I took a day off, kids! So that nothing happens here!
It's actually better! Grandpa can go shopping with the kid.
~ And we'll finally have time for ourselves.
~ Mommy! Mommy! I got bitten by a bee!
Dad, what are you doing? Mom, is Dad trying to see how long he can stay under water?
~ Leave your father alone and go on out!
~ Grandpa!
Granddad, my dad invented a new game, we need a stopwatch!
When I whistle, leaves start falling from the trees.
That's nothing! When I whistle, branches begin to crack.
That's nothing at all. When I whistle... slaps start coming.
~ Well, you're chosen!
~ Why not me?
You could forget to come back and we'd stay hungry.
~ Into the enemy camp we have to send...
~ The most reliable one!
~ Be careful not to get captured!
~ Grandpa, whom are we fighting against?
~ Who's the enemy?
~ Mom.
~ So mom will be our enemy!
~ I'm against that!
~ Don't worry Dad, I'm for!
I was talking to Kos. You can get married in the village. I'll write the wedding speech myself.
I'll casually mention Venda and the rocks.
Anna will be thrilled to hear about the wedding speech; it's not necessary...
to mention Venda and the rocks.
Oh come on, it's a woman. In that moment she won't even know what she's agreeing to.
~ And I'll take care about you staying away from rocks until wedding.
~ Why do you want all the paperwork?
When we two were climbing, you didn't have any permission, either.
And Mom was as furious when she found us on Dragon Tooth, too.
But we two continued to climb. And I'll have to pack up soon.
You're not staying even until the end of July? What does Anna say?
~ Nothing!
~ She doesn't know anything, again?
~ I don't want to ruin her last week.
~ No way! You're not leaving until the wedding.
~ An international climbers' session is not a dovecot!
Then the wedding will be before you leave.
Vasek, what are you doing up a tree again?
Just wait until you get down!
~ Who is stealing my gingerbread?!
~ Please will you not say you caught me?
~ I didn't say you couldn't.
~ Not you! Dad and grandpa did!
I'd get points deducted.
We have a new fighting game, and it has strict rules.
~ Take what you'll eat and leave the rest at home!
~ But Dad and Grandpa are hungry, too.
~ Why isn't Daddy coming home to eat?
~ It's a secret! Listen!
~ He wanted to come home, but he's afraid.
~ Afraid? Of what?
That you wouldn't let him go out until after dinner.
Dinner's in the oven. You can help yourself.
~ And what is it?
~ Noodles with poppy seeds!
~ Wow!
Have you told Anna you're leaving?
~ You told Mom that I'm as able like you, didn't you?
~ You're good, both of you!
You're giving me tasks, but I've got my worries.
~ If you haven't had enough, you can all sleep in the kitchen. All three of you!
~ Of course, that's great!
Vasek!
~ What are you doing?
~ Having a party.
~ Alone, alone?
~ No, I have company. Pepa.
Keep an eye out for Vasek. He'd deduct your points.
No worries, when I can't see Vasek, he can't see me.
~ This is the law of optics, darling.
~ He has binoculars.
~ I wonder who gave such a weapon to the child.
~ Do you know where?
~ Around the chimney.
These are silly jokes! We're finally alone and you're pouting.
~ Go where you heart leads you.
~ If it were up to me, I'd always be with you.
~ I also have my duties.
~ Yes! 24h working time.
If you left grandpa with a boy in the woods, you could miss something, right?
~ Oh no!
~ Yes! Otherwise you wouldn't have played cards with them until midnight.
~ But you'd locked the door, darling.
I knocked.
~ Knocked, knocked. At half past eleven!
~ You were waiting for me? If only I had known.
If I had known.
~ What are you doing with that towel?
~ I'm so hot when you're angry at me.
I'm not mad at you.
What are you doing with the hands all the time?
Not here! We have to sneak off somewhere.
Listen, for this foolishness, go pick someone else.
~ Shall we go higher?
~ What if Grandpa sees us here?
~ Don't worry!
~ Don't talk and climb down.
~ You can untie yourself.
~ Why is Grandpa watching us so closely?
~ He wants to play with us.
~ Why doesn't he go climbing with us then?
After climbing on the roofs all year, he's looking for other entertainment.
Damn! Everywhere you step, there's jam or compôte.
The woman will start pickling fir cones.
I want to find a mug and I need a compass in my own kitchen.
You'd better take a compass into the woods and come up with a game for two.
I'd be grateful if you'd take the boy and give Lubos a moment with me.
~ I'm working on it.
~ Jesus Christ, what are you doing?
~ Looking for mugs.
~ For the water creature.
~ Yeah!
~ Here we go. What do you think?
~ Where did you get that horrible outfit?
This is a family tradition. The last time, we scared Lubos.
~ The boy will enjoy it, won't he?
~ I can already see it. He'll be terribly frightened.
~ And you call that joy.
~ Women! They never understand.
The boy will have a memory -- for life.
"Close your eyes, Anna, your rope is loose...
"fall a bit to the right, below us is the rest of the team,...
~ "Boom, this time it ended up well..."
~ Stop singing and loosen up! Give me some slack.
~ It *is* loose.
~ Damn, can you see where it's stuck?
I see it! It jammed there at a crack.
~ I'm going up there!
~ Don't move! Don't you dare! I'm coming right down.
Daddy!
Dad!
Hold on! I'll go get help!
Help! Grandpa!
~ Don't panic, Vasek!
~ Help!
~ Get back, Vasek!
Help! Grandpa!
Grandpa, help! Grandpa!
~ Dad's hanging on the rock.
~ Which one?
Dragon's Tooth!
Mom, help! Water Goblin!
~ What's wrong with dad?
~ Hanging.
I told you, Grandpa! The child got shocked by you!
Fanda, look out! Out of the way!
What is it?
A water goblin, and he called me Fanda.
Oh gosh, that boy scared me. What are you doing here?
It was just a loose bit of rock in my hand. Fortunately the boy listened to me.
Why would he listen? You disobey me, too!
Don't worry! Your jokes are so stupid!
Damn! Our Mom!
Anna, honey! Where are you coming from?
~ You are such liars!
~ I'm not! I'm just a sprite!
~ This is where you go shopping?
~ No, this is the way to the shop.
~ What are you doing here?
~ Here...
~ This is on the way, Daddy.
~ Yeah! It's on the way. You know...
What's this, clothesline? I forbade you to climb rocks. You promised!
~ Don't shout!
~ So what is it?
I confess, I climbed up.
I wanted to show off in front of the kid. I'm an egoistical idiot, you already told me!
What about Vasek?
Vasek? He was watching me.
You expect me to believe that Vasek sat and just watched?
You should trust me more. He's my child!
~ With me, nothing can happen to him!
~ Be reasonable!
If the boy had been up there, too, he couldn't have come to get help.
I believe you, Grandpa! And when you kill yourself on the rock, I won't care.
Don't be sad, Dad! Mom didn't say the truth.
~ Do you think she would shed a tear for me?
~ A whole river. Absolutely!
I wonder how Anna will now rush with you to the altar?
Have you told her that you're leaving on Wednesday?
Lubos!
Don't worry, I'll work it all out!
Be careful, everyone. What do you see here?
~ This is a general plan of attack.
~ What are we attacking?
Leave the cakes alone, or you're not gonna eat the dinner.
Do you think it will be edible, what those two are cooking?
~ Grandpa, listen to what the chief says.
~ Grandpa is to go north.
Around the Stone Snake cross to the Dancer.
Your mother will go to the south, along the creek upstream.
Vasek will follow the footsteps of grandfather and I'll track Mom.
~ My dad has just the best games!
~ Around three, we'll meet here!
And we then come back home together. In the evening we'll have scoring, prizes.
For stamina and the like!
What if mom gets lost?
It would be best if the three of us all tracked her.
Colombo, you're going north! I can do it myself!
Oh! I understand!
~ What are you doing? Where are you grating the cucumber?!
~ Into my muffins!
Just you dude, you just don't give up! You're all mine!
Don't tell me! I understand about your shopping and the ants.
You climbed on the rock every day!
~ So Vasek could watch.
~ Hardly a big sacrifice.
Don't tell me you'd climb rocks for your pleasure, in this heat?
If you knew how guilty I feel about what I did, but mostly for what I didn't do.
I can never give back to Vasek what I owe him!
Eight years of ordinary life.
In August, I'll go anywhere with you. Even on a bicycle to Krkonose Mountains.
~ I'd rather stay here with Grandpa.
~ The wedding could also be here, in the village, on Tuesday...
It doesn't matter where the wedding is.
It matters! Grandpa would be happy!
Today's Sunday, I'll write a letter to my mother on Monday. It'll arrive on Wednesday, ...
~ Friday, and the wedding can be on Saturday.
~ Not sooner?
~ Why?
~ If you knew what you don't. I'll tell you... I have to tell you...
Don't say anything now!
Grandpa, this is no fair game! Dad isn't tracking Mom at all!
He's even carrying her.
So let them be! In the evening we'll deduct their points.
You broke the route, too. You should be at the crossroads, not the cemetery.
Don't yell, here's where grandma rests. Too bad she didn't live to see the treasure...
What treasure?
You have a treasure, Grandpa? Hidden?
~ Grandpa! Grandpa!
~ You see, the boy makes a silly thing out of everything.
He probably is really ours!
Don't think about anything anymore.
~ Repeat, Colombo went to the North.
~ Colombo went to the North.
Somebody's breathing here.
~ Don't turn around! This isn't Colombo.
~ It's Pepa.
~ This isn't Pepa.
It's a wild boar!
Too bad Venda's not here.
~ Mom, we'll be walking to the wedding?
~ So what? You'd rather we rode a bike?
~ That's not a bad idea!
~ I've got an even better idea! I'll get you a great ride!
~ Grandpa, hell no!
~ For Mána it'll be a great honor.
How's this? I've got a better idea!
~ But I don't know just what idea yet.
~ I'm relieved.
~ Lubos, hold it until the wedding!
~ But Grandpa, there are only a few steps left until the top.
~ No way! And if you, little brat, tempt Dad, I'll lock you up with Pepa!
I warn you the last time!
Grandpa! Have you seen the guys?
They went shopping in the morning but they haven't made it to the shop yet.
~ And they left the letter for Mom on the table.
~ How did you find your way to the village?
~ On the road. There were ants in the sugar again.
~ You know what?
There's the mail box, the sugar, so go on home.
~ What about the guys?
~ I'll deal with this myself.
Mána's crew wishes good health to the bride.
~ My names is Voves.
~ Wolf, the head of the pigs' nursery.
We're here to be witnesses. Kos, our president.
~ Tomorrow I dress in black.
~ Why black?
~ There's a wedding, right?
~ Tomorrow?
~ It's Tuesday, right?
~ Sure, it's Tuesday!
~ You're having a wedding.
~ But the wedding will be on Saturday.
~ On Saturday, no!
~ On Saturday, definitely not.
~ Why not?
~ You're joking, right? Lubos didn't tell you? The whole village knows.
~ Tell me what?
~ He's leaving on Wednesday.
~ Who?
~ Lubos, of course!
~ The day after tomorrow?
~ Yeah, at noon.
~ At noon he definitely's going away.
~ Where?
~ Mountaineers are having a session.
~ In the Carpathians.
He also said that there'll also be Poles, Germans, and Soviets.
~ And Romanians.
~ Romanians, too, that's for sure!
~ How long he'll be there, did he say?
~ They say until the end of the holidays.
~ He'll be back on the 3rd of September.
~ Let it be, she doesn't know what's going on!
Oh I wonder if I've spilled a secret... Miss, do you know he is a mountaineer?
~ Grandpa!
~ He didn't tell you? I'll tear him to pieces!
~ What happened here?
~ Nothing! Lubos is lost.
~ Who? ~ The groom.
Anna, I'll fix it! Everything will be fine.
Take the shortcut. To the right at the pub.
Not the shortcut! No!
Come on, crank it up!
~ Congratulations! ~ We did it!
~ Now you really are the best! I'm so happy for you.
~ At one point I almost cried.
~ But you did it!
~ It feels like a fairy tale.
~ Why?
Why just "like"? Look at this beauty!
~ Noone anywere, just the sun... ~ Rock...
~ Dragon's Tooth... ~ And the two of us!
~ Can you hear that, Dad, Mána!? Is there a fire?
~ Yeah, right under our asses.
Mom, I'm here!
~ I'm a climber like my dad.
~ Be quiet!
Vasek! Vasek!
I did it!!
Guys, watch out, Mom!
~ Grandpa, how will they get down?
~ The way they got up, on the rope.
~ The rope!
~ Don't look there!
~ Bring me the boy!
~ Maybe the ladder.
~ The ladder. Deploy the ladder.
No, Mom, not a ladder! We are climbers!
~ This will be a thriller.
~ The Conqueror of picturesque mountains on a ladder.
~ It'll be our honor, Mána.
~ Providing a rescue for the chief.
~ Chief...
~ Mountain Rescue Service..
~ It won't...
~ Why not?
~ It's stuck!
~ It's turning again...
~ But the other way around.
~ What happened here?
~ I do not know.
Someone says something and you spread it around the village immediately.
~ We'll rescue the chief with the ladder.
~ Rescuing Lubos? You two?
~ He's hurt?
~ No! Why?
~ Otherwise, he'd climb down the rope like that boy over there.
~ Vasek, wait!
~ Darling, no! He deserves praise for that feat!
Dad, watch out, it's Mom!
Urchin, I'll spank you so hard you won't sit down for a week.
Lubos, down!
Now it will be exciting to see if the chief gets spanked, too.
~ The Mom looks pretty well, too.
~ Yeah!
Lubos, come on! You're losing your bride.
Anna! Anna!
Anna!
Honey!
I promised Vasek! Nothing could have happened to him!
I wouldn't be able to live with that!
He's my son, after all!
Anna, forgive me! I'll never do it again.
No, don't do that! Vasek is looking forward to the fun, my dad will be broken-hearted.
I'll get a shock!
I said I wouldn't go on a bike, but I went!
I didn't want to stay here, but I stayed!
I wanted to enjoy the holidays and I mostly enjoyed cooking at the stove.
You thought you would never fall in love.
~ But now that you can't live without me, it doesn't make a difference which day the wedding's on.
~ Wedding? What wedding?
The wedding will never happen!
You seemed to be a great dad. But you're a liar and a criminal.
Like any normal man!
There you are! Not a letter, not a card, nothing!
~ And that I'm here, worried stiff, you don't even care!
~ Don't get upset!
You didn't miss anything --- the wedding's off.
Why off? The rascal won't marry you?
The rascal would like to.
You're crazy! Surely you can't do this to Vasek.
Do you want him to tell everyone in school that Mom hasn't decided yet whether to marry Dad?
I have decided already! I don't care what Vasek will say!!
But I want him to stay alive! No one may threaten the life of my children, even their own Dad!
~ What children? Do you have children?
~ I told him what I don't want and why.
~ But he ignored it. Instead he takes him up the Dragon's Tooth!
~ The most important question is if you love him.
Love... I don't want to see him anymore. He let me down!
~ Why on Earth did I have to meet a climber!
~ You don't get to choose, girl!
When a man is not a man, he's boring.
Drivers or skydivers risk their lives every day.
~ In comparison, climbing is a safe sport.
~ Lousy men!
~ They absolutely can't value life!
~ It's not risky with Lubos.
He's just got a dangerous job. That's the male nature. And the boy inherited that from his father.
~ You'll have to put up with it.
~ With what? That he'll return with broken ribs one day?
That he'll not return at all?
I'm not going to accept that!
~ Wow, Dad and Grandpa!
~ Three, two, one, zero, hop!
~ And what about me?!
~ You're the wisest.
Prague has fifty schools and you find the right one!
Grandpa couldn't even find his way out of the station without me.
Don't trust him, Vasek!
~ I waited for him at the platform so that we can make amends for what you two have done.
~ How's life at home?
~ It's hell at home! What about Pepa?
~ Oh let Pepa be. What about Mom?
~ Still angry?
~ More and more!
~ Does she talk to you?
~ Less and less!
~ Bloody hell!
In the morning, she gets up, goes to the bathroom and closes the door, and's in there for an hour!
~ What's she doing for an hour in the bathroom?
~ Sitting in the bath, eating a dry roll, and sighing!
Then she comes out, looks at a calendar and sighs: "Oh yeah".
Maybe waiting for when you arrive.
In the evening it's even worse. We already had sour fish three times instead of steak.
~ Why?
~ Because I don't like fish!
Oh gosh, it's always trouble with women.
You just touch them and they immediately get a nerve shock!
You said that the storm would clear. But I see nothing has cleared so far.
Vasek, take care of Grandpa! And don't come home in less than two hours!
But, Grandpa, my dad doesn't have the key.
A one and a two. Arabesque.
A one and a two and brace those shoulders.
Anna!
Anna! Anna!
I've arrived!
Private business after the rehearsal!
I wanted to tell you...
I'll never do anything behind your back.
Vasek and I will always climb rocks right in front of you!
Turn!
Mom, don't be angry at Dad! I forced him to, every day!
Dad didn't want to climb rocks! He really didn't!
If only you knew how sorry Dad is! Really!
~ Don't start that again!
~ It's all my fault!
Look, if a child does not behave, you can spank him.
When an adult does not behave, there's nothing you can do.
~ And in the case of your Dad, not even a correctional centre will help.
~ Forgive us, Mom!
I can forgive all the little tricks, but this is something else.
~ You can't understand this.
~ You don't want us to be alone again?
We once were three, but it can never be two again!
Mom, Dad is here! At the Seven Climbers' Pub. He wants you to call him!
He's here! He wants to come home to me! Call him! Mommy!
You want to go to your dad?
~ Yeah.
~ Why don't you go? You'll have a lot of fun with him.
It would be sad for you. I know that!
I was sad, too, when I was here alone.
You're my little scruff. I'll tell you a secret. Do you want me to?
What would you say if a stork came to us in March?
I don't want a stork in March! I want my own Dad to come home, now!
~ Oh come on, it's just a metaphor!
~ We're going to have a baby.
~ The two of us?
~ The three of us!
Here, Colombo. I arranged everything. Absolutely!
Tomorrow at exactly nine! Ring three times! Password: kangaroo will arrive in March.
~ What's this?
~ Nothing! Vasek wants to go to the zoo.
~ Password?
~ Where's Mommy?
~ She went shopping!
Don't leave! You're staying here!
~ Password? Password?
~ Kangaroo will arrive in Tuesday. Erm, in April!
~ In March!
~ What's with a kangaroo, what is all this?
~ Kangaroos carry kids, too.
~ Oh, you want a brother.
~ I don't want a sister!
~ First they have to get married.
~ Grandpa, do you know how babies are born?
~ After the wedding!
~ I kind of thought that myself.
But it's enough if two people love each other.
~ Do you think that Mom and I love each other?
~ Of course, I tracked you the whole holiday!
If you weren't so thorough, you could actually get the brother!
Jesus Christ, they're not even married once but they're going to have two children!
~ You're a little quacker...
~ My mom always tells the truth.
~ But you're lying!
Grandpa, it would be best to put our boy under the pump soon after birth.
~ Why?
~ To see if he's tough enough!
And when he starts crawling, we'll put him on a rock to see if he can hold on.
You're way off. The boy you think will be born for your amusement will be a girl.
Honey, are you trying to tell me that our children are brought to us by a kangaroo?
How could the two of us have a girl?
Given that we're expecting a second child, we haven't had too much fun together yet...
~ Oh, really...
~ Oh, yes!
Anna!
Mom, Dad!
What's wrong with you?
~ You know what? I might send them to the zoo.
~ I know you, you'll go with them.
Anna!
Dad, Mom!