Czechoslovakia television Prague
presents
"How to pull a tooth to a whale"
written by
starring
cinematography
director
Vašek, why is there a scarf around the whale's neck?
Because she's got a toothache!
What's up, boys? Don't you want me to give you a lift?
Yes!
You know him?
Of course. He's my daddy!
And which one?
A spare one :)
That's impossible. My mum says that every prima man is already married.
Mann muss finden können :-P
Well, just like my mum!
I just took a tie, introduced myself as a minister...
...we had steaks, Pilsner beer and now we are friends.
When I grow up, I'll also deliver milk!
I'll be also work like my dad.
A claimber!
You are already here?
Yes.
I'll examine the exercise books at home,
he'll get new pyjamas
and make him turn the lights off at 8.
And Carla, no chocolate!
Aniczka, and what about dinner?
I'm going to make it by myself.
Vašek! Vašíczek!
I know that you are at home.
Wow! Somebody washed the dishes here.
Somebody probably wants an ice-cream as a reward.
My darling!
So where is my nice little boy?
Baf! (you tell this to make somebody be frightened, but as a joke)
What's that?
It's a dog.
What did you promise to me? That you'll leave all the foreign dogs alone.
It's not a foreign dog. It's Arnold!
He's able to get the dust out of the duster.
Oh please...
If you liked him, he could be ours.
And who would take care of him?
You'll take him to Valentas in the evening? And at night Carla will go with him, won't she?
If my dad was here, neither me nor the dog would have to go to Valentas.
You just decided, that you were going to make me upset.
Didn't you promise to me, that you wouldn't talk about it?
I'd also like to have a friend.
You'll get a dog. A nicer one.
But when you are older.
He's nice. He is friends with children.
He catches the second league.
Who? The dog?
No. His master. He's prima.
A goalkeeper.
Please, what are you talking about? Which goalkeeper?
Our school caretaker. You're definitely going to like him!
Why would I be supposed to like him?
Because he's not married.
So, look. You'll return that dog immediately
and I don't want to hear a word about marriage.
(ballet Romeo and Juliet)
Damn it, I'm going to have a bruise again!
Paris is a boor. But Julie should be gentle.
But it wasn't Paris, but that idiot Romeo.
Thanks.
One sunday again.
The third one in this month.
When corps from Varšava (Warschau) comes, you're going to have holiday for a whole week!
And what about rehearsals?
Don't you really want to go somewhere to have a dinner?
Vašek decided that we miss somebody at home.
How so? You explained it to him.
I thought it was over.
It was. Until his friend's mother got married.
Vašek is going to get over it. When he's older, he'll have another problems.
What if he doesn't get over it?
I hope, you're not going to reproach. After 4 years.
You can't let Vašek talk to all your stuff.
I've already forbidden him to talk abou marriage.
That's right.
It's even worse.
Yesterday he put the third bowl with a toothbrush on the shell in a bathroom.
You overstimate it everything.
I'll wait for you, won't I?
I told you it's not possible.
Vašek is at Valentas?
No, Carla is at our place.
Last you had free time 10 days ago.
If you want to, come upstairs.
You are really able to make it easier for me...
I have free time on the next sunday.
We'll go to the cinema to watch Funes. Do you want to?
Or you can invite Standa and you can play with cars.
Standa can't come now. Now he drives with that new daddy with milk.
He's got rabbits! And also a new grandpa.
Mummy... I'd also want a grandpa. At least one.
Tell me rather, where you yesterday pulled your trousers apart.
I was tracing.
A dog again?
No, a sport teacher.
Vašek?!
I'm detectiv Colombo. He's not married!
You know what, Colombo? I'll really give you a few slaps!
I'd take it. Mainly if we are going to be 3!
Look, Vašík.
If you hide the toothbrush by yourself and you wish something reasonable, I'll give it to you, right?
Come on.
All right.
You'll take me to the mountains. On these holidays.
Couldn't you wish something better? What about seaside in summer?
Why don't you ever want to go to the mountains? Because dad was a claimber?
Becuse the theater doesn't have a winter holiday.
You'll make them, then.
You will arrange it?
Of course!
And how, please?
Look!
You're my darling!
Can you ski?
I must not ski. What if I broke a leg?
Eat! We'll talk about it later.
Don't be afraid, mummy. I won't get killed like my dad.
Everybody is going to the mountains!
All of the boys have a dad, only I don't have even a dog!
My mummy.
So, children. Before we start writing, we'll recall a mummy.
How she is, what she does, how she looks like...
-And what if both of them come?
-Doesn't matter, there where 6 of them in our place.
-At one moment?!
-No, one after another.
Benda, Martinec. Put your exercise books on the table, you'll take an exercise paper
and you'll rewrite the essay after the lessons.
Please, comrade teacher, I can't do it today. I have to cook dinner.
Vašek, don't clown. Sit down!
Talk, children, how is your mummy?
Nice.
Nice-eyed.
Curly-haired.
Truthful.
Vašek!
I'm already writing it!
One, two, one, two,... (he just counts and says some ballet stuff I don't understand :-P)
Spartacus is the greatest man of antiquity and a role of Friga is a great chance for you.
It's getting dark, they are both free.
Get ready.
And go.
Everything is in the music, so listen to it.
You are happy.
This is useless... I can't work like this!
I got up at 6 o'clock.
How many opportunities do you think you are going to have?
You're going to be a retired before someone writes another ballet!
Everybody can arrange it.
-Everybody has a grandma.
-What about your mother?
You know her. She thinks that if she left for a few days,
the hospital would collapse.
So you want to leave...?
The week in february, when the school holidays are, I don't have
performances, I thought that if you left me, I would...
After what I told you?
I'm going to compensate all the rehearsals.
I'm nearly at all at home. I can't stand the boy!
That's out of the question. You're not going anywhere!
(there is a voice from radio, which talks about claimbers, who are on Mount Everest)
Oh my god! Leave it alone, please. The steaks were supposed to be on sunday.
Go to wash yourself.
I wonder that you can listen to it...
You bought a beer?
I'm asking you, why you bought the beer?
I thought he would come.
Who?
Minister.
Aniczka? You should go.
You know what, Carla? Vašek can take TV to his room.
There's Chaplin at 19:30.
I don't want Chaplin. I want you to be at home! Just like a right mum...
To make Vašek to be a main class cleaner is just like
making a goat to be a gardener.
But this week he was better.
It was really cleaned in the class and in addition
he was helping the school caretaker and sport teacher.
I thought he did something wrong, when you called me to the theater.
We wrote and essay yesterday.
Please, don't tell Vašek that I let you read it.
He's a mug. "Mummy is going to get married." Such a nonsense.
Do you know, what is the best about children?
That they can see a world, how it is supposted to be.
And their world is mainly harmonic home.
And what would you do, if you were me, Mrs. teacher?
I would at least think about it, mummy.
You're going to let me go to the mountains.
You'd have to resign in the theater.
I can also break up with you.
Mummy! Mummy is here.
You don't even speak to me...
Guess, who came to have dinner with us?
If it didn't involve us, we could just laugh at the Vašek's ideas.
That's really funny to make steaks for school caretaker...
Do you go somewhere in the evening?
To theater.
Why don't you call me? If I don't have night shift, I'll be able
to wait here with Vašek until 11.
And in the evening you'll go through the whole Praha.
And what about Jindrich?
If he had children, I wouldn't say a word. But in this situation...
Do you think, this is a life, Anna?
Er hat mich gern :-P
Then why doesn't he finally get divorced?
Please, let it be.
All right then.
I'll talk to Jindrich by myself.
You've never meddle.
I'm not going to humiliate myself.
You behave just like the life hasn't learnt you enough.
How long do you want to handle it by yourself?
It's hard with you, Anna.
When I told you in that situation a baby shouldn't be born,
you didn't talk to me for a half year.
You did it your way.
You didn't know what was going to meet you.
Talk to Jindrich. You'll rescue yourself only if you get married.
You can always give me an advise. But you can't
help me and take Vašek to the mountains.
I've already told you that mothers with children will
get holiday in that school holidays week.
Then I have bad luck, that I don't work as a surgery nurse.
I'll take Vašek to my place.
No, that wouldn't help. All the people in the house
know me, somebody could tell Vašek something...
Once Vašek will know it anyway.
How long are you going to hide it from him?
Many children live only with a mother.
Aren't there divorced marriages?
But you are not divorced...
Come on, little dog, come on. Don't be afraid. This is my mummy.
Send that calf away immediately!
Mummy! What about me??
Mummy, why was uncle Jindrich at the train station with a flower?
He came to tell me not to break a leg.
You like him?
A lot.
But it's also going to cost a lot of money.
I meant Jindrich.
Why are you talking about it again?
I don't like him. I'd know about better guys.
Vašek, I'm warning you. I took you here with one
condition - that you'll stop finding me a groom.
You can rely on me.
Daddy, daddy, I can't find sticks!
Then buy a medicine against sclerosis.
Thank you. Mrs. Bendová, you have telegram here.
Here.
I need to call Praha. Quickly. And
second call at 7 pm.
All right.
Vašek! You won't leave terrace until I come!
Of course!
Attention!
I'm going!
Out of the way!
Attention!
I'm going!
Stupid boy! If I were your dad, I would beat your
buttocks that you wouldn't be able to sit for a week!
-Are you ok?
-Yes.
-What about your legs?
-Tangled.
Stand up then.
-Where are you from?
-From a Snowhite!
From a Snowhite? Hm. I'm really happy.
With who are you here? Why are you looking at me?
With who are you here?
With mum, of course!
Take your ski and go.
Hey, sir, are you married?
Vašek, Vašíczek, come quickly!
This sweater really suits you, you are very nice in it.
How so you are not wearing pyjamas?
Am I supposted to go to the dinner in pyjamas?
No. We are going to have dinner here.
Mum, Mummy, I want to go to a bar. At least for an ice-cream.
No, you have a lot of sins today and I have ordered a call.
Mummy, I arranged something. He's going to wait there for me.
Who?
One of my friends.
I'll return in a while.
And you - stay at the room, do you understand?
Anna.
Oh wow, you grew up! Even though you are still so small.
You don't remember me.
-I...
-Don't you remember?
I'm waiting here.
I'm sorry.
No, the telegram wasn't sent by Jindrich, but by theater.
Mummy... Please, come and stay at least those 2 days.
I can't tell Vašek that we've just arrived
and we are going to go home again.
I'm going to return on thursday.
It's not important, who's sick.
There's just change in the theater.
We can't do anything then.
-How much is it?
.Moment. I'll ask the post office.
How many years haven't we seen each other?
You are on holiday here? As an instructor again?
I've been here for 7 years.
Here?
Here I have a date with one boy.
With a boy?
I even don't know his name. I promised him to have an ice-cream
with him in the evening and I've met you here!
You are better and better. Instead of shot
you invite boys for and ice-cream?
But he's really small. You haven't seen such boy yet.
He told me his mummy loves dancing and if I wanted,
he could take her with him.
Please, why are you telling me?
Well, you asked me what I was doing here.
Maybe we'll meet again.
Definitely.
So don't delay yourself. Don't make him waiting in the bar.
He isn't waiting in a bar. He's there.
Vašek! Come here!
You have a prima boy.
He's wild. What is this?
That's a jacket.
Say goodbye and go to bed.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Praha. Who wanted to pay the Praha?
I'll pay it.
Mummy! Mummy! Open! I didn't tell anything! Really!
Mummy! Open!
Vašek, you are going to worry me to death. What did you tell him?
Only number of our room.
And you invited him, didn't you?
Yes, I wanted you to look at him.
What?
If we liked him, that we could be friends with him.
That's all.
Pack your stuff up. We're going home.
Tomorrow.
Mountain Rescue.
No. He's on the hill.
What are you doing here?
I came for help.
What happened?
Mummy forbade me to talk about the goodbye.
About what?
That we are going home today.
She promises to return, but we won't return.
I know her!
You finally call. How is it on the hill?
If mum knew that I'm under chief's control...
Snowslip situation?
I'll take care of myself anyway. I'll sweep, I'll do laundry.
When it's warmer, when it's warmer.
Warn these destinations immediately.
Please, sir, let me stay here.
I'm made for mountains.
So you want to work here? How many years?
2 days. Before mum comes.
Who's that boy?
Well, he's such Dokey from Snowhite, isn't he?
You make jokes and there's blocked
groomer in Labský dùl.
I've been happy for that for a half hour now.
Call Karel. I'll be there.
And what about me?
You know what?
Right man never begs.
If it helps you, you can leave the boy here.
Vašek?
You have more boys?
It's hard for him. He's just come and must back to the town.
Well, he'll get over it.
There are things, which no woman can understand.
Simply - I'll take care of Vašek for those 2 days.
I don't understand why.
We haven't opportunity to talk yet.
I'll be sure that you're going to return.
You would be able to take care of a child??
You can rely on me!
I'm not sure.
Vašek, we'll go to Rokytnice for sticks.
And we'll take mum to the train station.
Vašek, you're really going to let me go alone?
You've already allowed me that. Don't worry.
Luboš rescues people from snowslips!
What do you mean - Luboš? It's always Mr. Richman for you!
Mummy doesn't know that we've been already friends for 2 hours.
Vašek is coming with me!
You have a great seat at the window.
Don't worry, I took care of the whole section.
I'll die from fear anyway.
That would be a pitty.
Mummy is prima. She started "duzing".
Bye.
How did you recognise that I'm a claimber?
I'm detectiv Colombo. You have crampons in your cabin.
You know what it is??
Of course!
Metal boots for climbing.
Look, where you are throwing the snow!
And what is Chomolungma?
Mount Everest. Hillary and Tenzing were the first people there.
And which mountain over 8000m high was first visited by people?
Annapurna.
And where were the most dead people?
Nanga Parbat
And who was the first up there?
Hermann Buhl. He's my second favourite. After my daddy.
You are good.
I have books. Not humbled mountain. Tigers from Himalaya. That's on radio.
-Done?
-Done!
Go!
And who buys that books for you?
Daddy?
Daddy was also a claimber!
And what does he do now?
Now he's dead.
Don't be mad with me, Vašek, I haven't known that.
When they were coming down, he was the last one.
And suddenly there was a snowslip.
Wow! We rescued a groomer!
You'll take my sleeping bag.
One my friend once also borrowed it.
He got intestinal flu. That's really bad, when there's 20 degrees under 0.
And where did you sleep?
Well, we didn't sleep.
Do you have a lot of friends?
No, I have know a lot of people.
Friends are boys who you can always rely on.
Mum says that daddy had no friends.
That's weird.
When you hold the same rope with somebody,
you must trust him. You cover his back and he covers yours.
Then there's a real friendship.
Maybe mum thinks that somebody could rescue him. Some his friend.
I'd like to call Špindlerùv mlýn, 93439. Thank you.
You can call it off.
He called himself.
Who?
Špindl (= Špindlerùv mlýn)
He told me to write it. I might have sclerosis...
Vašek ate 7 dumplings, brushed his teeth and now he's sleeping.
He's idiot. He makes fun of me.
But he called 1 hour later, that there's snowing outside and that he can't fall asleep.
Boženka, I'm hungry!
Today you were great, Anna.
You made me really happy.
That is probably because I took a nap in the afternoon.
Took a nap? She was sleeping here for 3 hours as if she was dead.
Am I allowed to invite you for a dinner?
Oh my god...
I'll make 7 pieces of him!
Why did you try do make fire?
I just wanted to make toasts for you.
It's already on fire! You can rely on me.
You can rely on me too.
Look. I borrowed these boots for you.
You could wear your boots to the dancing lessons.
Luboš, how does a man become a real claimber?
When he claimbs a first hill.
Which one?
That's not important.
When you like it, you'are going to be claimber for a whole life!
How?
Where to put your hands, legs, how to be warm.
That's simple. You make a mistake and you're dead.
I don't know... I'm sure my dad didn't make a mistake!
I meant it another way.
A proper man is the most happy, when he can overcome the obsticles.
My dad was proper! Strong! One head taller than you.
Of course. The best man goes always the last.
You were never afraid?
When you want to win, to beat a 8000m high mountain,
which has been here for millions ages, you must have self esteem.
So you weren't afraid.
I was afraid.
The wind in Himalayas sound like coming train!
Once it made me cry.
My dad was also in Himalayas.
Why didn't you return?
At night? We couldn't see.
And in the morning?
We started getting to the peak.
You managed it?
It was the happiest day in my life.
The sun rose. There was silent. Only rocks and ice.
You stand there and it seems like you are God.
I'm also going to be God! But mum can't know that!
A lot of people think that every claimber is crazy.
I'm crazy.
I can see that. You're outting salt into your tea!
Hold tight!
(They just count or say nothing important ;-))
I was at lawyer.
You buy or sell anything?
At divorce lawyer.
What if we 2 tried it with rules?
I only don't know if I will get used to Vašek.
Do you know how to pull a tooth to a whale?
You make a sea crane, you give a wagon of ? to a whale,
you prepare dynamit, 3, 2, 1, bum!
What are you laughing at?
I've never kissed a guy.
How so? You didn't like your dad?
I did! But I didn't know him yet.
-Listen, friend, aren't you accidentally a little babbler?
-Accidentally a big one!
Your dad was one head taller than me in the morning
and now you don't know him?
In that time I was little like this.
Mummy didn't get married again?
No. I'd also like a daddy. Standa has already a third one.
Mummy probably loved daddy a lot.
When somebody loves somebody, he can't forget him.
You'd be surprised how angry she is when I draw Annapurna.
Your daddy was at Annapurna?
Of course. There's his grave.
I was also at Annapurna.
With my daddy?
No, all of us returned home.
My daddy was in the special expedition.
They examined soil under the ice-berg.
Look, I'm a great dressmaker.
Wait, wait, wait.You want to claim
that your daddy was in expedition Annapurna with special geologic programm?
Of course.
And when was it?
When I was little like this.
Vašek, Vašek, what are you playing at me?
You were little like this and you remember that your dad had shoulders like this?
I have a photo at home.
And you've never seen your dad?
I'm telling you, that I was little like this.
And what is it, little like this? What is it?
When I was in my mummy's belly!
You're 8 years old?
Yes.
And you were born in... September?
Damn it, you can see the future.
What are you doing?
I'm trying how snow is going to be tomorrow.
You don't have to do every crap like me.
Vašek, what would you say if I tried dating your mummy?
You would try it?
Would try it... I'll try it!
You like my mum?
-I like YOU!
-I like you too!
-Luboš, you must be careful!
-About what?
That trying! Mum doesn't want to hear a word about marriage.
She nearly beaten me!
I'll do what I can.
-Vašek!
-Mummy!
What are you doing?
We arranged that, didn't we?
Yes, but kissing was Luboš's idea!
Stand up, lazy people! Stand up!
One, two, one,... :)
The boy skies great, what do you think?
(I just can't explain what he's telling her,
he's just teaching her skiing :))
Anna, when did we date each other?
Do you know that I really can't remember?
I think, we could count it.
You were at the conservatory.
It's not important today.
And hadn't it been before I went to Annapurna?
I really don't know.
If you think...
It only seems to me that Vašek wants to look like me.
As if I was his daddy.
Well, it probably only seems like that.
Probably.
Vašek wants to look like everybody.
It was a school caretaker last time.
But school caretaker isn't a claimber.
Whose grave is under a snowslip.
To our last evening.
Why did you take me here?
I think it's really long time you weren't dancing.
Everything is like at these times.
No. Nothing can be repeated.
I'm leaving to Alps in a month.
Before that I'm going to be in Prague for a few days.
Think about the "datum" until that time.
Which datum?
You arranged me a funural - I'm going to arrange you a marriage.
Wait, who am I going to marry?
Me of course.
I even didn't get married.
I haven't told you yet?
I have so miserable memory...
And you remembered that we had been here at these times?
There was the only music box here 9 years ago.
Do you remember about our bet
that you would bring a flower in 10 minutes?
And I lost.
No. Mountain rescue called about emergency situation.
A man lost in Obøí dùl.
I'm glad that you remember details.
You rescued that man.
You return after midnight.
And why didn't you get married?
I was always more affected by mountains.
And what about now?
Now I'm not strong enough for the hills.
By that you mean you'd be strong enough for me.
No. For our boy.
You don't have to tell me anything.
I won't reproach. We knew each other for 14 days.
9 days.
You dated somebody. And I was in the way.
And what were you doing for that 8 years?
Who did you want to marry anyway?
Vašek is not your son.
You are lying. We met here. In december.
I went to Himalayas in january. And the boy was born in september.
We returned from expedition in november. All of us.
-Nobody stayed on Annapurna under a snowslip.
-I hope you won't be so stupid and you won't tell Vašek.
If this is your point - you can rely on me.
I was so happy with my friends that
I didn't realise I was living alone.
For example this Christmas.
There were a lot of people around me and no "my" person.
And when I started thinking about it,
so prima boy appeared.
And in addition - mine.
Anna. Say it to me.
I'm beging you...
Tell me he's mine.
Please, don't be crazy.
I hoped I wouldn't meet you again.
If somebody is in my way today,
I'll put him in the sack and I'll throw itto the river!
You can guess, you can count,
but you don't have a proof that Vašek is yours.
I do.
He's as great as me!
Where were you running?
To a train station. Luboš is coming today!
Which Luboš?
My daddy!
A spare one.
So mum found somebody?
No. I found him by myself!
He wrote 9 letters to him!
What is he like?
A big one. A chief of a mountain rescue.
Mum has a first general rehearsal.
We should wait outside.
Let's go inside then!
This is mum?
Damn it, she's great.
We're going to sleep in one room.
And who's the guy?
Uncle Jindrich.
I don't like him!
He's not confident and doesn't like dogs.
Then we'll put him in the sack
and we'll throw him into the river.
Enough!
This is Annapurna.
And up there?
Also Annapurna. Also Annapurna.
I screwed this one. This was in december.
This was when I was 5.
And why is there a christmas tree and those presents?
For ym daddy of course.
To bring him company.
-I'll take you with me.
-Really?
When you are adult.
-Do you have that photo?
It's hidden.
Then show it to me.
I don't want mummy to steal it.
Let me guess, will you?
Am I right?
You knew my daddy?
Are you able to be silent?
In front of your mum?
This is me.
It's not you! It's my dad!
It's your dad, but it's also me!
What does it mean?
I don't know!
That I'm your dad.
That's not true!
It's not you! It's my dad!
Why couldn't it be me?
My dad is dead! A hero!
What are you doing here?
Luboš is lying.
Anna, please, don't be mad with me.
I told Vašek.
You are egotistical.
Idiot.
Do you have a knife?
I've been collecting these cars for 5 years.
All of them are yours now.
You can't take him serious, mum.
He's a babbler.
And don't swear at him.
He's going to have dinner with us.
I'll help you.
Me too.
Mummy, how so Luboš knew my dad?
I didn't know him.
Why is he lying?
You pointed at him.
Were you his friend?
I don't know.
But I know!
You left him under a snowslip!
Damn it!
Say something, Anna.
Leave me alone. Both of you.
I'll tell you something.
If my dad was allive, he would be
at home with me every evening.
He would go to the cinema with me.
And we would have a dog.
But your dad didn't know
that you exist.
If he knew, he would visit you.
And why didn't he visit mum?
He knew she exists.
Mum, is he my dad?
Is he or not?
I want to know it!
Yes, this is your dad.
You screwed it. Everything.
Let mum be! Go away!
Mummy, don't cry.
He's already away.
You've got me. I'm going to be with you.
Until we die. Every day.
Look, my dad is as exact as a clock.
Your mother called.
She made a meeting with me.
Tomorrow.
Don't you know, what she wants to tell me?
I can imagine that. To make you get divorced.
And you don't want to?
I haven't been wishing anything else for 4 years.
Maybe it would be worth it.
To talk about us.
You should meet Vašek. Not me.
I've been waiting in fornt of the school for 1 hour.
So?
Nothing.
Why didn't you listen to me?
I knew Vašek would never understand.
Can I visit you?
At 4? At 5?
You aren't interested in who was it??
I'll come in the evening.
I don't even know you!
You don't know anything about me either...
And you made Vašek think we're going to live together.
I'm afraid he doesn't want to talk to me.
You could have written a letter.
I read about your return from Himalayas
in the newspapers.
Why didn't you write you were pregnant?
Where? To Asia?
Camp number 4?
I returned.
The boy was nearly 3 months.
Why did you want Vašek to never know me?
What did I do to you?
I... I was kind of proud to be pregnant with you.
I thought you were hero, when
you rescued that man in Obøí dùl.
I thought...
I thought you were going to be happy when you return.
That I'm as brave as you.
That I kept the baby.
But if you wrote the boy was born...
You didn't even recall me
and you'd be so happy to have a baby.
When are you leaving?
In 4 days.
Vašek needs time to get over it.
If children could understand everything,
they wouldn't be children.
Because there are more differences between children
and adults, not only that children are small and adults are big.
It was also my fault.
It wasn't.
Vašík, did you want a dad? You did.
You liked Luboš.
You said he was a friend.
He is not, mum.
I cried for him while he was in the mountains with foreign friends.
Luboš didn't know about you.
You must trust me!
He cheated me.
He lied to me in the mountains already.
He pretended to try dating you,
and you got married a long time ago.
We didn't.
When I was young, I trusted you
that you bought me in a shop.
But now I'm old enough to know
how babies are born.
Really?
After marriage.
Well... Marriage isn't the main thing.
It can happen when people love each other.
If he loved you, mum,
he would visit us on saturday or when it's my birthday.
You are stubborn just like your little tooth.
We've been persuading it for 2 hours
and it doesn't give in.
But when it grows up, it won't hurt anymore, will it?
Luboš will be waiting for you tomorrow in front of the school.
I won't go there.
I told him.
I did what I could.
It depends on you.
I'm going to gargle.
Vašík, you are a goon. Such beautiful pictures...
Why did you destroy them?
I won't be a claimber anymore.
You've got prima bike. You are good at it.
I've bought new equipment.
I have it in hotel. Don't you want to have a look?
I've brought you something.
Do you like him?
I'm not allowed to bring foreign dogs.
He's not a foreign dog. He's Ben.
Keep him. He's yours.
And what about mum? Won't she beat me?
Don't worry. She'll be happy.
You're lying! And you're teaching mum to lie.
You talk about me via phone.
I let you go to the mountains not to loose you
and there you forgot me in one day.
It's quite funny actually.
When a man is afraid, he's about to loose.
You really want to go to a hospital?
No. Your mother invited me in your place.
I would have to know that, wouldn't I?
You won't invite me upstairs?
You shouldn't have gone with me.
Anna, would you mind Vašek having a dog?
No way.
That's a disaster...
Don't worry! I'll fix it!
Leave me alone. Both of you!
Where is he?
Who? Vašek or that dog?
Jindrich of course!
You went crazy.
All of you.
Mummy, are you glad that we have Beník?
Of course.
Go to wash. Don't play.
Come, Beník, we'll make a beautiful dog out of you.
Luboš has a dad in Kamenice. They have rabbits.
Also a cat. A pig.
You would have a grandpa.
You always wished a grandpa, didn't you?
Enough. Everybody can screw something nice.
Also me or Luboš. But you're a prima boy.
And it was quite good idea with those toothbrushes!
-There should be 3 people in every family.
-We are 3. You, me and a dog.
What's up?
Today I've been waiting for 2 hours.
I can't make Vašek talk to you.
He didn't even show up.
He's more faithless than a mountain.
Anna, I'll wont make it...
Vašek was waiting for you for 8 years
and you give it up in several days?
But I'm leaving tomorrow!
What if you didn't go to the mountains?
I can't leave my friends.
You're just like a snowslip.
You made me a grave, Anna!
I wouldn't make that...
I wouldn't make to read in the newspaper
that somebody is allive and make him funural.
And what was I supposed to tell Vašek,
when he started asking about dad?
You waited for me 1 more year,
before he'd sterted talking?
3 more years,
before he'd started thinking.
If there was an idiot in this world,
it was me.
You don't need to apologize.
I don't care about you today.
Don't say that...
There's our 8 years old boy to be stubborn.
Aniczka, you must go!
Moment, moment.
Wednesday is a visit day.
There's my wife here.
Vašek's got lost.
What are you making up?
When I rang and told him about your broken leg,
he just went crazy.
Before I packed your stuff up,
he was gone.
I've been looking for him for an hour.
Please, don't panic,
now he's already at home.
He's been already here?
There are many hospitals in Praha
and he found the right one.
We have a clever child, don't we?
Why is she staring at us?
She's my mother.
Look after his homework
and put the keys into the mailbox before you leave.
Go.
What a behaviour! So you have a child together?!
Then explain to me...
He was that rascal??
If they don't make peace, I will die...
Why didn't you tell me about having grandma in a hospital?
Can you imagine how frightened I was?
I'll spend the night here.
You don't have to go to Valentas.
I couldn't come today.
Why?
I had a punishment.
A bummer, isn't it?
Mum has to go to school.
And why?
I didn't want to write an essay.
You know what?
I'll go to school instead of mummy.
But you are leaving tomorrow.
I'll stay here with you.
You'll go.
I'll arange it with mum.
Girls don't know anything about friendship.
And you do?
I do.
I've already written that essay.
What does my dad do?
My dad is a chief of Mountain rescue. He does what he says.
He waits for me in front of the school at 3 o'clock.
He's reliable. He bought me a dog.
He's got experience because he¨s a claimber.
He claimbed a 8000m high mountain.
He gets over all obsticles.
He's a good friend.
Do you know how to pull a tooth to a kangaroo?
You make a sea crane, you prepare dynamit...
It wasn't a kangaroo, it was a whale!
That's not important.
It is! Because you have to give dynamit to a whale.
Kangaroo would visit a dentist.
3, 2, 1!