Into the corner!
- Calm down. Coming for lunch?
- Whom do you have here?
- Just Zubor and a few animals.
- We'll take a look.
Two, three, four.
Two beggars eat from four plates?
You'd better not go there.
Frankie is sleeping there.
He hasn't eaten yet.
Might tear up your pants.
Who's Frankie?
This should scare me?
- You know better.
- And who eats from the fourth plate?
- Mike. - And who's that?
Frankie's father, a nasty fighter.
Yesterday he tore two of my dogs
to pieces. Shall I wake him up? Mike!
- No, we're in a hurry. - Come on out!
The gentlemen want to see you!
On the horses, let's be off!
To the table.
You've come such a distance.
You must have set off at dawn. Why?
- I wanted to see you.
- And why did you want to see me?
Because...
Because I liked the way
you saved the boy from punishment.
Me? He just chose the right hand, that's all.
And what was in your other hand?
You saw it? You have sharp eyes.
Sharp by name, sharp by nature.
I must be back by sunset.
My parents don't want us
to meet until the wedding.
I told them I would go hunting.
I haven't behaved honestly.
I think...
I can forgive you.
- You should go now.
- I'd like to see you again soon.
Better not. Do you want to spend your horse?
But the day after tomorrow
I'll be passing this way.
Thomas! Are you mad? Here... by the castle!
The constables are looking for you.
Father will have you caned.
You wouldn't survive it!
I just wanted to tell you...
My grandpa said...
I grow really fast. Soon I'll be grown up...
and strong like my father was.
If you could just wait I could be your...
Tom, I know...
I just thought Ostrik could find
another girl... I'd help him.
You saw us?
You know, I like Ostrik, I do.
And I love him.
To fall in love with my future husband...
I can call myself lucky.
It's not always like that.
I wish you all the luck.
For good luck... may it stay with you.
You're a nice boy.
Perun, go.
Thomas, come here.
I've been training him for months.
He's good but unpredictable.
Tie this to his foot.
And how is Formina?
What do you know about her?
Only what you talk about...
in your sleep. Wash your eyes,
they are a little red.
It's hopeless.
Tatar! Halt! Back!
The fox must be rabid.
We have to kill it or
it'll infect all our animals.
What has got into you?
He'll never come back.
What have you done? I tried everything...
I told him a falcon should not
behave like a donkey.
From now on, you train him.
Look... Thomas is sending us his greetings.
Frankie, come and have a bath!
- Won't you miss him? - I will.
But I know a better one.
A falcon beyond compare!
I know which one you mean.
I nearly trapped him with my net.
He's the king of all falcons.
- Shall I stop at your Grandpa's? - No need.
- You'll meet him at the castle.
- How do you know?
The falcon told me.
Hey, catch!
It's for Formina.
You can't go in there!
His lordship has forbidden it.
- I've come to beg for my grandson.
- First I want to know where he is.
- Speak! - I don't know, my lord.
- On my honour I don't know.
- You don't know? I don't believe you!
- You should, my lord. - Vagan!
- Metod is an honest man.
- You've come to tell me that?
- I've brought you a falcon, my lord.
- And that's why I should believe you?
- This one is better than
- the one lver stole from me.
- Liar! Can you prove that?
Tell his lordship who gave you this scar.
You can keep your field
unless you deliver me Thomas.
If I find him myself
his punishment will be worse.
Get lost, you old fool.
I like him. We'll try him after lunch.
I saw a rat in the tower.
- Lf Balador sees it...
Where is the rat poison? - Over there.
But careful with it.
- You're not saying much, Vagan.
- Because I know little.
This morning you spoke more.
Now I know even less
than I did this morning.
What counts is the falcon knows
what he has to know.
Let us begin.
Where is he flying?
You wanted to make a fool of me?
You've brought me a carcass.
The rabbit gave him heart attack!
Did you poison my falcon?
- I know nothing.
- And you brother "the falconer"?
- I've seen nothing.
- 'Cause you didn't want to see!
You're lucky I don't like
when people get whipped.
And tell lver to stay out of my way.
He's got one scar already.
My lady...
- Vagan! - I've got something for you.
You know where Thomas is?
Tell him, I'd like to dance with him
one more time before I get married.
Let's go.
Hey, hands off from the nest!
You'll pay for this.
I'm Lord Balador's falconer!
- I'm following his orders.
- Liar! You're stealing the eggs.
Nonsense. You've hurt my arm. Help me...
He was stealing falcon eggs
and Lord Balador is looking for him
- because of Perun. - Put him down!
Move back!
Lord Balador will punish everyone
who helps him escape and...
Shut up, lver. Now you listen to me!
You poisoned the falcon.
You used to be my pupil,
taught you everything.
And you've turned out to be a filthy thief.
Look: Hawk, sparrow hawk, peregrine.
The falconer robs his lord.
Stop that evil man!
Shoot him yourself if you feel like that...
He poisoned our falcon, alas!
We won't find a better one.
And what about that one?
It's him. The falcon king.
For him Balador would forgive you everything.
He'd also give me a castle.
Repair it! Stitch it again!
- Does it suit me?
- You're a beautiful bride.
Enchanting.
Sugar...
Get lost!
My lord, I trained the falcon
you gonna give to Ostrik...
- What do you want? Spit it out!
- Could I be the head falconer?
- Your time will come.
- You should know that Vagan...
Do you know anything else
besides tale-bearing?
We're slow. I have to exercise my horse.
I'll meet you at the castle.
- Still the same hothead.
- Don't worry, he'll get tamed soon.
- And where is Ostrik? - He has to be here any moment now.
He rode ahead, was impatient.
He's savouring the last moments
of his freedom. Please...
What do you want from me?
I'm thirsty.
I know you!
You made a big mistake.
Now you won't get out alive.
I'm not going to the gallows.
Why are you holding me here?
What are you up to?
It's none of your business.
I'm settling accounts.
If I discover a corpse here,
a reward would not come amiss.
I'm going to bed. If Ostrik appears
tell the maid to wake me up!
- I'd like to talk to him.
- No trace at all, nothing, my lord.
It's not possible! Looks like he
disappeared into thin air!
Take more men and keep
looking until you find him!
And bring us new candles.
Fly!
- We're looking for Ostrik.
- What would he do here?
We'll see. Search the place!
Stand up. Let's go.
Here's another one.
And here's the evidence!
Tie them up. They are criminals!
It belongs to Ostrik.
I gave it to him myself.
We found it in Vagan's cottage.
- I bet they've robbed and murdered Ostrik.
- Vagan!
And Thomas! At last I've got you.
Where is Ostrik?
You're asking us? We know nothing.
We weren't invited to the wedding.
Thomas...
- Where is Ostrik?
- I drowned him in the mud. - Be serious!
- Do you know anything about him?
- Let me go and I'll find him.
Put them into the torture chamber!
The judge will try them!
- What have you found out?
- They denied everything stubbornly.
But the small one, Zubor, gave them away.
When he saw the red-hot iron
he nodded to everything.
- Anyway, this evidence is undeniable.
- And your verdict?
A life for a life, Your Highness.
Start buidilng the gallows.
And hurry up!
Thank you.
Thomas!
I begged my father but he doesn't want
to listen. I can't help you.
Tell me, what have you done to Ostrik?
If you believe we're able to kill
you'd better go. Get out of my sight!
Wait!
Watch out!
I'll be back for you.
Be careful.
I'll find Ostrik for you even in hell.
Find Ostrik, find him.
What are you looking at?
You can't help me.
Sign here, my lord.
Father, how can you believe
Vagan or Thomas to be murderers?!
You can't send them to death.
Ostrik will return, I'm sure.
I believe he's alive because I love him.
Hey, help me! I'm here!
- You're all right? - My leg...
- How did you find me?
- Not me... he did.
He flew around my ears and
shouted "help Ostrik". So I came.
I had nothing else to do. Come on.
You understand the bird speech,
you suckling?
Sometimes better than the human speech,
you bridegroom!
- I've seen you somewhere.
- Maybe in the mud? - You're that dancer...
that insolent boy!
I wanted to give you a good hiding!
When you get well we can fight.
But now hold on so that
I don't lose you on the way.
These criminals have caused deep grief...
to Lord Donat, his wife, my daughter
Formina and to us all.
The judge decided they should be
hanged for their evil deed.
- My spur was the only evidence?
- Yeah. It was enough for the judge.
A judge like that ought
to get hanged himself! Wait.
- I've still got the other one.
- Other what?
- The other spur! - And I've got the falcon.
Fly!
...justice. A life for a life!
Hangman,
do your business!
Here with it!
- Ostrik! - Hangman, hold it!
I am here! Stop that!
Ostrik!
He's injured.
That's the man who wanted to kill me!
- Iver! - Let me go!
Ostrik...
Formina...
We almost executed innocent men.
Iver indicated to me
it was your wish, my lord...
You should follow the law
and your conscience, not lver.
I don't need a judge like that.
You'll go to the stocks.
- You're pale. - Just tired.
Come on, let's go.
- Thomas! - You little wanderer.
Do I have to cut the wood myself?
Grandpa, come on...
I'll forgive you Perun...
Haven't you worn out my bay?
- No. Anyway, it belongs to Ostrik now.
- You're forgetting something.
My lord.
It's the falcon king.
How did you achieve that?
I've promised a castle for him.
Now you are lord of a castle.
I don't want a castle. I'll keep the falcon.
In that case I'll make you my head falconer.
You've already got Vagan.
But when you go hunting...
- I will borrow you the falcon... my lord.
- My lord.
My lord...
I have wronged you, falconer.
You decide on his punishment.
I grant him mercy. But I will not ever
see him again in this region.
So be it.
Thank you for Ostrik and for me, Thomas.
- Without your help he wouldn't be here.
- I'd like to dance from joy.
But Ostrik can't.
Would you substitute for him?
It is not proper under the gallows.
Besides, I miss the healing mud.
Keep it.
Leave it now. Go...
- We've come for you.
- Would you like to come with us?
I need a good falconer.
I'll think about it.
Maybe I'll fly to you one day.
The sooner the better.
Subtitles: Barbora Rázová, Bratislava
Produced by
Director of Photography
Directed by