Did you enjoy that?
We'll show Lord Balador the falconer
Vagan is still good at his craft.
Tomorrow you'll go to the castle.
Damned Vagan!
Beautiful...
Vagan promised me one like this.
I've been training it secretely for a year.
For you, my lord.
- Vagan is an old braggart.
- Stop it. I've heard enough!
Well, people talk, my lord.
Here you are...
Wonderful, indeed.
Once hunting, I caught sight
of the famous King Mathew's falcon.
For that falcon I'd give my castle
on the Danube.
Nobody can catch that one, my lord.
Producer
Come on, this way! Faster!
In coproduction with
supported by the Slovak State Fund
and the Fund of the Council of Europe
present
THOMAS THE FALCONER
Based on the book by
Jozef Cíger Hronský
Screenplay
Featuring
Photographed by
Directed by
- Tomorrow we'll saddle the bay.
- God help us.
Father, Thomas! Lunch!
Hurry up, men,
Grandpa is starving.
Come on, son.
Here you are.
Grandpa, it's not just for you.
Thomas!
Hey, calm down. I've heard you.
It's all right now.
Damned fool.
- You wanna get your ribs broken?
- The bay is death-ridden.
Yesterday you said
you were at death's door.
Right, but the door was sealed.
Death is scared of me.
Thomas, don't do that any more.
Oh, my...
How did you know about the thorn?
The bay was complaining.
Are you deaf?
We are all deaf except for
master Thomas.
What did you tell her?
To throw a cone at you
if you don't stop neighing.
Liar! You liar!
Just you wait.
You robber...
With that whip of yours I'll change
the bay into a lamb tomorrow.
You touch the stud and Lord Balador
will get you caned.
- The bay cost him forty cows.
- And it's worth it, I'm telling you.
I've never seen
such a beauty in my life.
- Ostrik'll get the stud as a wedding gift.
- And he'll ride away on it...
- with beautiful Formina.
- And who is Formina?
He doesn't know who Formina is!
Lord Balador's daughter, born on the same
day as you only a year earlier.
The day you were born, at the castle
they celebrated her first birthday.
- So we're actually siblings.
- And I'm your Grandma! - Shut up.
- Forty cows for such a horse...
- Tell me about her. - Wait a moment.
Balador has offered a castle
for a falcon, just imagine.
The one with the golden crest?
The falcon belonged to the King
of Hungary. It saved his life.
People say so...
Once King Mathew got lost in the marsh.
He would have died there,
but his hunting falcon
showed him the way out.
- The King rewarded the bird with
a golden crest. - And set it free.
- What do you know about it?
- Nothing. Everyone'd do so, I guess.
Our smart Thomas
knows better than anyone.
You're lucky the marten is asleep.
- The little beast...
- It's your birthday in a few days...
Here's your present.
Wolves...
- The wolves! - Light up a big fire.
We'll drive them off.
You go left, I'll go right.
We'll meet back there.
You stay by the fire.
Thomas!
Put more wood to the fire!
- Are you okay? - Yeah!
Over here guys, help me!
I've got no fire!
Oh, God...
Thomas, come back!
Father...
- Mama won't be lonesome any more.
- Now they are together again.
Thomas. Come on, let's go home.
What for? Balador will hire a new herdsman
and we can go begging.
Forward, jump! And back!
Sit...
Perun, fetch!
Bravo, Perun!
Me and my brother, we've prepared
a little surprise for you.
You are free. Run!
- What's this? - Be patient, my lord.
Perun, get him!
Let go!
- Perun, come here! - Wild beast.
- Isn't the lad hurt? - He deserved it.
- Broke a jug... - That's all?
And put the splinters into the dog food.
Perun could've died.
Punish him. But not like this.
According to the law.
Put him to the stocks and then cane him.
I'll plead with Lord Balador for
a piece of land. He'll remember me.
Once he went hunting and passed by...
I bowed and he waved at me.
He must remember me.
He will not let us go begging.
Again the little beast of yours...
You do it yourself!
- What have you done to her now?
- Nothing.
- Grandpa, can I come along?
- To the castle? No way.
You'd mess something up
and come to a bad end.
- I'd like to see Formina. - What for?
Maybe she'd dance with me.
You won't even get close to her.
If by chance you did,
Balador would burn your heels.
Come on!
Get up!
I'll finish you.
Loser! Loser!
Send for the healing mud.
My back was aching last night.
- Your husband is a weakling.
- I like him the way he is, Father.
Perun, to me.
Sit!
For you Formina, I've chosen
a better husband. Ostrik.
- But I don't wanna get married yet.
- First the betrothal...
- will take place. On your birthday.
- But that is tomorrow!
So what? I've prepared everything.
It will be your great day.
- Have I ever seen Ostrik?
- Of course, my dear.
On the day we signed
the wedding agreement.
- When was that? - You were two years old.
Ostrik was four then.
He stuck his tongue out at you,
and you hit him with a silver spoon.
- Hasn't he got a bump on his head?
- Not any more. Now come with me...
I'm giving Ostrik the young bay
as a wedding gift. And also...
- this falcon. - Is this the one which
saved King Mathew? - No.
That one wears a golden crest.
Once I saw him by the Rocks.
- I've offered my castle on the Danube
for him. - Is he worth so much?
- For me he is. He is indeed the king
of all falcons. The pigeon! - My lord.
- Feed him! - No. I can't do that.
Do you want to offend me?
- But your old falconer...
- You remember Vagan? - Of course I do.
I liked him.
He told me falcons get a pigeon
only after hunting.
You're right.
We shouldn't spoil him.
- And where has Vagan gone?
- I don't know. He left. Was proud.
Once I insulted him... I'm sorry I did.
But lver will replace him.
He's already trained this falcon.
Leave your presents
by the servants in the yard.
Our gracious Lady Formina
thanks you from her heart.
They won't let us in,
we have brought no presents.
Grandpa... Come on.
You wanna get into the castle?
Fine, come along.
- Why are you sitting here?
- Getting warm in the sun, you idiot.
- Get lost or they'll put you next to me.
- What have you done?
I broke a jug, that's all.
To the stocks for a jug?
Who ordered that?
- What do you think? Our lord of the castle.
- This Balador is really...
What did I tell you?
It is His Highness Lord Balador.
We have to go to the main courtyard.
His lorship won't come here.
- We want to congratulate the young lady...
- On behalf of the guild...
The presents are being listed by the clerk.
Over there.
Nobody can go any further.
We are expecting noble guests.
- You're Metod from the pastures,
aren't you? - And you're...
- Iver. The second coachman.
- Not any more.
- Now I'm Lord Balador's falconer.
- A falconer? You?
- What do you want here?
- We've come with a request to Lord Balador.
- This is my grandson, Thomas.
- Maybe I could arrange something...
- But he stays here. Come with me.
- Don't you dare move an inch.
According to the law, the convict
will get twenty strokes.
This is the ruling of the judge!
Executioner, do your business!
Bite him!
- What's up? What's going on here?
- Something is biting me!
Cane him! What's the matter with you?
Are you having a fit, man?
- Something's biting me!
- Run!
- Stop it! What do think you're doing?
- Catch him!
You idiot!
Guards! Catch him!
Well done.
Come on, Sis.
I've got something for you.
From Stephen and me for your birthday.
May it bring happiness into your marriage
as it has to mine.
- You want some? - You bet!
When the bell up there
rings this leg is yours.
- And when will it ring?
- It hasn't rung for years. Has no clapper.
He won't get away with that.
I'm here.
Rogues have all the luck.
- Here you are. - Thanks.
Make way for the cortege
of His Highness Count Donat!
Smile!
- What a dashing young man.
- By far and wide the best suitor.
- How handsome he is.
- I'd like one just like him.
- A fine bridegroom for Formina.
- Do you know her? Formina?
Of course I do.
I bring the mud to the castle.
This? For Formina?
And what does she do with it?
My brother takes care of the kennel.
And this is Perun.
- The best of Balador's dogs. - Quiet, Perun!
- Search him! Quickly!
Move!
Nothing else?
You want to rob this poor soul?
What if he's bringing a message from Vagan?
He is spreading rumours
- I stole his falcon.
- You can't compare with him!
You drove him away,
you good-for-nothing! Swindler!
You see? He's Vagan's spy!
Careful with me, old man.
Allow us to offer a few birthday
presents to the future bride.
And now our son wants personally give
this diadem to his fiancé
which she will soon wear
on her wedding veil.
Go on.
Thank you.
Looks good...
A little heavy.
I meant Ostrik.
On acount of my dear daughter
I thank you for the beautiful gifts.
And now, friends, to the table!
It is a healing mud. It takes away fever,
protects against the plague
and refreshes one's mind.
I know a fine lord who sips it like soup.
To clean his bowels...
- But Lord Balador heats it up and sits
in it up to his neck for hours.
- And Formina, too?
- No. She is as sound as a bell.
To us! We've been good fathers,
we'll also be good fathers-in-law.
To the bottom!
Hey, that's enough!
- You've promised we'll dance.
- I nearly forgot. Music!
Go and ask Formina to dance.
Everyone is waiting...
- But I... - It is your duty.
He's coming.
May I have the pleasure...
I'm not the best dancer but...
- duty is duty!
- Duty? I thought you came voluntarily.
- Yes, of course, but you haven't
finished eating... - Oh, no.
I'm not going to eat any more.
Would you believe
I once hit you with such a spoon?
Well, would you excuse me...
Have you seen that?
You were great.
- What happened?
- She is beautiful. - And?
- She wanted to hit me with a spoon.
- It's a pity she didn't.
I would burn my hands...
- What is your business here?
- I am here to dance with Formina.
You'll have to wait a long time.
I must wait until the gentry depart.
- I can see why. The stuff stinks.
- It has to stink in order to heal!
My mud...
What are you up to?
- What do you want here?
- You're Formina?
I've come to congratulate you.
It's my birthday today as well!
- You're not lying? - I swear it!
Do something!
So let's dance together.
Music!
Take my hand!
The mud heals...
Shall we jump like frogs?
That's enough!
- Who are you? - Thomas.
- You're forgetting something.
- Thomas, my lord,
the son of your herdsman
who was killed by the wolves.
We came here with a plea
for a piece of field... my lord.
- But you've spoilt my daughter's celebration
and for that... - No!
I wanted to dance and he fulfilled
my wish! And you said this would be...
- my great day! - I did say that.
But this is not what I meant.
Let the fortune decide.
A rose, a nice piece of land is yours.
An empty hand, you will get caned.
Now make your choice.
Rogues have all the luck!
The clerk will arrange it for you.
Now off, I don't wanna see your face
any more! Music!
- My friends... - Bravo!
- Eat, drink and be merry!
- Would you dance with me, my lady?
- With pleasure.
Grandpa?
Thomas. What are you wearing?
We got a piece of land from lord Balador.
- I've earned it by dancing with Formina!
- What?
It must have been a bewitched day.
You fly high... but it was me
who danced with Formina!
There he is! Get him!
- I can see him! - Halt!
- Leave him alone! - Let Perun off!
No!
Perun, get him!
Come on!
Be a good boy, Perun.
Perun, catch him!
Can't you hear, get him!
What has he done with the dog?
You little brat! You'll be sorry for that.
- Enough! Take him away.
- Quiet, come on...
What's wrong with him?
We were training Perun to track
and we ran into this boy
who danced with Lady Formina.
He did that, it's his work.
Such a dog is useless.
- Kill him. - No!
- Give him to me. - Take the carcass away.
As for this Thomas, now I'm gonna make him dance!
Where have you been wandering?
Grandpa, does it hurt when you get caned?
It does.
I still have one...
And how many strokes would one get
if he'd done any harm to Perun?
Not a stroke.
Balador would roast him alive.
- Calm down, little one. - Hold it.
Take care of Agatha.
Come on.
Just one more thing. Come on.
We've come for your grandson.
- Thomas didn't steal the clothes.
- What clothes?
He bewitched his lordship's Perun.
- He's not in there. - Search the whole place!
Wait here.
Well, what do you say?
Have you ever seen a prettier girl?
You're right. Me neither.
So let's go.
What are you doing here?
You've come to rob nests, huh?
- I don't steal! - Has perhaps Lord Balador
given you his best stud?
- Out with the truth.
- I turned his Perun into a harmless puppy.
He's sent the constables after me.
And so I took off on his bay.
You've heard that, Tatar?
He turned Perun into a puppy,
stole the bay and
the constables are after him.
We've caught a famous bandit!
We'll take his skin off
and send it to Balador. He will pay us well.
- Welcome to the Rocks. I'm Vagan.
- Balador's head falconer.
Used to be. Someone slandered me
that I am no longer able
- to train a falcon. - I know all about you.
- Who told you?
The birds.
Let's go.
Get down. We're home.
We'd better hide him. Go on in.
What's up? Leave me alone!
That hurts! Let me go!
Zubor! Leave him, he's our guest.
I found him begging by the castle.
Someone had cut out his tongue,
- afraid he might talk... - Lunch is ready!
Vince!
Long time no see, huh?! Come on in!
- Iver would've hunted me down
like an animal. - You cook for Vagan?
I've been promoted.
At the castle I took out the rubbish.
Here you go.
- Leave it. It's for Frankie.
- Who's Frankie? - You'll see.
- The constables! They've found me.
- And me, too!