Hi, what's for lunch?
Is this everything you have for us?
I may ask what's for lunch, no?
Yes. But may we ask you
how about your grades?
Oh, grades...
It may turn out that you won't be
getting lunch, you know?
History... Mmm
Czech... You don't speak Czech?
Well...
Uuuugh...
Chemistry! Also nice.
So, Mum...
But I have an Excellent
in Math!
Give him some soup.
He doesn't deserve more!
Come here, Hujer!
You'll have to explain this -
Here, on Monday:
checked in at 6:00 and then
checked out at 6:02
and again in 6:03
What does it mean? That you wander
at the gate in and out?
I read the daily press.
I admire it. But we go to work
right on the first attempt! Take it...
Mr. Supervisor!
The sausages are on the table.
Thank you, Suzy, thank you.
Don't mention it.
So, the new building will be up to here?
A great deal of change is waiting for us.
They say we won't recognize
it when we see it.
No fear, George, you'll grasp it.
Oh yeah, no fear. They are building something decent, aren't they?
I was talking about that schooling.
Not to be afraid about it.
We are not afraid of it, no.
A lot of people are interested -
here - Hloušek, Krabatý...
Hloušek, Krabatý!
What is it?
Come here.
Moment
Even Famfula.
Famfula!
Come here!
Tell the comrade deputy Director
what you've decided about schooling.
Well, yeah, I would go for it.
It's not about Famfula
Although we are glad that you
want to take that
welding course.
It's more about your high school, George
About mine?
Yes. In order to be a supervisor
in the new factory, you know.
Wait, I was thinking the young would take over.
You wouldn't send us, the old people
with the bad knees
to school?
Look here. Given the automatic production
everything will change.
So, for example, here
Here an automatic transporter
will lead to the new building
There will be an enormous KL-2
And above everything,
There will be a glass observation tower.
It will be so beautiful!
Later, in the office, I will
show you the plans, you know.
And in that observation desk
a supervisor will sit
with a high school diploma.
He will possess a ruler...
a logarithmic one, of course.
And he will be automatically
above all...
...even salary wise.
Well, I think it's not so desperate at all.
What would you say to that, George?
Well, as I have told you before
let anybody sit in that square tower, but
you won't get me in that school.
Hujer is raising a hand.
If you'd allow, comrade deputy Director,
in the case that I would
graduate that high school,
may I, as a quality control inspector, rely
and I am not pushing myself into
comrade Kroupa's place,
could I hope for a glassed space?
Naturally.
It depends how comrade Kroupa will decide.
Oh, excellent!
And because comrade Kroupa
already has decided,
we could disband all this and everybody
could mind his own business.
Neruda.
That one.
In the cage with a lion spirit.
So, what kind of a problem is this?
To learn a pair of verses?
I did know it by heart,
but it fell out.
Fell out!
I went to school 30 years ago
and nothing has fallen out.
I remember some of the poems even today.
For example:
„The mother has died
and they burried her.“
See? And wake me up in midnight
„She left orphans behind...
Well, OK.
Now may I go swimming?
„They came every morning
and looked for their mother“
But you think about love notes
and not about school.
„And the mother felt sorry for the poor children...“
Ha-ha.  It's still there!
Somebody is ringing!
„...and her soul returned.“
Good evening!
Hi!
What has happened?
We would like to discuss with you
that issue,
that, well...
Enter, please. Enter.
That way, come on.
Now, George, we have contemplated
a long time about it.
We won't force you into anything.
I wouldn't even advice you to try me.
But try to imagine it. When Hujer
graduates from that school
and you won't, it would be a disaster,
because he will fight for the supervisor job.
And you saw him how
crazy about it he was.
And I would have to, only because of Hujer,
at this age, learn formulas and write homeworks?
Mr. Kroupa, that you won't manage it?
Just don't say that.
Look, the people at the workshop love you.
You are strict.
You won't turn a blind eye to anyone.
You are also competent and just.
When I just imagine Hujer...
It's true, George, you won't do this to us.
Daddy, don't hesitate. You have good memory.
„The orphans behind her..“
You remember it more than 30 years.
Come on, go swimming!
You, advisor... as if I needed your advice.
The „best“ in class.
You see it George,
he's all after you.
OK, wait a sec.
Wait.
May I?
Look at this.
Even if you cut me in such tiny noodles
you won't get me into any school!
We welcome the students
of the Technical High School
We welcome you and
wish you a lot of success in school.
Here you have the school program.
We welcome you and
wish you a lot of success.
Here you have the school program.
We welcome you and lots of success.
We welcome you and wish you
a lot of success.
Here you have.. Hi, Dad! Here
you have the school program.
Your clasroom is up and right
If you can't find it - it's the same as mine.
Is it free here?
Yes
Kroupa is an ox.
Šlajs!
Tuček!
I won't ever get rid of him!
Sorry, we have been sitting
together since 1st grade and he's keeping
that place on the first desk for me.
Hi!
Hi! Man, where did you get this?
And where have you lost this?
You know, my wife.
Here, in the school rules it is written
that the student should go to school
properly kept.
Does it mean that we have to
shave every day?
Good evening.
Evening!
Sit down.
Thank you.
Whose is this, please?
I took the liberty, for the occasion
from my little garden... some plums,
if you don't find it insulting...
Well, really, from you,
maybe we can taste them in class,
everyone together.
No, no, please!
They are only for you!
OK, thank you.
My name is Čeněk Janda.
I am your class teacher.
This is good!
Pardon?
Nothing, we are just glad.
Yes. I will teach you mathematics and...
Dear students of the evening technical school!
Excuse me.
Allow me to.. [distortion]
This equipment has some years behind it.
Comrade Director wanted to say, basically,
that he welcomes you, that
we have actually talked about it
at the council
that having to go to work every day
and from work to school,
this isn't really a joke.
But we, on our side
will do anything for you to succeed.
I will teach you mathematics and
descriptive geometry.
And now, I would gladly
get to know you.
Březina?
You work as a..?
Locksmith.
Thank you.
Dudek.
Accountant.
Gregorová.
Turner.
Fulinová.
Toolmaker.
Yes. Thank you.
Aluminum?
Is Aluminum present?
Aluminum moved to Humpolec.
OK. We'll put that down.
Hujer?
Here.
Viktor.
Quality Control
for the moment.
Ah, we talked.
Kroupa?
Supervisor.
I am here conditionally -
Pardon?
That I am here conditionaly,
it's decided this way.
If I have any difficulties
with the learning
I quit on the spot.
Yes?
You are entitled to it.
Mužik?
Rakouna!
Supervisor.
Thanks.
Pavlíček?
Kroupa jr. is an ox.
Planning.
Thank you.
Plha?
Warehouseman.
Roubiček.
I have a question.
Here...
in the school handbook
it's written that
„Always, the student must
go to school
properly kept.“
Does it mean that
we have to shave every day?
Don't disturb.
But, no!
When I shave daily, I bleed.
So, you don't have to take thesе
rules litelally.
It's about small children.
But children don't shave.
It's true.
But they have to be washed
and combed and such...
Roubiček.
And I have another question.
Here, in article 8, it says -
„The parents are being informed of
the student's grades
at regular meetings.“
Yes, it's also about kids.
Well, it's because my parents
live in Kojčice.
This is far away, near Pelhřimov,
and my parents are old, and...
But..
...it's a lot of travelling...
...as I said, Mr. Plha,
Don't torture your head with this,
it concerns little children.
Roubiček.
That's why,
because I don't know otherwise.
The train is not for free, also.
Please, sit down at last.
But no, don't you understand?
I don't know about you, but
these 70 korunas for my parents, to travel...
Roubiček
Supervisor.
Supervisor at the mill.
Thank you.
Šlajs?
Clerk.
Thank you.
Tuček.
Well?
And you work like a...?
Like a horse, Mr. Teacher.
Is the place free?
Certainly.
What's up George?
What?
What what?
Come on, tell me!
What should I tell you?
What about school?
How is it going?
School?
Haven't you seen a school yet?
This is it..
It is interesting, they have all those things -
desks, a blackboard, a sponge.
And there are some models, that you can see
the structure of animals, stones...
What do you want to know more? What?
You know what I want to know, don't you?
I know.
Here, I would go there,
But I am there on a condition.
We clearly agreed on it -
And poor you,
poor you!
If it doesn't click.
Poor you!
Sit down, students!
Mareček, please hand me the pen.
I am Tuček, Mr. Professor.
Yes.
Aluminum is still absent.
Aluminum moved to Humpolec.
It does not concern me
where he is.
Let him work it out with your class teacher.
I am marking him „absent“.
Thank you, Mareček.
I am professor Hrbolek.
I will teach you Czech.
And, if anybody is interested,
I can teach you private lessons in Latin.
And if somebody finds it difficult
to keep up with me in the Czech language course,
I offer private tuition as well.
Well, is anybody
interested?
I am retired, I have plenty of time.
Well, I am just substituting for
a colleague - Ptáček.
I have a question -
May I put Latin to use in my field?
And in what field do you plan to
dedicate yourself, student?
I keep the warehouse
in the screw mill.
Even a warehouse keeper could read
the original texts of Vergil.
So, I write you down.
But,
What is your name?
Plha.
I have not yet decided, for sure...
You will come
every Wednesday at 14:00, Mlha.
And now, we'll write a
little evaluative dictation.
So, prepare sheets of paper,
prepare your penholders, pens,
ink pots.
And we'll start dictating.
„Fierce jackals howled grimly at the white moon“
Look here, only one mistake!
I thought that word „howled“ somehow
was connected to „owls“.
„Fierce jackals owled grimly“
Otherwise, as you see
without a single little mistake.
It could have been an Excellent.
Only this tiny mistake,
as you can see.
Only this tiny mistake.
On the other hand, Hujer,
what is this blob, at your age?
This is a shame!
For a little reality check,
I'll tell you something.
What do you think did I get on the
evaluative dictation?
Good?
Very good?
Not even close.
I am familiar with it.
May I reveal?
A total failure.
That's it, sirs.
These were some crooked words,
weren't they?
Please.
An ordinary dictation from my
mother tongue - Czech and
flunked.
You see that I have come a long way
that I have patience,
but if it goes on the same way
we'll have a serious conversation.
Tell me
what are the disadvantages of the
steam engine?
A disadvantage of the steam engine is its
great weight.
We'll say „mass“.
Its great weight..mass, and
low efficiency.
How low is this efficiency?
Look, I don't like this,
I'll answer or I'll tell that
I don't know.
Don't be silent like a
ghost.
What is your name?
Ghost.
With such a name, you have
some right, but
please, learn it.
between 5%  and 10 %.
Let's summarize -
The historical significance of
the steam engine.
Svátek.
The... the steam engine
was invented in the 18th century...
Yes, please.
The steam engine
invented in the 18th century
Continue.
Šlajs is raising a hand, please.
Please,
he's ashamed to tell you.
Can you disclose
what is so delicate about
the steam engine?
He's ashamed to say that
he must walk.
Walk?
And where?
Nowhere. Just walking.
Svátek is accustomed to walking
while thinking.
If he doesn't walk he
won't be able to think.
Look, Tuček.
I already know about
your bright ideas.
But he can do it, please.
I work in sales
and when I dictate letters
I must walk.
OK, then. Get out on the aisle
and walk, if it would help you.
The steam engine
was invented in the 18th century
and was developed fundamentally
in the 19th century.
That is why
we call the 19th century
„The steam century“
Jarda!
The phone is ringing.
Thanks!
Hello, here is the gate.
Here is the rail station.
Gate,
The monkey house has arrived.
Is it that thing behind you?
Has it arrived already?
Yeah. You have it on the third track.
How wide is it?
How... how wide is it, they ask?
About... 3 meters (10 ft.)
Most important, I don't want it
to stink here for too long.
Everybody, come and see!
It has been delivered!
It will be warm inside.
It has a lot of control units.
What is this?
This is the cockpit of the supervisor
and an executive armchair.
Hujer, the forwarders are waiting for
the stacks!
I am on my way already!
Running!
You must also have a look
they have installed an armchair.
Hujer, today you also
wandered about the gate!
I know, I know, but
the paper!
Stop, Franta! Stop!
Famfula!
How does it run?
It runs wonderfully, but
it doesn't sow.
It's quite a substantial problem
for a drill, no?
Did you look under?
No
You had to bend a little, eh?
There is stuck paint under.
Mareček, hand me the pen.
I am Tuček, Mr. Professor.
Yes. Yes.
And as I see it, Aluminum is still absent.
Aluminum moved to Humpolec.
Yes. Yes,
but he is absent.
Thank you, Mareček.
So what did we
study
last time?
Mlha?
Last time we studied
one of the great poets
of „the steam century“
Jan Neruda.
The steam century?
Yes
19th century is called
„The steam century“.
We studied it in physics.
Well, all right.
All right.
But don't say it in my classes.
We shall keep to the standard name -
The 19th century.
And what did we have for homework, eh?
So?
That I didn't give you any homework?!
No, Mr. Professor,
you said that, above all, we had to
get a good rest.
It doesn't sound like me.
Please.
We had to learn a poem by heart.
„Like lions beating against bars“
Yes.
Thank you that you reminded me.
Kroupa.
Come on, Kroupa.
Come here.
You had problems with the
dictation
You may compensate with
reciting.
And no mumbling,
let those verses flow.
Jan Neruda,
from Cosmic Songs.
„ Like lions beating against bars,
like lions, captured in a cage,
we yarn to fly up to the heavens,
yet we are...“
„earthbound“
„We seem to hear a voice from stars:“,
please!
„We seem to hear a voice from stars:“
“Come, you men, closer,
Just a bit closer..“
„a bit closer“, eer
„Just a bit closer, you hubristic beings,“
please
„Whose feet are stone-bound!”
„We come!“
„Forgive us, dear Mother.“
„The Earth is too confined for us.“
„Shine - “
„we'll add it to the thought“
„and our legs“
„will march, steam powered“
The steam century!
I said it...
Don't disturb!
We'll come!
We
shall come.
We hear, we hear you coming,
but what next?
I don't know it after that.
What would I do with you, boy?
You didn't make me happy and
I won't make you happy too.
Sit down.
For the next time, you'll have to make
an analysis of this poem.
And now, a prosaic work of
Neruda.
Please.
What do you want?
Please, Mr. Professor,
let's sing.
Let's sing!
Please!
What!?
We don't have a music class
and in other classes,
like chemistry
It does not fit in.
But we'll be delayed too much.
I wanted to...
I wanted to bridge the gaps!
It is raining!
What?
Let's sing „It is Raining“!
All right, but quickly, please.
It is raining, let it pour.
Where shall we go, dear horses?
We shall ride to the meadows,
until the cockoo starts to sing.
This would be quite enough.
We shall ride to the meadows,
until the cockoo starts to sing.
So, the prosaic Neruda
Then the cuckoo started singing,
and my girl started crying.
Please, cuckoo, don't you sing,
and my darling, don't you cry.
Don't you smoke?
Ugh, no.
I am a non-smoker.
This is good.
Do you know what I said to myself
when you recited?
What?
No, really.
You have the feeling.
There is so much feeling
in the first verses.
No, really.
You have a good presentation,
but you need someone to
study together.
Mrs. Týfová!
You know what?
Let's try it together.
Yes?
Let's stay a bit more
after school
and I guarantee you that tomorrow
you will know it excellently.
You are very kind,
But I cannot today,
it's a mad house around me,
dinner, wife.
Icecream!
With nuts!
Acid!
Sulfuric!
Caustics!
Boron!
Buy yourself!
Think about it.
It's on sale.
And then, on page 46
solve example 7a,
b, c,
and on page 32,
examples
d, e,
f
This is your homework
for the next time.
You may go.
Kroupa will stay a second.
Listen, Kroupa,
math is giving your dad
a hard time.
Do you learn with him together?
No.
Isn't it possible?
To lend a hand about it?
Well...
It's hard.
At least the equations,
he would need some
explanation.
He doesn't know basic things -
removing brackets, fractions and etc.
Yes, but he won't allow me to explain
anything.
It's hard.
Please, Mommy!
Oh-ho, tomato sauce.
Are you home?
How is school?
Normal. And you?
Did you get any grades?
No. And you?
What about me?
None of your business.
What about me.
It's about you.
I go to this school, and
I am immersed in the problematics
Damn!
So I can examine you a bit.
Did you learn equations?
Yeah, we did.
Great, excellent,
I would give you
immediately
such an example
2a-(3b-5a)=a+b
Dad, you must first remove
the brackets
and then you will
I know what I will do.
But I am interested
if you can do it too, well?
I would, at first, remove the brackets.
Right.
And how?
You will..
I mean
I will do it in this way
I will imagine minus one before the brackets
and I will multiply all the numbers in the
brackets with it.
Wait, wait, don't brag so much about it
How did you do it?
Multiplying?
If I wouldn't get it with that -1
Then I will remember
that when there is a minus
before the brackets,
then all the signs in the brackets
will change into their opposites.
Oh! But, look
before 3b there is no sign
If there isn't one, then it's a +
Ahaa!
And, in this case 2a - 3b
and so on
and later?
and then you will move a+b
from the right to the left side.
And, how do you move from one
side to the other?
Do you examine me,
or I examine you?
You examine me.
that's why
See,
you are quite good with it.
But, don't  rest on your laurels.
to be... why am I so stupid?
to be
yes
„We jump against the bars“
„you and us we'll smash them“
„Against the bars we jump as lions“
„and we will smash them definitely“
„Against the bars we jump..“
Daddy, leave that alone!
It's 1:45 a.m.
Outratová!
A short meeting of the studying commitee
in the afternoon.
Yes.
Špaňha!
A short meeting of the studying commitee
in the afternoon.
Yeah!
What's wrong with you?
With me? Everything!
I can't get sleep at nights.
You look all green to me.
Karel.
A short meeting of the studying commitee
in the afternoon.
What's on the program, George?
Grades.
Is it that transport?
Rousek!
A short meeting of the studying commitee
in the afternoon.
Comrade Kroupa!
Come and see!
Look at it!
In order that the supervisor
should not get down for
every sheet of paper.
They put it here for him.
It goes up.
He signs it.
And then it goes down.
It's an internal telescopical transporter
of the factory mail!
At first - information about
my success  in school.
At the dictation
„Fierce jackals howled grimly“
we were the worst.
I compensated with reciting and Failed
the poem - „As lions jump against the bars“
Another failure.
And then it follows
briefly:
Equations with one unknown.
Failed.
Discontinuous functions. Failed.
Physics
Levers in balance. Satisfactory.
See!
Leave it alone.
What are the reasons for the crash...
Wait, George.
You cannot speak so definitively
about a crash.
You have just begun.
Obviously.
What are the reasons of the crash
of the New York Stock Exchange.
Failed.
Presence of nitrogen in nature.
Satisfactory.
So
and now tell me
what do you plan
to do with it.
Look, George.
Aren't you a bit passive in this school?
My boy, for example
is not an Einstein at all
but he is first to collect
recyclables.
And the teachers look at him
differently.
It's possible that those wastes
would have their role,
but it's not important!
My grades are important!
Well,
I think that
we must accept
that those grades are not
the ones that we promised,
but I would not perceive it
so dark.
The general view of the situation
as you sketched it
is not rosy at all.
Although
and we must not overlook it
and I would not agree with you
there are some positive sprouts,
I mean that nice „Satisfactory“
from nitrogen
and those levers in balance, no?
These are the first birds of spring.
You let those birds fly at
your executive meetings.
Here we must recognize
that I go under!
And I ask you
Isn't it the right moment that
I, on my own,
voluntarily and honourably
quit school?
Out of question.
Bullshit, no way.
As you wish.
I warned you.
So, we'll push this cart further.
Mr. Kroupa,
I brought you the literary analysis,
but there are things, that me and
my husband could not apprehend.
The first line is all clear.
The poet compares man to
a lion in a cage.
„we yarn to fly up to the heavens“
This means, as my husband says,
that man would gladly fly to the stars,
but he is prevented from it
being earthbound.
Naturally, the Earth's gravity.
And here you can talk about
people already flying to the stars.
Well!
This is a bright idea!
You'll hit it right at the heart,
connecting it to present day.
And then, there are these
hubristics,
and we couldn't grasp it.
„Just a bit closer, you hubristic beings“
Does somebody know what are hubristics?
A hubristic?
A hubristic is a beetle.
A beetle?
A beetle.
It's a bug, that it
rolls this in front of it,
a tiny ball
of that -
of droppings.
You mean a pooper?
Yes, a pooper, but
but in biology they call it „hubristic“.
Five, failed.
How many dumplings do you want?
Five.
Five?
What?
Dumplings? Six.
Five, failed.
Five or six, at last?
Six dumplings.
My father has a five. Flunked.
Nonsense,
you know that Father eats at the factory.
Wait.
This is his paper, I found it at school.
This is horrible.
Look, here.
How's that possible that he
cannot calculate?
If he would allow me to explain, but no.
Have a look!
the one he examined me with
and how does he transfer it?
-X, wow
He is a bonehead.
It's too much for him.
I am afraid that he will go crazy.
In nighttime he beats his head
against the wardrobe.
He shouts in sleep „We come! We come!“
He shouldn't have gone to this school
It's not for him.
Come on, if some Hujer can do it.
Is this from you, Hujer?
No
I know nothing about it.
I brought it.
It's recyclables.
What is it?
Old paper,
about 15 kg (33 lbs.)
See, we did not count on it, that
you would also join,
why not.
If you are into it then
but in this case it would
be necessary
to elect a team leader
for recyclables.
Please, I would get involved.
I would dedicate
a separate notebook to it.
See?
Dad won't raise a hand and won't raise a hand.
Hey, he already did raise it.
He talks a lot.
Hey, hey, do you see it?
And he's stuck.
See how he scratches his nose?
He does this when he's lost.
The poet wants to express
that man is still small
and compares him to hubristics.
This is an unusual word, isn't it?
So, what is it?
A hubristic is a
beetle,
dung roller,
who rolls its small ball
between earth lumps.
First, we don't say „a hubristic“
but a „hubristic being“
and then
your explanation of the word is
rather extravagant.
Is there someone that thinks
the same way?
Except Maleček and Hustoles.
See, Hustoles, we can't believe it.
Well, is someone on the same opinion?
Yes. Great.
Though, it's not quite right.
Does somebody know the true meaning
of „hubristic being“?
Plha
is raising a hand.
Well?
Mlha?
Please, I have a question.
Please I,
in this poem stumbled
upon a word that I don't understand.
Which word?
The word
„a hubristic“.
I have never heard it.
But we are talking
more than 15 min.
about it, Mlha.
They have it entertaining there.
Come.
We must go home.
Hey, Hrbola takes out his notebook.
Oh, yeah.
I hear him already
„What should I do with you, boy?“
„You did not make me happy
and I won't make you happy also.“
What should I do with you, boy?
You did not make me happy
and I won't make you happy also.
Satisfactory.
Good night, Kroupa!
Good night
Mr. Kroupa.
Yes, please.
They gave us a hard time.
My God,
such a warm evening.
It's quite wonderful for a walk.
Yeah.
Go for it.
I'll go home
and open a window and a beer.
Good night.
George!
What is it?
I
have to admit something to you.
What?
I knew that „hubristic“
was not a poop beetle.
I said it
because I felt sorry for you.
You were facing it so lonely.
Whom?
That beetle of yours.
But this is not my beetle.
Hora, that fool, gave me this advice.
Nobody stood up for you.
There was nobody
that you could rely upon, and
I rushed to help you.
Look, Mrs Týfová, you are a
very sympathetic
lady and I feel flattered
by your interest in me, but
don't you feel
that we are not 20 anymore?
You think that we are so old?
Certainly not. But with distant
birthdays. Good night.
The pooper beetle!
Stop! You!
You!
Thank you frankly for the help.
You cannot possibly imagine my success.
With your knowledge.
But I did think that it was a beetle, yes.
And if you have another brilliant idea, share it.
I will brag about it at school.
We collected this from all around the offices.
There is about 40 kg (18 lbs.)
This is great!
Great help!
The recyclables team leader with the highest quantity
will be rewarded.
Last time we
detected metal elements
in solutions.
Please, pay attention.
So,
And now we'll test
if there is sodium inside.
Attention,
We'll meet at the cemetery.
G.K.
The liquid is being coloured.
Calm.
Don't disturb.
And we'll prepare another solution.
So,
and, hm
carefully,
carefully, in this manner
Silence. Don't disturb.
What's your name?
Matula
What dou you carry?
I don't know.
And now we'll detect
the presence of potassium.
Knock. Knock.
Silence.
Don't disturb.
Take!
It is dissolving.
What's with you today?
Please, comrade Professor,
there is a student from another class.
What?
Are you here a long time?
Aha.
What are you saying?
Are you here a long time?
Yes, please.
Let me see what you've got.
Who sent you with this?
The comrade Director.
And you have to give it to me?
You have to write it on the blackboard.
Write down:
Thanks, bye.
Bye.
A meeting with parents and friends
of the School, 20th 19:00 The Headmaster
This should not be valid vor us, this
Why not? Just write it down.
Everybody, write it down.
Kroupa, they must be out of their mind!
My parents are in Kojčice, this is
far away, at Pelhřimov.
Such a distance, and now
travelling is not for free, too.
But it's totally logical.
Our families must be informed
of our progress in school.
Sit down.
Plha is raising a hand.
PLease, I have a question.
This message on the board,
about the parents' meeting,
is it valid for us?
The orders of the headmaster
are always valid.
But no,
this is too much...
Don't forget that at 50, one learns with
an effort.
It doesn't get so easy in the head.
I wouldn't criticize him for his difficulties.
You have troubles on your mind, don't you?
Something else is bothering me.
I promise myself, that if I am to have kids,
If we are going to have kids.
then I won't be ashamed to ask
Do you want twins?
Wait.
Shortly, if we were to have kids
I won't ever be ashamed to ask
Hey, Pete...
No, not Pete!
OK, then, hey Theophilus,
I can't solve equations with two unknowns,
please explain.
And,
and he will explain.
If this Theophilus is after me,
then he won't be able to.
Two circles in a plain may have
two intersection points
one intersection point
or none at all.
In the first case,
the sum of the radiuses is smaller
than the distance between centres.
and the difference between radiuses
is smaller than the distance between centres.
In the second case,
the distance between the centres is
equal to the sum of the radiuses.
In the third case...
Listen to him.
If for A, for A
if the sum of the radiuses
is smaller than the distance between the centres
And the difference of the radiuses is greater or equal to the
distance between the centres of the circles.
In this case, one of the circles is situated
inside the other.
Basically it was right, except for a small inaccuracy.
Come and draw it, so we can see it graphically.
Please.
What happened, who went out?
Týfová was not feeling well.
Please, go and have a look.
I am going.
What happened to you?
Who sent you this?
Kroupa.
What a cynic.
Asshole.
Kroupa, lend me the drafting compass.
I need it.
Come on, draw with a coin.
Don't you have your own?
Why don't you buy one?
I welcome you.
I welcome you, comrades.
Welcome
Welcome.
You must have come to see
our factory?
Please, tell me
what would be your interest in us.
So,
I am in charge here
in general
respectively
quite soon.
My name is Hujer,
Hujer
Well, so
Here, behind me, you see
this is the old workshop
and there
we are building a new one
entirely automatic
and it will be, will be
the beating heart of our plant.
You have ecountered our
machines in the fields
and you didn't expect
that bolt by bolt,
the Holy Truth,
was born here.
And there, it is the sprout
of the new one.
He was asking about you
What do you do, what obligations
How was his name, again?
Týfa, engineer Týfa.
I don't know Týfa.
I go with Týfová to school.
So dear friends, I welcome you
to our factory. [translation in
Romanian]
This is our deputy Director Kalivoda.
My name is Kroupa
and I am the supervisor.
Hujer, mind your job!
Hi, Daddy.
Hi.
What's up?
Did you do something to Mum?
Me? No. Why?
She behaves strangely.
Doesn't speak, just walks around
shines the mirrors and
disappears again.
Maybe she wants them clean.
Come on, they are shiny like a...
Didn't she say something before?
Nothing interesting. Although,
Somebody, engineer Týfa called
and when she put down the phone,
she looked haunted.
Man, this doesn't
look good.
It doesn't come
by itself.
Did you ask her?
I asked, but
she would say the same -
nothing!
Mommy,
why do you shine those mirrors
all the time?
In order to see by yourself what
a prick you are.
Oh, well,
must we deal with such problems
even among grown ups.
If I am concerned, Mr. Director
I would throw it in the bin, but
the husband of Mrs. Týfová insists
that we elaborate on this and
for Kroupa to apologize.
Hi, Kroupa.
Did they call you too?
No, where?
I am going to Latin.
Where did they call you?
To the Director.
What do they want?
About those poor grades in math
they will suggest that I leave school.
And I'll say to Hrbolek
that Latin is not for me.
„laudo, laudare“
What to do with this
at the drill mill.
I cannot imagine at all
how should we discuss it with him
Enter!
Good afternoon
I am Kroupa
They told me that I come here.
Sit down, comrade Kroupa.
Thank you.
Listen, I don't know
if you are aware of the reason
why you have been invited
Well,
I can guess.
So, it would be easier to talk about it.
I certainly don't think that you have planned it
I did not plan anything, I was
I was persuaded to do it.
Who persuaded you?
Hora,
Outratová, Rousek
Write down those names!
You cannot possibly know them, they are from the factory
and I would appreciate if they don't get trouble from this.
They had good intentions.
I also think that it was rather a
misunderstanding, than
Well,
I told them immediately,
that it doesn't make sense.
And I am ready to drop it immediately.
We consider it obvious,
that you won't repeat it ever.
And it would be necessary
for you to apologize.
It's enough that I go away, what
apology do you need?
If I have insulted you personally,
because I've been here, please
accept my deepest apologies.
Wait, comrade Kroupa.
We don't understand each other.
Nobody wants from you to quit school.
But the lady comrade was clear about it.
It's only about dealing with
the note to Mrs. Týfová
with some tact.
Yes. Exactly.
We are maybe the same age
aren't we?
Isn't it a bit boyish at our age.
This comrade husband, this Tyfa,
he rightfully considers it an insult.
First, you tell her in the eye that she's old,
and later write to her
„We'll meet at the cemetery.“
It is cynical.
Look,
the International Day of Women is approaching.
You gave her a nice gift.
This piece of paper
I see for the first time in my life.
You cannot talk?
You must write letters to each other?
„At the cemetery“!
Such,
such shame!
And I have to run around and explain!
As if I don't have worries of my own.
Please, don't shout.
Good afternoon.
Hi.
They called me to the Headmaster's office
investigating
as if I were some kind of a rascal.
Wait, it's here somewhere.
Hey, 84
Ring.
Emil!
The bell!
Open!
What is it, darling?
Don't you see that I am in the sauna?
I am studying!
Eh, do you see?
„A happy home“
And you nearly destroyed it.
Oh, my God!
He's naked!
Poor Mrs. Týfová.
Are you looking for someone?
I am Kroupa.
Aha.
A fellow student of your wife.
And this is my son
who came here to explain something.
Aha.
Please. Obviously. I'll open the door.
Come inside.
It's not necessary. We'll do it quickly.
It would be more appropriate,
if I understand it well,
if it's about that
apology,
that my wife would be
present too.
It's not an apology, but an explanation.
What is your name?
George Kroupa.
Pay attention, please, that he has
the same initials as me:
G.K.
Whom did you write that note to?
A girl from our class.
What is her name?
Eva Tůmová.
Take into account, please -
„Eva. T.“
What did you write in that note?
We'll meet at the cemetery.
Did you intend to suggest that she is old,
about to die?
No.
What did you think about?
Well, that,
to come to the cemetery.
We usually meet there.
Pay attention, please, that my
son is dating a girl schoolmate
at the cemetery, among the graves.
So, if I understand it well,
Yes, you understand it quite well -
I did not write that note at all and it
was not addressed to your wife,
whom I greet from my heart.
It was a pleasure.
I was honoured. Come.
Týfa took it with dignity,
as Cicero,
nearly naked.
George explained everything.
and now everything is in
ultimate order.
Wait, now I see
you have a girlfriend!
Yes, I have.
And how old are you?
You, boy!
When I was as old as you are...
But, Daddy.
I did not finish. What?
When I was old as you are now,
I also did have, naturally, a girlfriend.
I have to go.
It's high time.
Mom, is this brown sweater OK?
Yes.
So, you also are going out?
We go to parents meeting.
It's enough that I'll be there, no?
We are going to ask about you, Daddy.
I spoke to Mrs. Tuček and to Mrs. Šlajs.
Everybody is coming.
Please, this is
completely unnecessary,
I tell everything at home.
Come on, we'll do it gladly.
We don't need the school to tell us
that we are not interested in you.
What are you saying?
They won't let you in, look,
Here
„A parents and friends of the school meeting“
Are you some parent?
I am a friend of the school.
He'll solve the example, but
often will make a simple mistake from haste.
His grades are quite decent:
arithmetic: Excellent, Excellent-
and Satisfactory, just as I said
And George Kroupa,
if you'll be kind,
Mr. Professor.
Sorry, it closed.
Kroupa knows math, it's in order.
Here he is.
Although,
lately, I haven't noticed,
Test Failed, again Failed, orally Satisfactory
These are maybe my grades, Mr. Professor.
Ha-ha. Yes
Wrong page.
This is about another student
from another class.
He's good, as I say. Very good, Excellent, Excellent
You can be satisfied.
I know. With the son.
Please, colleague,
for a moment.
Excuse me.
Did you call them?
Who?
The family members.
These here?
No, those old ladies, children, brothers-in-law
of the students from the evening school
I know nothing.
Didn't you notice the crowd in the corridors?
I sent them to the drawing room.
Now, they are sitting and waiting.
Please, comrades,
he did not call them,
what shall we do?
I think that Janda as a class teacher
should take care of it.
But I am not ready here.
It doesn't matter, please finish it quickly
Yes.
and I will calm them down.
And you in your classes, also give it some speed
and come quickly there.
and give info on grades, and etc.
But I don't understand...
Speed it up, speed it up!
Please, please.
Yes.
Dear friends,
I, as a headmaster,
would like to express my satisfaction,
that you have come here,
in such great numbers.
Believe,
we did not expect it.
Although we suspected it,
when we prepared for it,
that it won't pass unnoticed.
You know,
the cooperation of school and family
is very imortant.
It is not only about
basic behaviour,
formation of the individual,
but also for some known issues
not very noticeable, but
important details,
Look,
They would often go dirty to school.
I have instructed
the comrade janitor
that the most notorious slatterns,
excuse my language,
he would pull for the ears
and take back home.
Obviously, it concerns
younger students, especially.
And, here,
this was my introduction.
And here we have the class teacher
and he will deal with it
by himself
and will be more precise.
Please.
What class are you looking for?
Good evening.
I received a letter from my nephew
that there was a meeting
What's his name?
Hujer.
He attends the evening school.
Here, behind the corner, in the drawing room.
Thank you. You are very kind.
Please. Please, sir.
Where is Hujer's class?
Stairs up and right. It's the drawing room.
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
We come for uncle Hujer.
We want to ask...
Next floor, drawing room.
Excuse me...
Hujer.  Next floor, drawing room.
I cannot make any compromise
At this school the technical subjects are the most important.
And you?
Hujer, Robert.
The older brother of Viktor Hujer.
Hujer, he is
a very dedicated student, but
his ability of independent thinking is weaker
but his diligence, untamed,
he will get the grades, don't worry.
What did he say?
That he'll graduate.
You?
I am Zelenková, Hujer's sister.
Well, you've heard it.
You?
I am Hujerová.
Wife?
No, I am the wife.
I am his sister-in-law.
You?
I am his cousin.
And you?
Hujerová, wife.
But the wife is...
I am from the first marriage.
OK, then
So, that everyone can hear me.
What is the Hujers' range?
Hujer? Does he study here?
Hey, Máňa! From Čáslav!
Silence, please!
Sit.
You are?
From Kojčice,
near Pelhřimov.
And who are you interested in?
Our son.
Plha,
Mr. Teacher.
He is „Very good“.
Very good.
Let's go.
God bless you.
Hello.
What's for dinner.
Come.
I asked about you.
You are OK with math
and then you have a Good in history.
You'll have to fix it.
So what?
Will there be a soup?
Wait, father.
We asked about you.
And we won't eat because of it?
Aren't you interested how it went?
Of course.
Turnout was abundant, yes?
14 people came for Hujer.
Wait, seriously,
it's tragic for you in math
I know, this is no big news,
You could ask me and not go to school.
I don't want to keep you accountable for it, but
It's the last thing that would happen
that you keep me accountable, what?
Let George speak, please.
As if somebody is stopping him.
Please talk, so that your mother won't go crazy.
Come, we'll learn together.
Every evening, two hours
or three, well?
It's only about mathematics.
Father,
think about it
the boy means only well.
Well,
You are very kind, sonny
but with this
I must deal alone,
you know that we would fight
and that I would be nervous.
And then you have your own issues.
Get better with history.
It's also important
because, if someone doesn't know history,
it's worse than not knowing
biology.
You are so stubborn!
I shouln't give you any soup.
As you wish!
I can go to a restaurant.
I still have enough for a soup!
Hujer,
One minute before break's end
you must tell Janda to come to class
Maybe his watch is broken.
Me?
Why me exactly?
He said that you are the most trustworthy
True.
But, I'll have to...
Oh, yes.
Not to make a mistake.
You know what to do.
2 min. 30 sec.!
Better go.
Enter.
Comrade Professor,
there is a minute to class.
And what?
The class will start.
Yes.
It's time, we must go.
Listen, Hujer,
I can't say you lack diligence,
but at the moment it is almost
insolence.
Is it fast?
I set them this morning
to the radio.
He's coming!
Hujer, how come that your things are not ready?
I had to remind you, and had no time.
Please, excuse me, I otherwise always...
Next time, take care of yourself.
I will take care of my duties.
Everybody sit.
Thanks, I have my own.
Kroupa to the blackboard, please!
You have an angle Beta...
No, I don't have.
You have an angle Beta, and sides A and B
Draw a triangle.
Side A
And now
we draw
side
side B.
Side B.
How do you know that
side B goes this way?
I don't see the angle.
Plha is raising a hand.
I have a question.
How could he know that
side B will go this way?
Please, sit.
Comrade Kroupa, these are basic things.
You must know this unconditionally.
By the way, not to forget
Yesterday at the council we agreed
that those students, who feel
that they won't make it through school
I don't mean directly you,
Have the possibility to
leave school on their own desire.
in order to avoid
the unpleasant fact of dropping out.
What are you doing?
Feeding them.
Don't you want something for them?
No.
Yeah, I wanted to...
Listen,
let's not speak generally about
two hours of learning together
it has to make sense
I was thinking
what would you say about
between 8 and 10 in the evenings?
Is it OK with you? Is it?
If not, then tell me.
Don't you smoke?
No.
When I smoke, I throw up
You, Hujer.
Šlajs knows about a locomotive.
Come on!
Don't you say anything about a locomotive.
This is again some kind of a
joke.
No, Really, Šlajs found it.
An old one.
And if we take it for the recyclables,
I know your ideas.
You are...
like little kids
Don't be an asshole, this is 20 t. of iron.
Immediately, it's first place in the republic in recyclables.
Really.
Bring it.
I'll weight it
and write it down.
You don't want it? OK
You could have won a bycicle.
A bycicle!
Stand up, Kroupa!
Sit down!
Stand up!
Yes, please?
No, nothing.
Sorry.
What is it?
You had a crazy night, didn't you?
I study at night with my son
and then get up at 5.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Please.
Hujer Fruits and Vegetables
I took
Silence. Don't disturb!
I took the liberty
if you won't feel insulted
Thank you, Hujer.
Thank you.
And now, we'll detect
the presence of aluminium.
Aluminum moved to Humpolec.
What is a logarithm of  a product?
Logarithm of a product is equal to
the sum of the
logarithm of the [yawning]
But, dad.
Factors!
It's a multiplication!
I did say „factors“. I said it like
a bit differnet
I am learning this words, well?
Don't cheat!
On the writing test you'll be on your own.
I am not cheating.
So, listen.
What did I say?
factor or term?
Term.
Now you see.
You suspect me wrongly
and I actually said
"Chinese"
So, how did you do that test?
Well,
I solved everything.
George said that I did well.
If there wasn't some trap, then
it would be fine.
Let's hope.
It was a hard test. A hard one!
I had a lot of work with it.
The test did not turn out the best.
A lot of good students disappointed me.
Svátek. Good.
Tuček, Šlajs. Satisfactory.
Same mistakes, same grades.
On the other hand, some poor students,
Kroupa,
Take your logarithmical tables and come here.
What is the result of logarithm
Please, if Plha may hand me the glasses.
of  3457 x 40876 / 7222
Please, lend me those tables.
You give the pen, I give the tables.
It's correct.
You really know it.
Do you know your result from the test?
I don't dare guessing.
Excellent.
We study
together with my son.
Great. Greet him from me.
Thank you.
Look,
I'll tell you
this is quite good.
It's not bad.
Though, a Good in history? It's a shame.
Look my grade in history!
But you don't have it at all, Dad.
No? It's a pity.
I would shine then, little one.
The burning of Jan Hus -
My God, your behaviour is Excellent.
I thought it was Very good.
You aslo have it Excellent.
Yes, it's all right.
Well, Dad,
there is this Satisfactory in math, but we'll fix it.
It's not bad at all.
And you also go to work,
you deserve a praise.
Mom, did you hear that?
Pour the soup.
I think that we fully deserve it.
I said „fully“, Mommy.
Full.
What's up, George?
Got comfortable already?
I would rather not get too comfortable here.
Let's see the final tests.
It would be fine.
The beginning is the most difficult.
AC to 004
Alleviate 5
Two buns and a milk.
Two buns and a milk, Suzy.
What kind? Full-fat?
Normal.
OK.
Hey, the executive coucil.
Weld!
We are welding!
Up!
What is this?
I took the liberty,
some plums from my little garden,
if you won't feel insulted,
Mr. Boss.
Translated by Konstantin Pavlov,
komitata@gmail.com
With my greatest thanks to
the magnificent Czech culture.
The translation and timestamps were made
for 5 days
from the original audio track.
December, 2011,
Sofia, Bulgaria.
I love feedback.
Merry Christmas!