Come on, you need your vitamins!
- A titchy Trabant overtook us.
- Did I shut the sitting-room window?
- Old cow can't keep to the sidewalk...!
- I shut it, Mom!
- Good girl, and the kitchen?
- That too.
- Good.
- Does a worm have a head?
- A worm?
Not a head, but a front and back.
Presents
We're not taking them a present.
- Never mind.
- How d'you know which is the front?
- Of what?
- The worm.
- According to the way it's crawling.
- What if it's reversing?
- Worms don't reverse.
A black car wouldn't be pretty.
- In summer...
- A Trabant overtaking!
- It would be hot...
...in a black car.
- Is a worm a snake?
- No, it's a worm.
- Another Trabant overtaking, Dad!
- Snakes are larger!
In the film
What if it's a big worm?
- It's still a worm.
- Clean up, Susie, you're all sticky!
- What if it's this big?
- It's still a worm.
- And this big?
- A worm!
Idiot!
- Who, Dad?
- That Fiat could have passed.
A COTTAGE BY THE WOOD
Hm. Now you remember...!
Story and Screenplay by
You said no Trabant
would ever overtake you, Dad!
- Wait till we're out of town...!
- I didn't take the thermos.
- He's crying, Mummy!
- What's the matter?
- I don't understand.
- What?
- You said a snake was bigger
than a worm.
- It is.
- A worm this big must be a snake!
- All right, so it's a snake,
and stop bothering me!
Visitors, Radim!
A double nil!
Who?
- The Lavickas.
Where's the stork you told us about?
- Here, children.
Storks build nests near ponds.
- Welcome!
- Excuse the dust.
A mill's a mill...
Well, kids?
- Good morning, Mr. Zvon!
- Here I'm called The Miller!
I had that wheel made.
But it looks antique, what?
- Children, the wheel is imitation.
- But the balustrade is original.
- Really, Radim...
- We try to keep up the traditions.
So this is a mill.
This is where they ground the flour.
The grain was poured in there.
- You see, children,
the grain went in there,
was ground here.
- Mind your heads!
- That's the groats mill,
the plain flour mill,
the peeling mill.
- So, children!
The groats mill, the plain flour mill,
the wheeling mill.
- Peeling!
- Peeling.
- Groats were used to feed pigs with.
- Groats were fed to piggies.
- Here the flour sacks were stacked.
- All this is flour?
- I put in sawdust,
but the sacks are original.
I'll show you something, children!
When the water-level gets high,
we'll ask the Miller
to set the wheel in motion.
- And I'll tell you an interesting story
about the local water-sprite
and how he helped the Miller
fight the local squire.
Whenever I tell that story people say:
,, You must tell us again!".
The groats went in here, the flour here,
and here the semolina.
- Attention, children!
This was for groats,
this for flour, this for semolina,
and this for double zero flour I guess?
- No, that's the toilet.
But I refuse to keep animals.
We had a dog...
...that kept barking.
- What kind of dog?
- Harry.
I got rid of him.
A cottage is difficult to find nowadays.
Easier said than done!
Maybe Kos would know of one.
How's life?
- Good morning!
- Ah, the Miller!
What an honour!
- Getting on with it, I see!
- We never stop.
- You're building it yourselves?
- No.
We've got a bricklayer.
He charges ten crowns an hour.
A good one, and cheap!
- Ten crowns?!
- A rarity nowadays!
- What was this originally?
- A barn.
I left only the foundations!
- You sure remodelled it!
- Comes more expensive this way,
but you have what you want.
Where you want it.
Whether it's a doorway, stairs, bedroom,
kitchen, bathroom, yes,
living room, garage,
toilet, pantry,
cellar, hall, bath!
- Yes, it's true!
Quite a villa!
- The amount of building material
this eats up, though!
- The sand, lime, cement...
- Look, Radim!
...Bricks, shaped ones...
- Nice!
...lintel, trusses,
I don't have them here yet,
nails, screws, wiring...
drains, tiles...
pipes, binding!
You've got your twin leads,
triple leads, guttering, sheeting...
- Problems...!
...an electricity meter,
a lighting conductor,
switch and wiring boxes...
- You understand all these things?
- We've got this bricklayer.
The cheapest man around.
Asks only 10 Crowns an hour!
Including transport and food!
- Where's the mortar?!
- Coming right up!
Here it comes, Mr. Lawrence!
Kids...!
Enough sand in it?
- Too thin!
- And now?
- O.K.
- He can't hold a brick,
but he's a real expert!
- He's an expert!
He's built three big houses here
this way!
- Listen, Robert.
The Lavickas are looking for a cottage.
Would you know of anything?
- A cottage?
- These kids of ours...
- Fresh air for them...
- But something habitable,
no remodelling job.
Because von Olda is...
- Can I manage these?
...not the type for building work!
- No.
- It needn't be big.
Just - away from it all.
- And now?
- Yes.
- Some place good for the children.
- Yeah, a cottage.
What about that one over there?
It should be up for grabs by the autumn.
Old Ma Jerabkova's sinking fast,
it should be free by Christmas.
- Breathe deeply, Susie,
so your chest expands!
- So you could have that
when she goes.
But it's probably damp.
Maybe that one would be better,
with the red roof.
- Which one?
- There, the red roof
with the white gable.
- Do you know which one?
The one with the wooden barn.
- The Cervenkas live there,
a motorbike ran over him last year.
And he's in pretty bad shape,
won't be here long either.
She's going blind,
will be going to a Home for the Aged.
But that's right in the village. You
probably wouldn't like it there either.
Hey! Did you ask Komarek?
- Over by the wood?
- Yes, that's it.
Go and ask him!
He wants to move to Slovakia,
to join his son.
It's all getting too much for him,
the milking, the feeding,
the cleaning, the chopping,
the cooking,
the loading, unloading,
the ploughing, the sowing...
- What a lovely place!
- God help ye!
- Thank ye kindly!
- God bless you!
- Hello!
- Good afternoon!
- Mowing, are you?
- Mowing, that's right.
- Coming along all right?
- Yeah, it is.
- Nice place.
- That it is.
- How old are you, friend?
- Seventy.
- Wow, that's something!
- Nice, isn't it?
- I say!
- You don't look your age!
- You live alone, Mr. Komarek?
- Yes, yes.
- His hearing's bad, you must shout
at him.
Do you live alone?
- I do.
- We hear you have a son in Slovakia!
- In Presov.
- Don't you miss them?
- If you miss them?
- They're asking if you miss them?
- I hear you, but I don't know!
- But this is a lovely spot.
- Ask him straight out
if he'd consider moving to Slovakia,
and letting them have the cottage.
- You want the cottage?
- We would consider it,
we like it here, what?
- We haven't seen it inside yet!
- Come and look, then!
A lovely spot!
- A fairy-tale cottage.
- We'll be quite envious, won't we,
Radim?
- Peter, don't cut yourself!
- What's your dog's name?
- Isha.
- May I stroke him?
- He's never hurt a soul.
- Isha!
- Kids!
- The quiet...
- Don't step in that, Peter.
- Like a picture!
- So romantic!
- Come along in.
- An old Czech idyll!
- I have some stuff in here!
But I'd clear it out,
restuff the straw mattresses and...
...you'd have a nice room
for your vacations!
- It's very damp, Olda!
- It's not that bad.
Just needs more airing
to make a pretty room.
- See, damp and rotten!
- Well, a couple of planks need
replacing.
- A very nice place you have.
- Cozy, what?
- How does it flush?
- Just leave it!
- Beneath the rustic beams
of yeasteryear...
- That's right.
- Are there mice?
- Why would there be mice?
- It really breathes rustic poetry...
- It's mildew I smell.
- Why would there be mildew?
- Come here!
- At least 100 years old, this.
- Older, chum.
- What a pretty wardrobe!
- Let's buy it.
- Yes.
Heavens, Mr. Komarek, when did you
last wash your dishes?
- When I run out of pots,
I do it in one go.
- Let's get it done, Vera!
Mr. Komarek,
what about...
- Get out, beast!
I'll tie her up.
- Mr. Komarek, what would you say to
letting the room to the Lavickas,
for weekends and vacations?
What do you say?
- O.K.
A musician from Prague used to spend
his time here.
And he loved it here!
That viola is his.
I keep waiting for him to fetch it,
I've waited and waited.
But he'll be coming.
- When did he leave it here?
- Wait, when...?
During the first... World War.
Beams, planks,
tiles...
Damn!
Look, they would be here with you,
and when you decide to sell out,
you'd make them the first offer.
- What would the monthly rent be,
now?
- How much would you care to pay?
- What about a hundred?
- O.K.
To cover the insurance and things.
- And a bottle or so, what?
- And when would you think of selling?
- Well...
- Mr. Lavicka is asking...
- I heard!
- When do you think?
- I'd bring in the harvest,
sell the cow in winter
and do no more sowing in spring.
Say 'please'!
Where's your cap?
- Forgot it.
Go!
- He forgot his cap!
You're sitting on it!
He's got it, Dad!
Well, here we are.
Good morning!
- Good morning!
Heavens, what a lot of stuff!
- Here's something for you,
Mr. Komarek.
- But there was...
- Hello!
There was no need...!
- We've arrived, Isha!
- Good morning!
- Welcome!
- May we auntie Isha, Grandad?
- No!
- Susie, don't be cheeky,
Mr. Komarek isn't our Grandad.
- Just let them be!
I'm a Grandad anyway, so what...
But leave the dog on the chain!
He'd get used to running about
and would't want to go back
to his kennel.
- I hope he hasn't got fleas.
- He'll have a flea or two.
But they're dog fleas,
they leave people alone!
Good morning!
- Good morning!
- This is Tony.
He catches snakes.
- There are snakes here?
- I should say!
- I summer, mostly.
Vipers, too.
- Do they nest here?
- Not here!
In the wood, or on the paths.
- You're preparing the floor?
How kind of you!
- Tony's a handy chap.
He'll show you how he catches them.
- How do you do it?
- Tell them how you do it!
- There's nothing to it!
- Say how you catch them!
- In my hand!
- Aren't you afraid they'll bite you?
- They won't bite me.
- I guess you wear gloves.
- No, I catch them with my bare hands.
- A viper?
- Yeah.
- Don't try telling me you take
a poisonous viper in your bare hand!
- He does.
I've seen him.
Look!
When I see a viper...
- Just wait a moment!
Children, come here!
This gentleman catches poisonous vipers
with his bare hands!
Listen to how he does it!
- But there's nothing to it.
- Do tell them!
- I'd rather show you.
I want to start lunch.
I need my pots and pans.
- Not just now, Vera!
In summer I sweat,
and my jacket...
- Smells of the sweat.
- Smells.
The viper gets a shock.
- Gets a shock!
- Doesn't know what's happening.
I reach in for it
and my hand smells the same.
- And that's what scares the viper most.
And that's what scares the viper.
That's Tony!
- See? It doesn't bite.
- Unbelievable.
- So, Olda...
Excuse me, I have to do my cooking!
Where did you put the baking-pan?
- Unbelievable!
Do you know why a cow's useful?
- It eats flies.
- It gives us milk.
- I thought we buy milk.
- What's the cow's name?
- Cow.
- Can we call her Jitka?
- Yes, she won't care.
- Jitka!
- Cow!
Is that any use?
- Hey, the water's coming here down
the slope.
The wall can't breathe.
I'll lead the water off
and the damp must disappear.
Next time we come,
the wall will be dry.
You gave me a fright!
- Here!
Mr. Komarek!
What about felling down this plum-tree?
It's old, and it won't let the sun in.
- The plumes are always full of maggots.
- Goat! Goatee! Come here!
- I'd have guessed that.
- But when you put them in a barrel
the plums and maggots ferment...
and ah - the Slivovitz!
Wait, when it's ours!
The floor's repaired.
You can dance on it now.
- Wait, Mr. Hruska!
How much do we owe you?
- Oh, don't mention it.
- Don't give him anything.
He drinks up all he gots.
- Indeed, yes!
The work, the new planks...
Come on now... all right...
- Well, if you insist...
- Be seeing you!
- Why on earth did you give him
that money?
- For repairing the floor...
- Is it our floor?
- No, but it will be!
- That isn't sure yet.
And we pay our rent,
so it's his duty to mend the floor.
Olda! You mustn't be such a softie!
People see it straight away
and take advantage of it.
I know you're in love with the place,
but do think twice!
100 Crowns a month for such...
...a damp hole!
- Firstly
it's no damp hole,
secondly I'm getting the damp out
and thirdly...
- Good afternoon!
...I'm investing in my own property.
Good afternoon!
- Good afternoon!
- I'm Ferry Kokes.
Would you lend me your spare tyre?
For an hour, to get to town with?
- Yes, of course.
Can't even shake hands,
look at the sight I am.
Seven holes!
Hopeless trying to mend them!
Did she leave an egg?
- Not an egg.
- Pity.
We're practically neighbours.
- Really?
- Yes, really!
I've got a cottage here two years now.
I was mad about it,
so I bought it old man and woman
included.
They wanted to end their days here.
Now I've got strangers in the house
and I can't get rid of them.
Come and see us some time,
and thanks a lot!
Thank you!
- Not at all.
- Thank you.
I'll bring it back tonight!
- There's no hurry!
- Seven holes.
And that was a second time!
Thank you.
I enjoyed that.
- Coffee's ready too.
- What's the time?
- It's past six.
- Oh, I'll have to be going!
I'll take the coffee with me.
Where's he going?
- I don't know.
Good evening.
Once upon a time
there was a Kingdom
which was neither large nor small.
All its inhabitants were happy people.
- I haven't heard this one before!
Go on, I'm listening!
- The ruler of this Kingdom was
a very old King.
- I bet he has three sons.
- This King had three sons.
- Didn't I say so?
- One day he asked them
to find a really wise man.
The youngest son set out at once.
He went around the kingdom
from town to town
looking for a wise man.
But in that Kingdom people were
neither stupid nor clever,
neither ever nor good,
neither cowardly nor brave,
neither ugly nor beautiful.
Children!
Come here!
Listen!
Do you hear?
- Something tinkling.
- Do you know what that is?
- No.
- The angelus, or evening bell.
In the country they always ring a bell
at this time of evening.
- It's coming nearer, Dad!
- No, that's just the wind!
The bell is fixed up
in a bell tower
and the bell-ringer stands below
and pulls that bell.
- The bell-ringer's coming up, Dad!
- No, children, this is Mr. Lawrence.
But it really did sound
like the angelus.
Good evening.
- Good evening!
- Finished for the day?
- I put him to bed early,
so he's up bright and early.
And what about you?
How are you doing?
- We're not here long yet...
- Quite a job, if you ask me.
The first thing you'll need are
some decent tools.
A good hammer...
- Don't rock me!
...and pliers...
...a pipe cutter, a shovel...
- Stop rocking me!
...a spade, a pick-axe...
...a trowel, a water-level...
a wheel-barrow!
A screen...
- Stop rocking me!
...a gimlet, a chisel, a plane,
a vice, a file, a rasp...
- Supper!
- Excuse us, Mr. Kos,
...sandpaper, a big rake...
- we have to go - my wife...
- Come along!
...A small rake...
Well, be seeing you. Goodbye.
And a frame saw!
Here I am!
- Come on!
- I'm not too late?
- No!
What's the time?
- A quarter to ten.
- Come and look, then!
You wouldn't believe me.
It's nearly ten
and they're still asleep.
Sometimes till twelve!
- How can they?
- The just do.
Well, slept your fill?
- If you went to bed
when the chickens do...
- Can I bring in the eggs, Grandad?
- Yes, go and see if they've laid any.
- A bright boy!
- That he is.
Good morning!
- Good morning!
- I bet you do the old man's
shopping too?
- Well, of course...
- Don't over do the good relations bit!
- Good morning!
- Better to keep your distance.
Let him be!
- Is he the owner?
- The former owner!
With water there he's more scare still.
- But surely, I'd like to...
- Just leave them alone.
I dug the hole because of them!
They could have gone to a Home. -
A lovely chateau it is!
But they refuse to budge.
Say they have it in writing.
So I sweeten it...
- Riffraff!
...up for them.
Thanks.
Thanks!
I'm repairing the chimney,
nobody can stop me doing that.
I'll make life such hell for them...
- The pancakes are getting cold!
And you stand here gabbing...!
- My wife!
- Good morning!
Goodbye!
- I'll smoke them out.
Drop in some time.
Look, Grandad sowing.
- That's a farmer, Susie.
- But Grandad sows too.
Right!
- He sowed.
He's giving it up.
He'll sell the cow and won't sow again.
It's pissing and pissing.
Mum! It's pissing and pissing.
- What are you saying?
- Grandad said it.
- So take a look!
Mr. Komarek can speak as he likes.
But no dirty words from you!
See, children?
These were lamps used in the past.
- In antiquity?
- What do you mean by antiquity?
Your grandfather still did his homework
in such a light.
- I would, too!
- You'd spoil your eyes!
- Did Grandfather spoil his eyes?
- Grandfather had a different problem.
- I hope we can put in electricity!
- But why?
It wouldn't be the thing in this
sort of cottage.
We'll furnish it in period style
and all our friends will envy us.
- For not having electricity...
Funny...
What was that?
- A hunt.
- I think somebody's arrived.
- Who'd be arriving...
- I don't know.
Chase those chickens out
and please go and look!
What are you doing?
- Trying to cut some firewood,
But the thing...
...keeps choking...
Can't get it to run.
- Did this ever run?
- It'll run again!
Hruska said the magneto is weak.
Try turning the handle for me.
- Where? Here?
- Right.
- The cooler's cracked.
- We'll keep it filled.
Come on, now!
Keep turning!
Wait! We must heat the plug.
Now wait!
What on earth are you doing?
Keep turning!
Glory be!
- Bring some water, quick!
It's boiling!
More gas!
More! More gas!
When I'm cutting, you must turn it up!
Again!
Keep turning!
Water!
- Where's Daddy?
- Maybe he's branding a cow.
- Branding?
- Hurry!
- We're off to look for mushrooms.
Coming?
We're off to look for mushrooms.
What?
...coming mushroom-hunting?
- I'll catch you up.
Here, children! Quickly!
The ants built all this,
pine needle by pine needle,
with its ant highways...
See? Here's one now...
Iook.
- This ant's carrying rice!
- That's an egg, you silly.
- Egg?
Good day to you!
- Hello!
We're looking for mushrooms,
but they don't seem to be growing.
- Hello!
You have to get up earlier!
- We enjoy our sleep.
- I know, I saw you.
- Saw us?
- I just had a peep.
Komarek insisted.
There was a mayor
who slept that long,
but he had the sleeping-sickness!
- Who said...?
- The postman.
But you wouldn't know him.
He comes round at eight.
- Then we don't know him.
- This is awful!
He shows us off like a circus act.
- But the weather's on our side!
- The weather report said rain.
That's the last straw.
- But not us, hey Marta?
We like it here even when it rains.
Then the water wheel works,
and I'll tell you the story
about the water-sprite.
- This really is a lovely place.
- Do you know what we love best?
- The early mornings.
- Yes.
And the evenings.
We lie and listen
to the frogs tooting.
Such an unpleasant sound elsewhere.
Here they just do:
- Higher, dear!
What do you do about mice?
Great, what?
- Are they for supper?
- Yes. Don't touch!
Ask your Dad to bring some water in!
This oven bakes like a dream!
- I never tried baking.
Hasn't been used since the wife died.
She baked a good cake too.
- I'm leaving them to cool,
then I'll ask you to taste them.
Does the water flow or...
- Quite, children!
Yes, that's them!
Take the pail back, I want to talk
to Mr. Lawrence.
Water!
- Water!
- Aren't you good.
- Mummy, look, the goat!
- Look how hungry she was.
- God, my cakes!
- Let go!
You beast!
Greedy thing!
Greedy! Goat!
Mr. Komarek, look at this!
Just look at this!
- What is it?
- Why don't you keep her tied up?
Ate six, bit into two.
- Damned glutton!
She's greedy, the devil!
- Our supper gone.
- Don't worry about me,
I'll finish those she started.
- Hardly enough for the children.
- Father gets a tin again.
Get out, you!
Impossible,
life with the hen-coop and goat.
- Don't be cross. Taste this!
- No thanks.
- Come on!
Real cream, what?
Goat cream!
It's you, Mr. Komarek?
I didn't recognize you.
- You're a peach, Mr. Komarek!
- Well, a funeral, you know...
- Who died?
- Old Petrina.
He was ill for a long time.
Well, that's life.
Come and watch,
it'll be a grand funeral.
The priest is coming from Brod.
- We're not dressed for it.
- Mum! We want to see the funeral!
- We want to see a funeral!
- The children should see a funeral.
- Just watch!
You needn't join the procession!
We sing this at school.
Is it a funeral song?
- No, probably the deceased's favourite.
- Who is Mr. Deceased,
the one with the trumpet?
- No, no!
The one with the trumpet's a musician.
The 'deceased' is the one who died.
When somebody dies,
he's called the deceased.
- But why if that's not his name?
- He is deceased,
but his name is Petrina.
Mummy, he's crying.
- Don't cry, love!
He was old and ill,
and glad to die, see?
- But I don't understand.
- What?
- Who died, Mr. Petrina or Mr. Deceased?
- I'll explain later.
It's a bit overgrown!
There's never time...
- Your wife died young.
- Not a single grey hair on her head!
A weak chest she had.
I had,, When I Put the Horse out
to Pasture" played for her.
It was her song.
I'll be going to the pub.
Well, goodbye!
- Goodbye!
Are they going to cry at the pub?
- No.
They buried him, played for him,
they can do no more for him,
that's life, now they can go
and enjoy themselves.
Don't keep pinching bilberries,
so your mother sees
how rich the forests are.
- A mushroom!
- Typical!
Mum! Mum!
- Mum!
Look how rich the forests are!
- You picked them all by yourself?
- Well, no...
Look at the garden Mummy made!
All by yourself?
- But the fence is your job!
You picked them by yourself, Peter?
Twice.
- How's that?
- I spilled them.
This'll be the scene
when we're all alone here.
- Will we do nothing but eat?
We'll eat and sunbathe,
and go swimming,
and paint the house...
- And fool around!
- That too.
It's ideal for the children.
I always won every fight, Tony.
- Not any more you don't.
- I always beat you!
- You wouldn't beat me today.
- You?
Every time!
- Not any more.
- Yes I would.
Come with us, forester.
- Where?
- Outside!
- Right.
- Let's go.
- Now you'll see something!
There's nothing to it!
- You've never tried!
- But I've seen it done.
Children, remember.
First speak to the animal,
so you don't frighten it.
Don't be scared, old girl!
- Her name's Jitka.
- Don't be afraid!
- Your master's forgotten you,
but we'll help you.
Now I can sit,
because she knows about me.
- Jitka!
- Cow!
- No, don't be afraid, children!
She's not rearing...
...just chasing the flies off.
Komarek!
- Come on!
Get in there! Jenik!
- Don't give up!
Go on! Go on! Go on!
Jenik, get in there! Don't give up!
- Jenik, at him!
- At him!
- Jenik! Good, Jenik!
- Mr. Komarek! Mr. Komarek!
- Here I am!
- Kick him!
- Don't be afraid of him, Tony!
- Give it to him!
- At him!
Shouldn't we fetch Mr. Komarek?
- Wait a moment!
This one's empty too.
He milked out two at lunchtime,
now I'll have to walk round
and do the other two.
That's it! That's it! Don't be afraid!
Empty, too.
So the situation has changed, children!
I think the delay turned her milk cheesy
and it stopped up the little holes.
Should have given him a Nelson!
- I did.
- Fancy me not noticing.
- It was that fast!
- Good evening, Mr. Komarek.
You'll have to go home...
- Pity you didn't come sooner!
...your cow...
- Take a seat!
This is my Praguer.
- Hello. Kalous.
- Good evening. Lavicka.
- You two've met.
- Ah, Mr. Hruska.
- I beat him again!
This is Fiala.
- Lavicka.
I would not advise that.
Everybody with re...
...haired person
- Re... red...
- has ter...
...terribly.
- Terribly... bitter meat.
- Yes.
- Your tongue would...
...sting.
- Enough.
We sent the right messenger...!
Come, children!
Hold the light for me.
Daddy said...
- Daddy's done his milking, Susie.
Now I'll try!
Good night!
- You beat me, Johnny!
- Good night!
Good night, Tony! Good night!
- He beat him!
- Good night!
I slayed him!
- I wonder how you'd have got home,
had I not come to fetch you.
- What is it?
- A hole!
- There's another over there!
I made a mincemeat of Hruska.
Where are you?
- Here.
Have any matches, Mr. Komarek?
- Yes.
- Milk!
Have a taste!
- Can't...
- Haven't had a drink yet!
- I have.
- You have?
- Yes.
- Don't wake the children!
- Who did the milking?
- We did.
The children shone for me.
- The children shone!
You in there, Mr. Komarek!
You here, Olda!
- They held the lamp!
They held the lamp.
What now?
- That's music.
He sure can play.
- Couldn't he wait till morning?
- I'll ask.
What do I ask?
- If he could wait till morning.
- Alright.
He can't.
- This is and awful holiday!
In the morning that old motor-saw,
at night he plays the violin.
- That's a viola.
He just says he'll sell the cow
and won't sow again next spring.
- It's impregnated,
but the damp could spoil it.
- But he's not doing anything.
- He's a slow country type, Vera!
It takes him a while to get into action.
- We made a basic mistake!
- What are you looking for, Radim?
- We wine and dine him,
do his errands by car,
we're company for him
and we pay rent;
he'd be crazy to move!
- Why not be friendly?
- We're overdoing it!
Look at Kokes...
- I'm not sure...!
Expect me to dig a hole
in front of his door too?!
- No! But we're practicing
the other extreme!
- It just needs more patience.
- And don't give him a break!
Keep asking him!
Has he written his son,
has he found a buyer for the cow!
And start wading through the red tape...
- Mr. Miller, you promised to show us
the mill wheel
when there's enough water, and tell
that water-sprite story.
- Yes, the story.
Today's the day, then.
Now I'll tell you the story
of the water-sprite
who helped the miller.
- Remember we have children here!
- I know.
The miller stood here,
he set the thing going,
then he was fetched away...
It's only a legend, of course!
- I'd love to hear that again
when it's quiet some time!
- So they want to hear it again too!
Everybody enjoys it!
Goat! You beast!
Goat! Goatee!
Where are you?
Come here!
Goat! Goatee!
Damned glutton!
Some idiot, Mr. Miller is.
No! Hey! Hey!
What is it?
- A flea!
- Some insect...
- I saw it jump in here.
- A little grass-hopper, maybe!
- Grass-hopper, my foot...!
- I'm itching, Mummy!
- So am I!
- Let me see!
Just look at this!
Look at this!
Your grass-hoppers!
- How could there be fleas?
- From the dog!
I told you it keeps scratching!
- Komarek said dog fleas
don't bother people!
- I don't care
what he says.
We're all bitten
and I refuse to spend my holiday
in a flea-hole!
- Where've you got to, goat?
Goatee!
Do as you like, then!
You still up?
- We've got fleas!
- You have?
Good night!
Mind out, children!
Keep your distance!
- First show him it's you,
so he's not scared!
- It's me, don't be scared!
Come here! Come on!
Come here Isha!
Don't be afraid!
Hold still!
You'll fell better too!
Don't be afraid!
That's it!
- Those are only dog fleas,
people don't catch them!
- Hold still, Isha!
- The kennel too!
- Come here, Isha!
Wait!
- Devil!
- Doggie!
- Show yourself!
- Is Mr. Komarek home?
- He is, come in!
Doesn't your dog have fleas?
- Yes.
But only dog fleas,
people don't catch those.
I've had just about enough.
How can I make any plans?
You'll have to talk to him.
He must tell us will he sell or not!
- He promised to sell the cow
and not sow again in spring.
- Has he written to Slovakia?
He hasn't.
Has he found a buyer for the cow?
Nope.
He's done nothing!
- We should remind him...
- I can just see you...
You must speak forcefully!
Will you sell out? When?
You won't sell out?
Alright, we'll find something else.
Come on!
Good afternoon, Mr. Komarek.
- Good afternoon!
- God bless!
- Have some coffee with us?
- Well, if you insist.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
I might break it!
Here you are.
I'm used to my own mug.
- Right...
Autumn's drawing near...
- Doesn't time fly.
- What are your plans afterwards?
- Afterwards?
Winter'll be coming, the snow...
- What about Slovakia?
- They have hard winters too.
Oh dear!
My son wrote...
- So he's written?
- They have snow-drifts 2 m. High!
- Of course, in Slovakia...
We went to Slovakia and...
- We want to talk about the cottage.
- Yes, you should buy it.
Yes! It's all the same to you.
- Exactly!
That's what we wanted to talk about.
- I'd keep my little room
and the rest'd be yours.
I'd keep an eye on the place for you,
you'd have milk...
- You mean - live on here with us?
- Yes. When I die,
it'll be all yours.
- We'll have to think about that.
We hadn't thought about that.
Don't we get along famously?
But it is great here, what?
- So look, Olda.
I finish here the day our holiday does!
- No rush!
- It's as clear as daylight.
- Everything will turn out alright!
- As clear as day! Nothing will change!
Fleas, chicken droppings!
I'll put a harness on him!
You'll groom him,
we'll be crammed into one damp room -
and the only difference will be that
except that we'd pay 20,000!
We'd be crazy!
Home, children!
- Look here, Vera...
- Make your choice.
Either me or the old man.
Good morning!
- Good morning!
- Hello, what's up?
- The kids are flea-bitten
and Vera's worried,
They were dog-fleas,
is there no danger of rabies?
Sorry to bother you, pal.
- Let me see!
We've never had this here before.
Where did you catch them?
- At the cottage.
- I'll prescribe you some powder.
- Can I scratch?
- Yes.
Listen Olda...
Do mushrooms grow there?
- Tons, pal!
A lovely place.
- I know.
But while Komarek's around
Vera'll never be satisfied!
- He won't sell?
- He wants us to buy it
with him included,
and we'd have to wait till he dies.
How old is he?
- Over seventy.
- What did his father die of?
Heart and lungs are sound,
no vertigo
takes life with humour
digestion excellent!
He'll outlive us yet, chum!
This drives Vera berserk.
We just live with the animals
and can't keep the place clean.
- Wait!
Has he got a visitor?
- No, he talks to the radio.
...I'll fulfil three wishes for you.
- Mind it's not a trap, boy!
He has nobody else to talk to.
We're going for a walk!
- He had three wishes and wasted
two already.
The ants will help him,
he helped them out too.
Good day!
A bastard, that Kokes.
He's stuffed up their chimney.
They'll freeze in winter.
- What have they done to him?
- Nothing. They don't want to die.
Water's the best way.
They jump out
from between your fingers.
This way it's sure.
- Would you care that the place had
no electricity?
- Definitely not.
You've got electricity in Prague.
D'you know what I'd do with that roof?
- Tile it.
- Yes.
With old corrugated tiles.
And I'd let grass grow in the yard.
- Grass, right.
- You'd leave that threshold?
- Yes.
I'd leave those stones.
- Vaclav,
why aren't you my wife?
Coming to Oumerice, boys?
- No. Why?
- Local feast-day there today.
- Good morning.
- Good morning!
High time, too!
They are our guests!
- These are my Praguers!
- Grandad! Look who's come!
Johnny!
Sit down!
Help yourself!
- Thanks. Enough!
Thanks a lot.
Roast duck!
Haven't had that for a long time.
Bon appetit!
- Bon appetit!
Help yourself, Johnny!
- Yes, yes!
- You must starve yourself all year!
- Oh no!
The young lady cooked for me -
Mrs. Lavicka.
They...
- You don't know these gentlemen.
They're from Prague.
Stop it, grandad...!
Just ignore him!
It's sclerosis.
Do help yourselves!
They...
- Come, Grandad, to bed!
You must remind him of somebody.
Take no notice!
You don't know them, Grandad!
- They...
- Guess how old he is.
Ninety-two!
- That's a good age!
- He must take a rest.
- They...
- You don't know them!
- They look a sight!
Who is he?
- The old man?
- My father.
- Your father?
- Yes!
- Your step-father?
- No, my own!
Well, goodbye, Mr. Komarek!
Take care!
Be seeing you!
- Goodbye!
Come here, goat!
Home already?
- Yes, holiday's over.
- Good afternoon!
Good afternoon!
I have another week,
and hope to finish here.
We still have to set in the windows,
finish the chimney...
- Don't rock me!
...finish off the electricity,
build the fireplace,
I want to do the bathroom ceiling,
but I don't have a Rabitz wall.
- What's that?
Wire netting.
You nail that to the ceiling...
First you daub a bit of cement...
Help! Catch me!
Looks like a job for me!
I can't find him!
- Didn't he ride through?
- Must be inside!
- Mr. Lawrence!
He must be inside!
- I'm not working for you again!
It's the end!
- But all that's left now
are the windows
and the chimney!
- I've finished with you.
- Anything wrong?
- The beer's gone.
- You've only got the walls to do,
and the ceilings...
- No, take me home!
- We'll be going.
- Goodbye!
- But... Mr. Lawrence,
I'll never rock you again!
- No! No!
I've finished with you!
You'd cripple a man!
We have a cottage by the wood,
but it's not ours.
Grandfather Komarek lives there.
He's very...
He isn't our grandfather either.
He's very kind, but he's in the way.
- Wait, Susie! How can you write
that he's kind and in the way?
- How do I write it, then?
- Yes.
That he's kind, that's true.
- He is in our way,
that's true too.
- But how can she
put it like that,
he's kind and in the way.
- How do I put it, then?
- That he is kind,
that he means to move away
and then the cottage will be ours.
- Right, that he's kind
because he means to move away.
- No!
He's kind, full stop!
When he moves away,
the cottage will be ours.
Decided to spend the winter in bed?
Where does it hurt?
- Everywhere.
Don't even enjoy my smoke.
We'll have to get you down!
- Down? Where?
- To the car and to hospital.
- Hospital?
I'm not going!
- It's pneumonia, Mr. Komarek.
That's serious.
- I've never been to hospital.
If I'm to die, I'll die at home.
- You won't die,
but you can't lie here!
And you can't lie here ill.
- Don't worry, Mr. Komarek,
you'll be back in a few days.
- Stop fussing...
I'll dose myself with linden tea.
I sweat and I'm well again.
- Look here, Johnny,
they won't bite your head off!
- Yes.
- I'll take care of your place.
...do the feeding...
- Of course.
...and everything.
- Don't you worry!
- I wouldn't beat you today, Tony!
- Hm.
- There'll be pretty nurses there!
- What good's that to me?
To an old man!
Have you arranged things?
- Arranged what?
- The sale,
all that!
- With you staying on here,
we would hardly...
- Who says I'm staying?
What would I do here?
- But we didn't know that.
- Hruska's buying the cow,
I shan't sow again,
I'll die and that's that!
- Don't think of that.
- Yes.
- You must get well now!
Good morning!
Are the Kokess here?
- We're just expecting them.
Good morning!
I'm looking for the Chief!
- Over there!
Good morning!
- I 'phoned, about Komarek's fields.
- You're Komarek's Praguer.
- Yes.
- How's the old man?
- Still in hospital.
- The Co-op's not too keep on
getting those fields up on the slopes,
we'll make them into pastures.
- So you'll confirm the Co-op taking
them over?
- Yes, give it to me!
- When can I fetch it?
- I'll do it on the spot.
Don't like red tape!
Joe, over here!
My regards to the old man!
- Thanks.
Hell, this is the fifth time!
Look at this! Look at this!
Maruna!
How many times have I said
you must sweep the yard properly?
- Go and get stuffed!
- This is the fifth time!
Goodbye!
- Chick-chick-chick!
Goodbye! Goodbye!
A trash-bin with foot pedal.
You don't have that either.
Hello, Mr. Kos!
- Hi there, neighbour!
- Looks like you're all set
except for the letter-box.
- How's life?
- Oh, all those rubber stamps.
I've seen enough of them! You have...
- I know!
...record...
- The land register, geodetics...
- The Co-op.
- National Committee.
- Regional National Committee...
- Agricultural Agency.
And the Notary.
But now things look so bad
with Komarek...
- He's still in hospital,
but he comes of good stock!
- Wait... You don't seem to know!
- Something's happened?
- Very bad!
He was getting no better at hospital.
So the poor old boy asked to spend
his last days at home.
At least that's what Hruska told me.
Hruska's looking after him.
The grate!
I knew I'd forgotten something!
D' you have a grate?
- Hello!
Hello!
Been waiting long?
- A couple of minutes.
- The notary, Mr. Grulich.
- The Lavickas.
- Hello!
- Hello! Hello! Hi!
- You see, Mr. Komarek...
- That's the owner?
...the letter...
- Yes, that's the owner.
...didn't answer our letter
so now we don't know.
- We'll soon see.
If Komarek has died,
it would be complicated, what?
- Such a sale takes years sometimes.
Somebody inherits,
I had a case the other day
with nine heirs to a house.
- That could happen here too.
- Eight of them agreed to sell.
One refused, and that was that!
So now it'll drag on for years.
The owner should have left a will.
- Daddy, he's crying!
What is it, Pete?
What don't you understand now?
- Gran... dad... died.
Go on...!
They're just talking...
...just pretend, see?
- He may not have died,
maybe he just can't hold a pen any more.
- How many heirs are there?
- A son in Slovakia, a father...
- Was there a Will?
- Hardly.
- But they had a preliminary...
...sales contract.
- So they should have the right...
- But such a contract alone
means nothing.
Probably not even witnessed.
- Probably not.
- No good, then.
- What do you mean, no good?
But he has the right to decide
who is to inherit his property!
- But as a dead man can't make
any decisions...!
- I'm not saying he can!
- The Will is decisive!
Look!
Children!
- Grandad!
Isha!
- Welcome!
Featuring
Properties
Costume Designer
Wardrobe
Continuity
Assistant Director
Assistant to Head of Production
Assistant Set Designer
Assistant Cameraman
Set Designer
Make-up
Sound Editor
Film Editor
Music by
Played by
Conducted by
Head of Production Team
Director of Photography
Directed by
Produced by
Dramatist
THE END