ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
Eda!
Mum, just a few more minutes.
Prague -
September 1945.
The Nazis have been defeated.
The Communists haven't yet taken over.
Put your hat on properly!
Don't lose it!
Let me look at you.
Straight there, then home.
Give me some.
Screenplay
Starring
Sound
Music
Edited by
Production
Director of Photography
Directed by
- That'd be something!
- What?
If I could play like that
I could earn money in pubs.
Mum and Dad'll probably
buy me a full-size violin now.
Violins just screetch
but an accordion...
- A liter of beer.
- I'll be right back.
- Hi, Dad.
- Hi, mate!
Want some? Here.
- Daddy, come home!
- I can't leave yet.
Tell Mum the cards
are going Dad's way
and if he stopped now
he'd ruin the family!
- Trump!
- Come and get it!
Here you are!
My husband's back
from the tram tracks!
- Can't you clear away?
- In a minute!
Look at the time!
I can't enjoy my dinner unless
I've finished what I'm doing!
You take her, Eda. The dinner's
been ready for ages!
She'll settle down if
you push her over the bump.
Come and hold the light for me.
You're so clumsy!
It's a temporary connection.
Hold this red resistor up
to this wire... here...
What's the matter with you?
Don't hit him on the head.
He'll become stupid.
Become? He already is!
Chroust said how could you
who put matches in the cockets,
- call yourself an electrician?
- You telling me what to do?
Tell Chroust we wanted
it painted straight.
Not crooked.
You call that straight?
Every day I have to look at it.
His sloppy work!
Don't step on the couch
in your slippers!
Hold it.
If this doesn't work,
I don't know what will.
Turn that down!
Come and help me clear away.
- What was wrong?
- Stupid resistor!
How did you work out
what was wrong?
It's my job.
Good that you understand
these things.
Wash your hands.
Both of you.
Open your mouth.
It's good for your bones,
blood, the lot.
You're as thin as a beanpole.
Bon appetit!
Look at the way you're sitting!
Hook them over your shoulders.
You're a growing boy.
You've got to sit up straight!
You know
how Mr Chroust walks.
Chroust! An example?
Has the bearing of a soldier.
He sticks his chest out
like a pigeon.
Is Mr Chroust a Labour unionist?
- Mr Chroust's an idiot.
- But a Labour unionist too.
You can have clever Labour unionist,
like Mr Ludvik...
Every political party has
clever and stupid members.
Which party has
the most idiots?
Eat up, it'll get cold.
You can't talk to kids
about this sort of thing.
Now he'll tell Chroust
that he's an idiot.
At least he'd know at last.
If there are male and
female flowers on a plant...
Please don't whistle like that!
Examples of which are the birch,
hazel and cucumber.
I can't cane you. You don't
care about your results.
You won't see reason.
You can stand on your heads
for all I care.
It's your fault what becomes
of you. I just do my job.
There are many flowers
with male and female partners.
She's only wearing that smock.
- Who?
- What's that?
She's not wearing knickers.
She doesn't wear anything
underneath when it's hot.
She must have some shorts on!
Women don't wear shorts.
He must know.
He's repeated her class.
It shows when she sits down.
But you have to get up close.
They fly from flower to flower.
In cemeteries, gardens...
This is how they
fertilize the trees.
That's much better.
That's how you're meant
to behave.
This is how you'll learn about
nature and its mysteries.
Only bumble-bees
can get into some flowers
because of their long proboscis.
In chestnut tree flowers
you'll only see bumble-bees.
Sometimes the trees attract
ordinary bees,
but they soon realize
their proboscis is too short.
Bumble-bees also like clover.
- She is wearing some.
- So tell me their colour!
Pink ones, like my Mum's.
Yes, pink clover is a feast
for bumble-bees.
He had the same name as you?
Yeah.
Ugh!
What was he like?
I don't know.
He died before I was born.
They said he was a good boy.
When he died,
Mum took sleeping pills
because she didn't want
to live any more.
But they pumped out her stomach
and saved her.
Must've been horrible.
Yeah.
What happened to your brother?
He stood on a rusty nail
and his foot got infected.
That's why they're so careful
with me.
They don't want
anything to happen to me.
I'm not surprised, but
why give you the same name?
I'm a replacement.
You're a substitute.
School announcement.
We've acquired some tickets for
a performance of "The Idiot".
Any parents who want to see
"The Idiot", come and see me.
Our Principal's an idiot!
Silence! Be quiet!
Fakir, magician and juggler
Raji Tamil
will perform for us today...
I now ask the audience
to give me a word.
Cretin!
Toilet!
You're a disgrace!
The fakir will think
you don't know any other words!
Whore!
I can write it.
My feet can write any word
but they prefer to write
more beautiful words.
Say "spring".
Spring!
That's a very beautiful word.
Here are three hoops.
They're joined together.
Try to pull them apart,
check they've no joints...
There's no trickery
Now, give me the hoops and
I'll show you some magic.
Give the hoops back
so our guest can continue.
Give them back right now!
- We don't have them!
- They're not here!
If I get them back, you'll see
magic not on the program.
I'll swallow fire!
Quiet!
If you don't give back the hoops
when I count to three
not only will Mr Mrazek...
Raji Tamil is my name...
...not only will the fakir
not swallow fire,
but you'll go back to your
classes and continue lessons.
One...
two...
three...
End of the performance,
back to your classes!
I'll search you all myself,
you wretches!
Whoever has it will get
a "C" for behaviour!
Because it's theft!
Shame for the whole school!
I've never experienced this
before in my life!
Were those your only hoops?
No reserves?
Cretins!
They've disappeared
into the ground!
Want to see something?
Blimey!
But the head said
it was stealing.
It was a good laugh, eh?
Hi, Mum!
Hi!
Nice bike.
- It's my Dad's.
- But he doesn't use it.
He does when
he's late for work.
We'll have to dismantle it,
specially the mud-guards.
Dad might be angry.
He'll be glad we made a light
half-racing bike out of it.
They've problems again,
haven't they?
- And don't come back!
- I won't come back.
All those men I turned down!
Voracek,
Frantik from the butcher's,
I was a virgin then!
- Look where I ended up!
- My heart's packing up!
Nice people, eh?
Happens every day.
You don't have neighbours
like that, do you?
No.
- Why do they fight like that?
- He can't please her.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
Help me pour this away.
Just you see, he'll be
wearing black again.
Ready again?
You heard it?
My heart's packing up.
- Where's he going?
- To his coffin.
I'll have a heart attack
any minute.
It has to be.
You must enjoy yelling
at each other.
Think I enjoy it?
Ask her if she likes it!
Tormenting a person to death!
When she starts shouting,
he shaves and dresses in black
so she won't have to do
anything when he is dead.
Just in case you want
to hang yourself!
See that?
I don't know
what Dad's going to say.
Looks good.
See what I've got for you.
You'll think it's brill!
You'll kill that baby!
So it works! Now you can
look after the baby
- while you ride your bike.
- Yeah!
Watch out!
We all know that "Prague"
begins with a capital "P".
Be careful when you're writing
the adjective.
It's the same with other towns.
Who's going to write it
on the board? Eda!
Do stop whistling!
Good. Sit down.
One more time
and you're off to Vrsovice.
They'll sort you out there!
I want to go to Vrsovice.
I think we overslept!
You think or you know?
We didn't set
the alarm clock properly.
Half past six instead of six.
We didn't? You mean you didn't!
- Sorry, I got it wrong!
- You can't do anything!
Don't be angry with me!
You'll get there on time...
...if you take your bike.
You can eat some strudel
and an apple on the way.
Riding, strudel in one
hand, apple in the other!
So don't go far.
It looks like rain.
What a lovely baby!
You like it with
so much goose fat?
We didn't have it during
the war but now we do.
It's home-made,
my sister made it.
- I'm off. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- You know who died?
- No.
- Mrs Klecankova.
- I didn't know her.
Yes you did. The skinny one.
And young.
She wasn't even fifty.
Well, goodbye, then.
Feed it out... a bit more...
Hold it there...
Hi.
- What are you doing?
- Can't you see?
- Are they live?
- No, dead.
- Isn't it dangerous?
- Yeah.
Ever chewed gum? Got any left?
- I've only got half left.
- Give him some.
It's American, but don't
swallow it, just chew it.
- Thanks.
- Give me some, too.
Shove off.
You bums!
Get that pram away from here!
- How high will it go?
- 1000 metres.
Shit!
Out of the way!
Don't touch it!
Wait till I catch you,
you little sods!
It needed a longer pipe
or a different fuel.
- What's up with him?
- What's the matter?
I swallowed the gum.
It won't hurt you.
- But there's no more left!
- We'll get some more.
Look!
'Bye!
It's Dad. He took the bicycle
that's why he's home earlier.
Where are my mud-guards?
Where are they?
You rascal!
Not with that!
If you cripple him...
Don't hide behind a woman,
you coward!
On all fronts.
- Even the Germans?
- Dad said on all fronts.
How could Germans sing
"Roll out the barrels"
when they can't speak the language.
The Americans and the Russians
sang it as they marched.
And the Japanese?
I don't know.
And the partisans?
How could they sing
in hiding, stupid?
Who threw that?
See what I mean?
Miss Mayova won't be teaching
due to a prolonged illness,
so she won't be coming back
soon, maybe never.
Your new teacher
will be Mr. Hnizdo.
Let's welcome him.
I know that
his experience with
the anti-Nazi resistance
will help him to handle
you... where is Rosenheim?
He's not here!
...and soften up those
"heroes" among you.
The reputation of the class
is shattered.
Shattered.
I wish you much success.
My name is Igor Hnizdo.
Some idiot whistled.
So I threw a stone at him.
- What is your name, boy?
- Rosenheim.
You know you're late?
Not that late.
Four and half minutes.
Hold out your hand.
Now the other one.
Two for arriving late
and two for whistling outside.
It wasn't me!
And two for lying.
You're not allowed to hit us.
Correct. Corporal punishment
at school is forbidden.
With one exception.
This class.
A class that drives its teacher
into an asylum must be beaten.
Ministry of Education
issued a decree.
For your interest
it's decree no. 284/ C/1945.
I'll beat you with this medieval
instrument if you behave
as if in the Middle Ages.
It's for your own good.
You'll thank me each time
and we'll shake hands
to show our friendship
hasn't suffered.
Let's demonstrate with these
boys who aren't listening.
Thank you.
Teachers are sent here
as a punishment.
In this part police used
to patrol only on horses...
...and always in pairs.
I chose to come to this
appalling school because
I used to volunteer
for the front line.
I never feared the Nazis,
so I should be able
to cope with you.
It's a 635 calibre.
A small weapon.
War criminals are still at large.
Not all scores...
...are settled.
Where're you off to?
I'm bringing Dad his dinner.
Your boy's here, OK?
- They're transformers.
- I know.
That's you.
What d'you mean?
They call you "the Transformer".
Everyone has a nickname here.
Look.
When we're doing repairs,
I use this rod
to test the transformer.
If it doesn't spark,
I know there's no current
and I can touch it
with my bare hands.
Then I can let
the repairmen near it.
Aren't you afraid?
Yes, I could get burnt
to a cinder.
If I touch it
and don't turn black, it's OK.
- Has anyone ever got burnt?
- Yes, Mr Hlavaty, Mr Hejplik...
What've you brought me, Camil?
Nothing for you.
And I'm not called Camil.
That's not very nice of you!
Not nice at all, Camil!
Just in time today.
Get ready, here we go...
Now!
It's all lit up!
He's started off well, inspector.
He has them well-disciplined.
- Leave him in the boys' class.
- Yes.
Is it true he taught music
in a girls' school?
Yes.
So he was sent here
as punishment?
Leave him in the boys' class.
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
I'm watching the game.
Sorry.
My husband's a tram driver.
Really?
It's 3:3!
Excellent. Who scored?
Dusicka.
Excellent!
He couldn't suddenly
come home?
It would create
a real traffic jam.
He has to work according
to the timetable.
I have real coffee.
You've such a long hair!
Long hair - little brain, eh?
It's not a penalty if your hand
touches the ball by acci...
If it's by accident,
under no circumstances.
See?
You blind? Ball's out!
Dad painted that.
By himself?
From a postcard.
He can do anything.
Why's there a hole in every cake?
So I can see which ones
have cheese in them.
- I don't like cheese.
- I don't mind it.
If you like, I'll eat
all the cheese ones.
Go ahead.
- Men aren't so interesting.
- I don't go for them, either.
Wow!
You know what Stavinoha says?
The greatest delight is
to have a woman.
- You mean, as a wife?
- I suppose so.
I've seen my Mum naked.
So have I. In the bath.
- That doesn't count.
- I know.
D'you like the Fabian twins?
- Yeah.
- Which girl's better?
They're both the same.
On Friday evening you're going
to see something.
If you're not afraid of heights.
No I'm not.
OK, you'll see something.
Sorrow reigned across the land.
All eyes were on Constance.
The most treacherous of all
was King Sigismund.
Though he promised Hus safety,
he told the cardinals
not to believe Hus
and to burn him.
Hus could've saved himself
if he'd recanted,
and signed what they wanted.
How could he against
such false testimony?
He would've slained the truth
and for the truth he lived.
He said: "I would rather die."
So he was stripped of
his priesthood
and taken before King Sigismund
who ordered that an absurd hat
be placed on his head.
They tied him to a stake
and burned him alive.
The swine!
He was still singing
when they set fire to him.
He wasn't afraid of death.
He knew God would accept
him among his faithful.
Then the choking smoke,
kinder than the people,
took away his consciousness.
And his singing ceased.
He was no longer
among the living.
We shall remember that he died
for his convictions.
His message to us:
No man should be a coward!
He must honour the truth,
even if it costs him his life.
The fire raged,
on the bank of the Rhine,
the faithful
son of the nation dies.
And you ask:
"Who is in those flames?"
It is Jan Hus -
the most famous of Czechs.
Attention!
Important announcement!
Winter has arrived,
bringing the frosts.
The iron railings
in front of the school
can cause accidents.
Metal objects
become sticky in the frosts.
It is dangerous to touch
or even lick these objects.
I repeat:
Do not lick the iron railings.
Do not lick
the frozen door-handles.
End of the announcement.
You don't deserve it but we can't
put off your tenth birthday
until you start
behaving sensibly,
so from Mum you've got
a nice cake and from me...
An air-rifle!
It's not really an air-rifle...
...but it is a weapon.
Were you in the resistance?
Our teacher was.
In the resistance...
You know your Dad listened
to illegal radio.
He fixed his radio for it and
risked his life.
But he wasn't in the resistance.
Then there was that man
we hid illegally.
But you built barricades
and you weren't afraid!
I was afraid.
But you used a gun.
I had a gun.
Dad was a civilian.
He wasn't trained to fight.
Now you won't have to lean
your music against the pot.
Dad made it himself.
Do you like it?
Yes.
Music is
the most powerful weapon.
With music Czechs
conquered the world.
Smetana, Dvorak,
even Friml's "Donkey Serenade".
Let's put it to the test.
We don't have to,
it'll be fine.
Perhaps we could make
some improvements.
They have to get changed
for their dance class.
I don't think
we should do it.
Remember Hus died
for the Truth.
Perhaps it isn't him.
Mrazek - Juggler.
Can't be anyone else.
- Hey! Hi!
- Hi!
My friend wants to own up
that he stole your hoops.
He's brought them back.
Wait a moment.
Go get them!
Tear them apart!
At least you could bark,
you lazy animal!
Thieving bastards!
Know how much new ones cost?!
- Truth is stupid!
- No it isn't!
We're suffering like Hus!
Don't move! No-one move!
Don't try to do it yourself.
Hold on!
That's how you'll end up
if you don't hold on!
Don't be afraid of the flame.
It's for your own good!
Careful!
Didn't I warn them?
- Didn't you hear the warning?
- Yes, I did!
This isn't a school,
it's Sing-Sing!
Watch them!
All pedagogical methods
have failed.
They're so unpredictable.
I don't think you should
announce dangers over the radio.
That way you point them out
and then they have to try it.
If I tell them: don't drink
acid it'll eat your insides,
you're telling me
they'll drink it?
I don't know, but better not
say anything on the radio.
I wanted to ask you - do you
know Lieutenant Molnar?
No.
He also fought
in Africa like you.
He doesn't know you either.
I wasn't there long - they
sent me to the Eastern front.
I don't like leaving them
on their own.
Hello.
A litre of beer.
Hi!
Let's go, Dad.
Mum wants me
to bring you back.
I'll fleece you!
Look at that!
Give him one!
Where you get
all these trumps from?
Greetings!
Look who's here!
In trouble again!
You said it.
Didn't think I'd make it here.
For the last journey.
I need it.
My heart's about to give in.
Give it here.
Let's see
if this will flush him out!
It's really smoky
in there today!
It's your smoking
that's done it!
Who did it?
I thought I'd had it!
Tonda, come and see what Dad
won at cards for you!
I won an accordion!
Come and sit with us, ladies.
Make some room, boys.
We're talking about Dvorak,
how it was lucky
he didn't become a butcher
but a composer
who conquered the world.
In America
where he was invited...
What's the matter?
They said the gypsies
were on the side of the Germans.
- Who said that?
- Everyone.
In our partisan division
we had to stop
a German motorized convoy
in the mountains.
A Slovak gypsy said
to his commander:
"My face is darker, I'll be
well hidden in the rock.
Give me that anti-tank bomb."
And, boys...
and girls,
he gave it to that Nazi
tiger right in the belly!
The gypsies were good fighters.
Shame so many of them perished
in concentration camps.
Anyone wants me to teach them
the violin?
Women play in Orchestras today.
I'd like to!
If only you could play
like that one day.
Do you think he's got talent?
It seems to me he only
makes a noise.
He's got talent and a musical
ear, but he's got to work!
Hear that?
Off you go!
Careful! You nearly had
your teacher's eye out!
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Hello. How's it going?
He nearly poked
his teacher's eye out!
- I didn't mean to.
- It was nothing.
He got carried away.
- I'm Igor Hnizdo.
- Soucek.
- I'm glad you've taken them on.
- It was necessary.
Excellent soup.
Have some more.
How do you see
the political situation?
- The international situation?
- The works.
- I see our country as a bridge.
- No more thank you.
A bridge between
East and West.
Russia can learn democracy here
because they've never known it,
and the West will see
how freedom and socialism
can live under one roof.
We can show the world what
a small hard-working nation
can achieve
when no-one interferes.
Do you eat rabbit?
I cooked a rabbit.
Stalin said:
"What you bake, you will eat."
The Russians won't interfere
and the Germans are finished;
we've nothing to worry about.
These children can look forward
to a great future.
They'll be able to travel,
and see the world.
Dusicka and Lerch!
Hello.
- Hello, girls.
- Can we carry your books?
No thank you.
I've got trusty helpers.
- We've nothing to do.
- Really we haven't.
Sir...
Next time, boys.
Igor!
Ice-cream!
- Vanek's here!
- I was here first!
I've got three flavours
today!
He's lying.
- Who?
- Our teacher.
You can't be a parachutist,
partisan, political prisoner
and commander
of an armored train.
He wouldn't be able
to teach us if he lied!
He landed behind enemy lines
by parachute, at night.
He went into the woods to be
with his partisan division.
Then he was captured and put
into a concentration camp...
- He escaped...
- Escaped, did he?
It was impossible
to escape from the camps.
They were surrounded
by electrified barbed wire.
He could've dug his way out,
idiot.
And then he was a commander
in the revolt.
Just children's stories.
If he's allowed to carry
a revolver, he must have fought!
Who knows what he did
during the war.
You take that back!
No, I won't!
Take back what you said!
He won't take it back like that.
It's got to be like this!
- Eat it!
- Bastard!
I need two trusty helpers...
...to take a letter to Zizkov
school by 12 pm!
The Indian way -
what does that mean?
A hundred steps to walk,
a hundred steps to run!
It's very important, so my
messengers have to be fit
and must know how to find their
bearings in the terrain.
Leave your books here -
I'll wait until you get back.
Let's go to Zizkov by train.
The sand wagons are coming up!
- What if it doesn't go there?
- These tracks go there!
- I'm scared!
- Hold onto me!
- No!
- Chicken! I'll jump, then!
- I'm jumping!
- So am I!
I don't think we're going
to Zizkov.
We'll get off
at the next station.
Look - Prague, Hostivar.
We forgot that freight trains
never stop at stations.
If we'd gone to Zizkov,
it still wouldn't have stopped.
So it doesn't matter anyway.
True.
But it has to stop sometime.
When the lights are red
or if the coal runs out.
The tender's full of coal.
They have to stop for water.
You're right.
Look, a pump!
They could've taken water there.
They've got huge tanks.
They'll last
a hundred kilometres.
A hundred?
This is Benesov post office.
Is that Zizkov school?
Can I speak to Miss Melcova?
She's teaching?
I'll ring back in five minutes.
Tell her I'm going to call.
It's very important.
You can speak to
your teacher in five minutes.
Thank you.
What is so important
that you're in such a hurry?
- We can't tell anyone.
- Only her.
It must be a cipher.
Or a secret code.
Go to the booth.
We've got a message from
our teacher, Mr Hnizdo.
We couldn't get it to you
so we'll read it you.
"Igor repeats his challenge.
To remain a virgin
means not to blossom.
Another chance tonight.
Igor the Painless.
P.S. Answer by return of post."
Are you there, Miss?
She didn't even say
thank you.
- We're off.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Did they pay?
No.
Come in.
Good afternoon.
Eda didn't come home
for lunch today.
Did he stay behind?
I sent him on an important
errand - for the school.
They should've been here
ages ago.
D'you think something's
happened to him?
No, they've probably wandered
off somewhere.
I'm really worried.
I've already lost one child.
I know, I know...
If anything's happened to him...
We went by train
but it only stopped at Benesov.
We were delayed
but we delivered the message.
We don't go to Zizkov
by train nor via Benesov!
They're given physical
punishment - you don't mind?
Where's the answer to my letter?
Where is it?
I read it to her over the phone
and she didn't say anything.
She didn't even say thank you.
Separate them in class,
because my son would never
have thought of this.
I'll separate them completely.
D'you know who died?
Vanek, the ice-cream man.
- I didn't know him.
- Yes you did.
The one who rode
that motor-bike.
Him?
He was drunk and crashed
into a poplar tree.
- Ice cream, wasps, a mess!
- I'll take one, please.
Your headmaster wouldn't
believe you had it in you!
Praise to Cejka, a born accordion
player, a musical talent.
We'll celebrate the 1st
anniversary of the liberation
not just with song,
but also with drama!
Let it be about
the partisans!
Not only about the partisans but
all those who fought
against the Nazis.
They say he'll be locked up.
It's true.
He's been charged.
- What?
- Charged.
With touching girls up.
He's been touching up
the twins.
Mum says he got them
pregnant.
Hi, you cows!
I hear you're pregnant!
- You're an idiot!
- And you're stupid!
Is that basket
for the babies?
Let me introduce your new
teacher, Miss Plecita.
We want our teacher!
Mr Hnizdo was dismissed because
he used excessive
corporal punishment.
- It's not true!
- Who said so?
Didn't he beat you?
Those who were beaten
come forward.
Rosenheim, didn't he beat you?
No.
I hope you're not lying to me.
Your mother complained to me
that you had swollen hands.
She's talking rubbish.
Which song-birds do you know?
The tit!
Two tits!
Miss...
It's been cleared up.
Truth triumphed, as it
says in our coat of arms.
We kept it quiet about
you beating us.
I know, thank you.
Remember what I told you
about Ancient Rome,
even if it's not
for 11-year-olds.
They had a democracy, but
in danger elected a dictator.
For us, the danger has ended.
You have proved that
a dictator is redundant.
Who d'you think
will win the election?
I'd say the Communists.
Me, too, that's why
I'm not giving them my vote.
Their plans are not bad...
"We're against collective
farms and any form of
forced collectivization.
The Communists are for trades
and small businesses."
I voted for them before the war
so they'd have more votes -
it's better for democracy
if there's a strong opposition.
Of course.
The ruling party must be afraid
things could turn
and they'll loose their majority
in the next election.
Otherwise they'd be
unbearably arrogant.
They can be tough.
We're Slavs, but western Slavs!
Here, no dictatorship
can flourish.
It's not in the spirit
of the nation, not so?
Here we are!
Stop the bus!
Here you see it!
These bunkers were built
all along the frontier.
From each one you can see
the other,
their lines of fire crossed so
even a mouse couldn't pass.
No cement or iron was spared.
They're so strong that when
the Nazis got hold of them,
and tried to blow them
up - they couldn't!
They even tried to blow one up
in front of Hitler;
the bunker was lifted off
the ground but landed intact!
We should've defended ourselves.
How could we
if the Allies betrayed us?
The Russians were ready
to help us.
The Russians?
Hitler drove them back to Moscow.
If we'd fought back,
we wouldn't be here.
There would've been
so much bloodshed!
I can't see anything!
Guys, where are you?
Here! Come here!
- Where are you?
- We're here!
Who knows what it would've been
like if we'd gone it alone.
I was a civilian,
because of an injury.
Served in one of these?
Seem to know it quite well.
In this one.
Then you went to the Western
or Eastern front?
My son tells us such
stories about you.
One wonders
how you managed it all.
I want them to have an example.
I understand.
- Come and see what we found!
- It hasn't exploded yet!
Don't touch anything!
Everyone take ten steps back.
This is a very dangerous object.
It's an anti-tank bomb.
A very efficient weapon
of Hitler's.
A bazooka!
Yes, a bazooka.
Defuse it, Sir!
If anyone knows how to defuse it,
best get it over with.
Blow it up!
Now you'll see what we do
in cases like this.
Group A - me, you and the driver
goes to the nearest military
headquarters to report it.
Group B - that's Mr Soucek
stays here on guard.
Forward march!
We won't be in Prague by eight.
Their parents'll go mad!
Group A - hit the ground!
You useless idiot!
Pack up your bags and go!
I've never seen anything
like it!
- Hello.
- Hello, lad.
Go and visit him.
He only just escaped death.
For me it'll be any minute.
- Hi.
- What happened?
Hand grenade out of a bottle.
I put some film in it,
lit it and corked it.
It blew up in my hand.
A terrible blast.
Thank God it didn't go
near your eyes!
Look under the bed.
It's yours.
I've lost three fingers.
Let's give it back to Mr Kavka.
Remember what happened
with the magician?
I'll keep it, then.
Have you tried discharging?
Sounds pretty hopeless.
Wake Modry up
and get the boys out.
I'll be right over.
Do you have to go there?
Yes.
Dad?
Be sure to use that rod.
Go back to sleep.
Are you afraid of the storm?
No, I can't sleep.
You and Dad won't divorce,
will you?
What on earth
are you talking about?
Mr Hnizdo
is better-looking
but I wouldn't want
any other Dad.
Who said I want another man?
Where did you get
such nonsense from?
You had your arms round
each other.
- I what?
- You were hugging him.
I saw you.
I was worried about you,
I must've huddled up to him.
It wasn't an embrace.
Yes, it was.
Poor child!
Your Daddy's been killed!
He was electrocuted!
Where are you going?
- Who's boy is this?
- The Transformer's.
What's up with you?
Mrs Mlejnkova's a complete idiot!
She heard "transformer"
and thought it was Dad!
Has that boy gone mad?
FIRST ANNIVERSARY
OF THE LIBERATION
Our programme...
Our programme continues with...
With the play "War is Over,
Peace is Everywhere."
Mr Hnizdo humbly omitted
the fact that
he wrote the play himself.
Our boy didn't want
to play a Nazi.
Who crawls out
of his hole?
A Nazi! Out of breath.
Whistle on, Nazi, the Allies
are coming for sure.
So rasp and croak away,
the Americans are in Plzen.
The Soviet tanks are just
outside Prague.
Czechs in the British
divisions make haste.
The partisans are firing
from all directions.
Not sweet is your song,
the political prisoners come.
Screech your song of death,
Nazi.
Together the Allies
will crush you.
Where's the one with the
moustache?
War is over,
peace is everywhere!
You were a real soldier
and partisan, weren't you?
Or you couldn't have written
so beautifully.
- I will always be a Slav!
- Another time, Lakatos.
Come on!
War is over, peace is
everywhere. Thus we shall behave.
We shall work; some with our
heads, some with our hands,
so that our Republic is an
example to the whole world.
THE END