25.000
GIVE THE DEVIL HIS DUE
Once upon a time
there was a kingdom
and in it a mill
wherein ruled Macha the miller,
a just and diligent man.
They had a fine son named Peter.
They'd have led a happy life
had it not been for...
...one kingdom thinking
the other better off...
...and this being
why the first was worse off...
whilst the third kingdom...
Based on the story by
Screenplay, Dramaturge
...was waiting for...
the first two to fight it out...
two to fight it out...
Starring and Featuring
With Historical Fencing Group Regius
Consultants
Mural Paintings by
Assistant Set Designer
Trick Sequences
2nd Unit Director
Continuity
Assistants to Production Manager
Costume Designer
Wardrobe
Properties
Special Effects
Music by
Played by
Film Staff
Sound Recordist
Make-up
Film Editor
Set Designer
Production Manager
Director of Photography
Directed by
Produced at
English sub-titles by Doris Koziskova
As if they'd all taken leave of their
senses.
For ten years the small kingdoms were
at war.
Peter grew into an upright young man.
But his father was losing his strenght,
grieving for the good wife he had lost.
Steward...
You maintained war
would make our fortune.
Where is that fortune?
To make it we'd have needed 5,000 ducats
for an army - to win!
Why did you make war then?
I keep you,
to keep track of these things!
It's no fun ruling.
I like hunting!
After your wars there isn't a partridge
in my woods.
If we set up an army.
I'd need 5,000.
You've gone mad.
Damn it, where are my...
Keys?
Keys!
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Don't you know
where my cash-box keys are?
Adela!
- No, Pappa.
Angelina?
- Oh, Pappa.
Where can they be?
Adela!
But this is where you usually put them!
- Here!
I never put it there.
- There?
Here!
- There!
That's all...
AII? ...our cash.
- You promised me a new dress!
The steward needs money a new army.
- 5,000.
Adela never moans about new dresses.
Because I give her mine
and then have nothing to wear.
Let go,
this is State money.
Don't cry, Angelina,
this dress is good enough for me.
- Shut up, you goose.
I'll never get married this way.
Must I do it all myself, you lazybones?
You're such a help, my boy.
Ah, the steward...
Go watch your pots.
- We are honoured.
Have you thought of getting married,
Dorothy?
The man in my heart
would hardly choose me.
How about Machal the miller?
Machal?
That old geezer?
I thought you were more cunning.
If a bright young woman married him
the mill could soon hers.
But he's got a son.
That can be arranged.
Where did that cat come from?
In the kitchen?
Good morning, neighbour!
Good morning.
Dear God, what a mess!
I was passing by,
something's burning,
would you like some help?
Thank you.
This is a woman's job.
There, aren't they lovely.
Help yourselves!
There's lots!
In a matter of weeks -
they were married.
If an old man wants to play the fool,
he marries a young woman.
For this we'll buy the field by the
pond.
The mill's enough, Dorothy,
a field would mean more work still!
But Frankie, you're so strong!
Surely you don't feel old?
Of course not.
Mind you don't burn it.
Haven't you got a good wife?
I have.
Others would spend it all on clothes.
Why did you let the men go?
Whoever heard of two men doing all
the work?
You do nothing but lazy around.
We have no money to waste!
Dad, say something!
Dorothy is right, Peter.
We'll manage.
Frankie!
There's a dance on tonight.
You haven't forgotten, have you?
But Dorothy, I'm...
- Or do I go by myself?
No, Dorothy, no.
And now a gavotte!
Let's sit his out.
D'you want me to dance
with someone else?
No.
- Well then!
Faster!
Frankie!
Poor unhappy me.
What'll I do without him?!
Once upon a time there was Hell.
There they had a pair of scales,
not to weigh people's pounds
but their sins.
There was no cheating it.
Stop!
Stand still and give me a report!
Your Majesty, King of the Darkness,
Lucifer XIV.
I bear fresh news of Dorothy Machal.
Wait!
Where is the Book of Sins?
- It should have been here!
Her cup of sins has overflowed.
Here's the Book.
- Scram!
Come here!
You left your post?!
The Bat has taken over!
- Quiet!
I thought...
- Silence!
Scram!
Dorothy Machal, page 1027,
line eight.
- I can see.
Line eight...
So I see.
I look - and see!
Yes, here.
You impertinent devil.
What do I see?
What do we see?
Stand still!
Don't move!
I said don't move!
That's my boot.
That was your boot.
A feather.
Where did it come from?
Come here, Cat!
Here, come on!
Let's see your teeth!
Teeth!
Your hands!
The other one!
It hurts!
All devils - line up!
No!
Come here!
A chicken!
All change back!
Your hand!
What is that?!
I was so terribly hungry!
I'll show you, wanting meat.
I hereby degrade you to rabbit!
That was one single feather!
Were it not for my intervention...
the Book of Sins'd have been destroyed!
So was my advice good, Dorothy?
Very good.
Do help yourself,
we're not stingy like at the castle.
Yes.
How pretty you are today, Dorothy.
A young one.
Tender?
I hurried over
to tell you -
how sorry I am.
You didn't even know my father.
Go and mend the roof, it's leaking.
Did you hear me?
The lazy lout.
Get down at once!
Take that of the chimney!
I am mending the roof
as you told me to.
Did you hear me?
Climb down at once,
you young rascal!
At once!
You're right.
I'm going.
No.
You dropped something.
Help me, woman.
What is this?
It smells horrid.
Where're you going?
You haven't chopped the wood yet!
Let the steward chop it for you!
I'll be back when you're gone!
This will cost you dear!
You lot her cheat you out of everything?
Where's your common sense?
I didn't leave everything.
Look!
My mother's.
The ring I'll give my bride one day.
Peek-a-boo!
I've got the warrant for arrest
for that stepson of yours.
When his Majesty signs it
the mill will soon be ours.
I mean yours.
A life sentence.
- A life sentence.
Good!
- Isn't it?
But it'll cost something.
No, no.
There was no need for that.
Put you'll need some for his Majesty,
He's so money-minded.
Angeline!
Come on!
Wait!
Wait for me!
Caught you!
Look what you've done!
Torn my only dress!
I'm sorry, Angelina.
Forgive me.
Come on!
- We can darn it!
No we can't.
I am willing to ignore
that he wanted to kill me,
but he robbed his mother,
that sadly berieved widow,
and he up and left her
with the whole mill to look after!
What do I do?
I didn't bring up her son!
No, your Majesty!
You could jail him.
He is an incredibly dangerous man.
Look, come back some other time.
I'm busy right now.
So he's a naughty boy?
I'm a helpless woman,
I'm afraid of him!
You're telling me,
children are a worry.
Yes.
Here.
Pappa, now you'll admit
that I need a new dress!
Here.
What has Petr Machal done,
that you want him jailed?
Children...
- May I?
There.
Would your Majesty take up the pen
and sign here, please.
Sign up, Pappa!
After you've ascertained
who's in the right!
- Oh, come on.
Right indeed.
Yes.
Joseph the Handsome.
I didn't hear you say good day.
On his Majesty's decision
you are under arrest.
No.
Arrested?
Why?
They'll explain at the castle.
Come on!
Go away!
Come on up!
You'll pay for this.
My best to his Majesty.
You must run.
Why?
I haven't done anything.
How can you rebel against the masters?
You must always stay in their good books
if you want to live in contentment.
I want to live in contentment, Grandma.
But here.
What's this?
Open the door!
Is there anything wrong?
Search the place!
Quickly!
Quick!
Open everything up!
Look properly!
Search everything thoroughly!
He has to be here somewhere!
He isn't here.
- He isn't?
Take her to the castle!
She'll be jailed instead of Peter!
Let her go!
Give in, Machal!
Catch him!
Here!
Catch!
Well, come on!
Come on, then!
Watcher rolling about for?
Where is he?
I'll catch him myself.
Machal, halt!
Help!
Help us!
Bravo, young man!
You've saved us.
Tell me,
where did you learn to ride so well?
We could have been killed.
Thank you.
Tie him up!
Quickly!
Come on!
Let's go.
Wait!
But he saved our lives!
Sorry, here's the warrant.
Take him away.
But that's unjust.
Angelina!
We thank you, Peter!
Don't mention it.
- Go!
On the other hand it was he
who made our horses shy off!
Bravo!
Bravissimo!
And now draw up a deed
that the whole mill is mine.
Dorothy Machal...
here.
It is high time
to bring Dorothy Machal down to Hell.
Who volunteers?
The first were Horse and Goat.
Make your choice!
A map of the village
a description of Dorothy Machal.
Watch out for feathers
and no alcohol!
Peter!
It's you.
I've brought some food.
Thanks.
Tomorrow they'll judge you.
Don't argue with father.
He's not a bad man,
but he doesn't like quarrelsome people.
Will your sister be there?
Angelina'll be there.
And what's your name?
- Adela.
I'll have to go.
Bye,
and thanks, Adela.
Ripple softly,
sweet breeze
cool my hot brow
and stop it aching.
Cool my hot brow
Call him gently, my Peter
tell him that we two are made
for each other.
Tell him that we two are made
Is that you, Angelina?
I knew you'd come.
Answer me, Angelina!
I only wanted to see you.
It wouldn't kill you to go and see him.
He thinks of nothing but you.
- Such a pauper, and in jail?!
No good to me at all.
They'll be judging him tomorrow.
Do talk to father,
he heeds your words.
Do you know this rock?
That's Devil's Rock.
- Let's climb up.
One shouldn't play around with
such things.
You're such a baby!
Adela!
Angelina!
Catch me!
Wait for me!
Adela, come quickly!
How dare you? You thief!
Forgive me ladies, I'm so hungry
and when I saw this snack?
That was our food for the whole day!
I'll have you locked up!
Thanks for the hospitality, ladies.
Where did you get this?
The ducats are real.
He was very odd.
I told you to keep away
from Devil's Rock.
I'll believe in devils when I see one!
Away with you!
Dash it, feathers!
A lovely day today!
Help!
What happened, Ma'am?
Nothing.
Just a bang in the stove.
You have a visitor.
- Who?
I'm no visitor.
This is more my home than yours.
What do you want?
- I came because of Peter.
It's that steward, not me!
I love Peter!
But...
- I need him here.
Tomorrow I'll go to the castle
and beg them to let him go.
I'll go now.
Would you watch my tarts
so they don't burn?
I'll be right back.
And that's that.
The old cow.
Take those weights off.
You inefficient fools!
Can someone explain
what this is about?
I'd like to know too.
The deuce!
It's not dropping?!
Are you Mrs Machal?
That I am.
Let's see!
Where is it?
- Here.
Are you Dorothy Machal?
Oh no!
I'm Anna Machal.
Peter's grandmother, not stepmother.
Horse, come here!
Here!
You are degraded from the rank of Horse!
Come for your wolf's tail tomorrow.
Scram!
Take her down!
What the devil do we do with her?
What now?
You brought me here,
you can take me back again.
Definitely not.
- No.
Hell has its rules.
Exactly.
What Hell has claimed its own
must not Earth bemoan!
Unless Mrs Machal were willing
to work off Horse's mistake here.
What choice do I have.
At least it's nice and warm here.
He stole this jewel-box
from his poor stepmother
and then fled.
That's not true!
They are my things!
My real mother gave them to me!
They're my jewels, he stole them!
Why would he have fled otherwise?
After all my loving care!
He is a rebel!
He wounded three soldiers,
bruised two...
and made a fool of one.
I didn't steal anything!
Ask my grandmother whose they are.
Why is she not here?
The devil carried her off!
I saw it with my own eyes.
You see, what a family.
Hell is never wrong,
I suggest a life sentence.
Life?
Till the end of his life?
Yes, your Majesty,
I suggest a life sentence.
Angelina, say something.
And confiscated property.
Justice is justice.
I don't know what he's guilty of,
but he saved our lives
when he stopped the runaway horses.
When he fled from justice, you mean.
Angelina'll tell you about it.
Speak up, we're waiting.
I don't know, Pappa.
I was too frightened.
But Angelina!
I request that he...
Stick him in the army, your Majesty!
For 10 years.
No!
Hold him!
I'll tame him.
Not long enough, for life!
12 years, then.
Your task is clear!
Bring Dorothy Machal
or don't come back!
Who volunteers?
What?
How dare you after all that!
Our object is making good use
of your mistake!
I thought...
- Silence!
And no thinking!
I'll turn you into a worm!
You too.
You need taking down a peg or two.
We're the ones to do the thinking.
Not you, scribe!
No!
Mr Lucifer, in your place
I'd send the one who botched it up.
He'll try all the harder.
I know this Johnny?
Yeah, some Johnny?
I've learnt a new trick.
Watch!
Only the Prince of Hell
may change his likeness!
Correct.
Naturally.
But costumes may be changed.
How hard Johnny's trying!
And he knows the place now,
he won't make another mistake.
Attention!
What for?
I'll show you what for!
Put that log down!
Call these buttons sewn on?
This one.
Stack' em up!
It's come down!
Halt!
Start building it up!
Come in!
How could I have lived without all this.
Shut your eyes, Dorothy.
Now?
He looked like...
- The devil.
Yes.
And he's scared of feathers!
Not for me, thanks.
This Finicky-Nick doesn't like our beer!
You don't like our beer?
It's good.
Say it's good didn't taste it.
Tasting means drinking, my boy!
All of it?
- AII!
And bring him another!
I bet we'll recruit 10 today!
Two bottles!
No, three!
Last time the wager was for four.
That was last time.
It's come down again.
Must be the wind.
Stack' em up!
And move it!
Come on, men.
Ah, for our lovely pub
ah, for their lovely grub,
the soup is so hot
the boor is with froth!
Pour out for the boys toe.
Here you are, boys.
Bring it here.
Sign it here.
Here.
There'll be not work in the army?
There's never work!
Nothing but parades and reviews-
and money!
I can't write.
Never mind, your thumb.
A great idea!
What's this?
Who put it here?
Who did it?
Whose stupid joke was it?
The deuce!
Get up!
Surprise!
Didn't expect me?
What are you wearing, you fool?
Out!
I thought...
- Don't think, shut up!
Where's your tail?
In my suit.
- In what suit?
The soldiers burnt it all!
By Satan, you let them burn your tail
and sign you up for the army!
From now on you're
an ordinary mortal!
Hell is shut for you forever!
Mercy!
Prince of Darkness,
I'll do anything to set it right!
Mercy!
I promise never to drink again!
Let me go!
I'm no soldier, I'm a devil!
I've come for a widow?!
A widow? A devil?
You wait!
Arms up!
One, two, three, four!
Arms down!
Forward march!
One, two, three, four!
Halt!
Call that marching?
Your name and rank!
Devil of Horse rank, no Wolf.
What?
You dare make fun of me?
Down - up!
Down!
Up!
Come in to the garden.
Wait.
Down!
Up!
Arms at the ready!
That's rebellion!
Throw your weapon down!
What's that?
Machal, back in line!
What did I say?
Get back, Machal!
20 days' jail
and 50 lashings!
Come back!
Did you see that?
Peter must have a good heart.
You and your Peter.
Mine?
You know he wants you.
And you?
Exactly.
Men need tricking, you silly.
50 lashings.
They shout at you all day
make you roll in the mud.
And all because of that woman.
Surely you're not in love?
No fear.
I was to bring a bad widow to Hell.
Was it Dorothy Machal by any chance?
How do you know?
If anybody I know deserves hell,
it's my stepmother.
So you are Peter?
And you really are a devil.
I should say!
Oh, but I'm not any more.
I'd have to get my wolf's tail back.
A wolf's tail?
I can't go back to hell till I have it.
What do you mean, a wolf's tail?
I can't change back without it.
I don't get it.
Go clean out the stables.
Doesn't Princess Angelina
look lovely?
Our cash-box is empty,
the ceiling's coming down
and we hold balls for borrowed money.
Curtsy, Angelina!
To the green one.
It's all arranged.
Angelina, Curtsy.
Angelina will marry richest suitor,
we'll pay our debts and have some over.
Do you like any of them?
Whom do you like?
Who is the richest?
She says who is the richest?
Well, who is the richest?
- Who is??
Quietly.
I'll find out.
Can it be a dead wolf's tail?
Sure,
how'd you out it off a live one?
I know of one.
But how to got out of the barracks.
Wait!
Ah, for our lovely pub
ah, for their lovely grub,
the soup is so hot
the boor is with froth!
What's happening?
What's should be?
Nothing?
- Nothing.
Sure?
- Sure.
I know now who's the richest.
I've investigated.
According to ancient custom
the Princess will throw a golden apple,
the man it stops by will become
her husband.
But that's not gold.
No, I shall gold it.
What if it rolls some Pauper?
Yes.
The ball is actually made of iron.
And this stone will make it stop
by the richest of the suitors.
Try pulling it away.
I can't.
I'll do it.
What is this stone?
It comes from Magnet Mountain
and attracts all iron objects.
I did say all iron objects.
Yes, but...
I'd prefer...
The army is important,
believe me.
Hello, officer!
What are you doing here?
How lovely you look, Princess.
And gallant, too.
But you haven't asked me dance yet!
Permit me to rectify my mistake.
For so long I've been wanting...
- Long?
I don't know you, you must be new.
Good evening, Peter.
- Good evening.
That's Machal, the young miller.
Where did you steal the uniform?
How dare you?
Guards!
Wait, Angelina!
I only wanted to see you.
Catch him!
Hurry up!
Throw him in prison!
Peter!
Hide in here!
He ran this way!
Come on!
Thank you, Princess.
- Run!
Prince, do you want our Princess?
I'd give anything...
Put this in your shoe and she is yours.
According to ancient custom
the Princess's husband
will be chosen...
justly... by this golden apple.
He to whom it rolls will have her.
As his wife!
As his wife.
The apple.
Roll it towards the left.
No!
Help!
Pappa!
I'll tell my Pappa and
he'll declare war!
Congratulations, you won.
My Pappa will make war on you.
Carry him away.
Pappa'll make war!
Take this thing out of my shoe!
What thing?
We've been cheated!
Take my shoe off!
We want the money we lent you!
We've been tricked!
- Silence!
We'll declare war together!
Take my shoe off!
My Pappa'll make war on you!
Sure.
What will we do?
Luckily we have a strong army.
There's a parade tomorrow.
What?
- A parade.
We have a parade?
Come and see.
- I'll come.
Action stations!
Dammit-all-to-hell
I said action stations!
Sound the alarm!
Attention!
Where is your uniform, you stupid?
This way.
Excuse me, where's the door.
Fire!
Come!
My dress!
Corporal!
Is this what you call a strong army?
Catch him!
Bring my horse!
Backwards again!
What?
- Turn me round!
Turn the horse round!
- Not the horse, me!
Wait.
Now.
Dorothy!
Let me go!
Leave me alone!
Help!
No!
Follow them!
Encircle them!
Quickly!
Everybody here!
Help!
Peter!
Give it to me.
Come on, Peter!
Follow them quickly!
We must get them!
How's that?
This doesn't load anywhere.
Dammit-all-to-hell!
You're ready for the gallows, Machal!
Hell's bells and cocker shells!
The gallows for you!
I snapped my sword!
My dear boy!
How happy I am to see you.
Good, she's sinking!
She's ours!
Take her!
She broke our scales.
Come here.
What do we do with him?
Leave me here for a few days.
They want to hang me.
Let go!
Take your hands away you hairy monster!
Help!
Let me go!
Don't touch me!
No,
help!
Help!
This is an ultimatum!
The ceiling's coming down.
Either I return their money within
the month
or they'll declare war.
Signed - all nine kingdoms.
Where am I to find the money?
How about selling the castle?
Are you mad?
Sell the roof over my head?
Actually, who'd buy the old ruin.
This castle was built
in the 12th century by my ancestors,
Ferdinand the Handsome and Josephine
the Mad.
Maybe I'd buy it off you,
to do you a favour.
The water strokes the pebbles
tenderly and softly
that is love.
Tenderly and softly
Peter, dearest Peter,
who'll tell you that we two
are made for each other.
Get up!
The Devil never sleeps!
He did all this in a few days.
Leave that be and come here!
What do you think you're doing?
All this work down here?!
You'll spoil our reputation!
Make three wishes
and back to Earth with you!
One wish -
take me back home.
Of course, I will.
But what else?
Wait a minute.
Ask for this.
Such a scruffy old coat?
- It's magic.
He who wears it finds a ducat
in his pocket every time.
What is your wish?
To go back to Earth
to fetch the Corporal!
I'm coming with you.
All right.
You may take the coat.
And your grandmother.
I'll let Johnny go under the condition
that he brings the Corporal and
the Steward.
All right.
But won't they hang me?
With that coat on you are protected.
Put it on!
But don't forget -
when you take it off you lose all
powers.
May we go?
Let's see you.
Yes, you may!
Whom do we fetch first,
the Steward or the Corporal?
I'm going home to bake some cakes.
We're going to the pub.
Not even Lucifer
will get me to the pub.
That's where all my troubles began!
So I'll make the sacrifice and go.
You keep watch outside.
- You're great.
The devil!
How did they recognize you?
Me? Look at yourself!
Potato soup.
A full plate, please!
Pork with sauerkraut.
- Yes, Sir.
Goulash.
With bread.
And cream-cheese dumplings.
Right,
but can you pay?
Your servant, Milord -
at first sight I thought...
that you're...
What?
The devil!
Oh no.
I'm no devil.
I only look that way.
Take a seat,
it won't be long.
Take them.
They're yours.
Lots of money you say?
Must be a foreigner.
He's throwing ducats around.
Ducats?
He hands out as many as they ask for.
But Angelina.
- He must be mad.
See?
- Dress up as a pauper and go!
We can't miss such a chance!
- 82, thank you.
- 83, thank you.
- 84, thank you.
Come in!
Excuse me.
That's the Steward, you know!
I know.
I'll knock his feathered hat off.
And I'll catch him.
Where were we?
- 80
- 81
- 82
- 83
How dare you?
See this feather?
I have two, just in case!
Noble foreigner, you won't believe me
but I'm the poorest man around.
They all cheat me,
my children, the steward...
All I have but debts.
What would you like, your Majesty?
How can you know I'm...
Let's not play hide and seek.
How much do you need?
20,000 ducats.
All right,
but if you give me your daughter in
marriage.
30.000
I know it's a lot.
I don't understand.
I'm not scared, but I need help.
Help?
I have the feeling the devil
is after me.
The devil...
The devil.
I'll think of something.
Don't bother,
I've done that myself.
But I need a certain bunch of keys.
Keys?
I know the whereabouts of the steward
and corporal.
I heard them make arrangements.
But they've still got the feather.
Never mind.
Is the look dependable?
Sure,
it can be unlocked only from outside
and there stand the guards.
We are absolutely safe.
Come on, you...
Come here.
Come, little orphan,
join the others.
Here I am.
High time, too.
Corporal!
Quickly.
Sound the alarm!
Which way?
What a lot of money!
I'll have some.
Help!
Where are they?
Soldiers, attention!
There they are!
Not there, this way.
The secret passage to the castle!
I'll help you.
This way?
Run!
Climb out!
No feathers.
- On our hats!
Back to the chest!
Quickly!
- This way!
I want to...
Wait here...
But Pappa...
- Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Come on!
Here we're safe.
And now we can disappear.
We're wasted in this stupid kingdom.
Thank you, Peter!
You'll have to marry him,
or he won't give us the money!
When he spruces up a bit...
I'm doing no such thing.
The Princess must marry me as I am.
I'll never marry such an eyesore!
Never!
Our debts!
Don't offend him.
I couldn't stand people seeing me
with such a fright!
As you like.
Goodbye.
Please, dear children!
There'd be war!
Get her to marry him, Pappa!
I'll keep my word.
My daughter will marry you.
She will sacrifice herself
for the Kingdom, for the family.
Au revoir.
Wait!
Poor little girl.
She'll get used to him.
One for us,
one for his Majesty.
Pull out another, Peter.
You'll need to renovate the mill.
One for us,
and one for us too.
And one each for luck.
Tomorrow we go to the castle.
I'm getting married.
Why are you doing that?
Thank you, Lucifer!
Who is it?
- Wait.
Yes, they're real.
I have come for my bride.
I'm marrying this one!
When I asked for your daughter,
I meant Adela.
This one?!
She's the one I'll marry.
Dear children.
I'll stay on the shelf?!
I'll think of something.
I want a husband now!
It's not fair!
Angelina, please?
- Excuse me.
May I have the pleasure?
With your permission.
Yes.
Angelina, a partner for you.
Interesting, passionate.
A good thing you didn't marry
that miller.
How about marrying a Prince?
Even the Prince of Hell?
Of course.
I don't believe in hell, you see.
In that case...
Lots of happiness.
Johnny!
But that's...
- She'll be fine.
Johnny!
I've got to go.
But...
Johnny!
Peter!
Hell may exist or not,
but it was a good idea.
If we look around us we see
that many people would be in need of it.
It isn't a good thing for people
to think
that evil can go unpunished.
I'm your love,
you are my love, too.
Why should we stay...
...why should we stay alone.
THE END