Even more crazy summer comedy
SUN, HAY
AND A SLAP
Story and Screenplay by
The Cast
Stage designer
Music by
Performed by:
Sound editor
Continuity
Production Manager
Cameramen
Directed by
Film authors thank
for cooperation to:
Made by
Hi.
- Ciao!
Good morning.
- Good morning... Hi... Good morning
Where're you off to, Blazenka?
I want to show the girls...
Do show us too!
My wedding invitations,
my Mum said to deliver them.
Mm... Mm...
- That's up-side-down.
Mm, Mm. Yea, yea...
I can't see a thing,
I sat on my glasses.
When is it to be?
- Soon, the Saturday after next.
Sure,
it's knocking on your belly-button!
Great fun, this.
Hello!
- Ciao.
May I?
Thanks.
All the best.
They smiled at each other,
did you see?
- But if looks could kill...
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You got one too?
Very nice, all gold.
Pity I can't see.
How much did it cost?
I wouldn't know.
No shot-gun wedding for me.
No, but she had two abortions,
the slut.
Don't stare at me!
Now then be good, Mum!
Don't keep making me mad!
For how long will I be held up here
like this?
Come on up at once!
- No!
The Doctor'll get angry.
- No. It does not matter...
Just let him get angry!
He'll go away and that's that!
Let him go, so what.
No one asked him.
He can take his own filthy medicine.
- Just try to pour it away...!
They'd do me in,
with such poisons!
Such horrible stuff!
She has poured it out... Of course!
This filthy, disgusting staff! My God...
You dare try that on me!
And you too with the filth!
The bastards all guzzle beer
and make me drink this!
I know why you go mad like this!
I bet the kids've brought you beer
and you're drunk!
Drunk - from what?
You don't give me food or drink -
more often than not.
Shame on you, Mum,
saying we don't feed you!
- It's true!
Don't pretend,
I'm an old woman
you need to get rid of me,
so you feed me on filth!
Come on, just,
just keep your mouth shut, mummy.
We give you the choice bits,
how can you say such things?!
Well, but it is true!
Like the soup today,
disgusting, gone off it was.
It was sour-cream soup!
It was supposed to be sour!
Say
what you want next time!
It was horrible muck.
But you ate it all!
Can you hear this, doctor?
- You never give me schnitzel!
You've got no teeth to chew it with!
I haven't, I haven't... Well, I have.
My teeth are in the side-board drawer.
They've been there for 15 years!
So how would you chew?
Make some goulash, then.
You know it gives you diarrhoea!
She always shits her bed afterwards.
Please stop it! Not in front of this.
I know what's behind it...
- And what?
Your old man's the same.
Meaning what?
I know he isn't worth a shit
but he's my husband!
A drunkard, and so are you!
How dare you, me and drunk?
- Yea, yea, yea!
You're the one who gets tipsy.
- You too.
Shame on you,
in front of the Doctor.
Dear God, I don't deserve
such a daughter!
You've got what you made
so don't complain!
Swallow this and shut up!
Why fight, I always win.
Just you dare spit it out!
She does it all the time.
I'm more of an animal-tamer
than loving daughter!
All this screaming,
the neighbours'll think
we beat you!
They want to get rid of me...
I'd rather go to the old peoples home
than this here.
What do I have here? Real purgatory.
- Well, granny...
Now then, today I'll give you
a better-tasting medicine!
You'll be up on the wedding-day!
You and your shitty medicines!
I told you not to talk that way
and damm it all
you keep swearing!
Why don't you feel ashamed?!
So old you could
to know better.
- I will not.
We do our best for you!
And what do you do?
If I did not tidy your scarf up
you'd disappear in there!
She has finished her rampage.
I'll have peace for minute.
The wedding-cakes,
Blaza's made some already, Doctor.
Come along.
We're so busy and this...
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Here's the wedding-invitation,
all gold,
isn't it lovely?!
It cost a mint!
Is that supposed to be a "K"?!
Leave me alone!
That's a fine "K",
if you saw mine...
You're educated, Doctor,
the chemist can read your handwriting,
but this?
He can't even write the addresses!
Christ, Bavorov with a small "b"!
Put it down, you idiot.
All you're good at is guzzling beer!
Where's the beautiful bride?
She's delivering the invitations.
This is the real stuff, from Moravia.
Well, doctor...
But Mrs Skopkova, I don't drink.
This isn't drink, Doctor.
This is medicine!
Just sniff!
You must drink Blazenka's health!
You've had enough.
Here.
Don't hesitate,
drink up!
Well then to Blazenka.
And bottoms up!
Ouch, it burns!
Now down the other leg!
Pity she's out,
I brought her something.
How beautiful!
What a waste,
the garden's full of flowers!
An orchid, look!
Blazena doesn't deserve it.
Do not say that, Mrs. Skopkova.
If I found such a girl,
I'd cherish her!
I know.
Where're you off to now?
I'm working like an idiot,
- And why?
Everyone's down by the river...
It won't...
- Hurry up!
It won't kill you.
Let's go.
- Well.
It won't kill you.
Venca!
What's up?!
The invitations!
Come and look at them!
Okay.
At ease, Joseph.
Great, aren't they?
- Mmmm.
Such pretty turtle-doves!
They give me ideas.
Stop it, Joseph's here.
He'll turn round.
Stop it!
Look, he's watching!
All right then...
Holy Elijah!
Crikey!
Away, impure thoughts.
Christ, what is it?
Apage, can you hear me?
Help!
Sodom and Gomorrah.
Christ's foot forwards!
Let him leave me! Let him leave me!
But I suppose
they may, now.
Let's go home.
Mother of God...
Dear old man, are you hurt?
An angel. A real angel!
Look where you're going, old fool!
Look, it's scratched.
Fuck it all!
Don't ride bikes if you're clumsy!
Be glad I didn't flatten you out!
So - are you okay?
Okay.
Let me help you.
That's all right, just mud.
Take it easy!
Very much.
I'll show you!
Let's go, girls!
I'll drive you to the village.
It's only a few steps.
Come on, climb in.
Wait!
- Let's go!
My brolly.
Virgin Mary, see this?
Your brolly and let's go.
God will repay.
- Yeah.
And my basket.
My bicycle!
Well, isn't he crazy...
Wasn't that the priest?
- In whose car?
Okay.
Let's go girls.
What happened, Father?
You look a sight, Father!
Isn't it horrible?
- Who was it?
A face like an angel
words tender and gentle
as she dusted my cassock
with a fragrant hand.
Some nightmare.
Mrs. Teacher!
Hello!
What are you doing here?
I knocked down some old geezer,
his bike scratched my car.
And such a lovely car!
Our old sinner Otto the priest.
Is he agonner?
A couple of bruises.
I need some coffee
quick!
- Sure, come in.
Two small lemonades.
You bought some in the shop!
But these are yellow.
Who's that?
A woman engineer from Prague.
She's on her way to Vienna.
To Vienna?
Open one for me!
How does Miluna know her?
Turn the radio off,
I can't hear.
Her name's Wendy.
Isn't she the image of her Dad?
You've knocked the breath out of me.
He's nothing much.
But she's got your beauty.
You always were special.
Good old Strakonice days.
Hubby left me the car
and some money.
But that's it.
The hell of a work!
Where can I find him?
Somewhere round the farm.
But probably in the office now.
Good morning.
- Goodbye.
Bye.
- I'll be back.
Hi.
- Look what I've done.
Pretty, isn't it?
- Show me!
Well, look.
But there should be a poem.
Beda and me,
we'll have:
Go with him
who loves you.
That's nice.
D'you know
what the idiot told me?
That he'd be run off his feet!
Maybe there's something in it,
look.
Who's that?
- I don't know.
Let me!
You wrote
that you'd parted!
That you'll take us home.
Bigmouth!
Yes, but...
- Well?
It didn't work out.
What?
She's so sensitive.
I see. Sensitive?
Whilst your child isn't.
You betrayed us once before.
- So I betrayed you?!
So I have betrayed? You say?
You married that rich old fart!
I wasn't good enough.
A mere farmer.
That's her, let's move!
This is stupid, here, like this...
- What taste you have now.
But I'd like to meet her.
You have got mad...
Hello, Miss Eva!
- Hello.
Good morning.
Give me a couple of days. - But
after than you will marry me, won't you?
Yes, I'll tell Eva myself.
With Evik... - Well,
and before you return from Vienna,
I will be free again, and so...
after that... - The poor girl.
On the 18th, then.
- Well, bye.
Do it by then
or else...
This village'll never have seen such
a scene!
'Bye.
That is a loss.
That's a face well slapped.
Again.
Who was she?
Don't go mad!
Confess!
Gaby.
I mean Mrs Feyfar.
Where d'you know her from?
Driving-school.
She taught me,
Venca and Miluna.
What is she to you?
Me? Nothing.
And what's this?
Well, what...
A friendly kiss.
It's normal for friends to kiss.
It may be normal elsewhere
but not here in Hostice.
How come she knew my name?
- By name?
She called me Miss Eva!
Even knew I'm still single.
I told her about you,
that we're going to marry.
And what's this?
- That's Wendy!
Mrs Feyfar just hands out
photos of her child?
Gaby...
I mean Mrs Feyfar!
...left it...
...for...
For whom?
For Venca Konopnik.
For him, but with you?!
He's getting married
so she couldn't very well...
She asked me
to give it to him and say
they think of him.
Well, that is all, or is there
anything else? What else?
Christ - poor Blazena!
Why's the light on?
I keep on about energy conservation...
Hi, Chief.
Where's everyone?
What's the matter now?
- Nothing.
"For Daddy from Wendy" - Who is that?
Imagine!
Venca Konopnik has a child with a woman
from Prague.
That's her, that's the kid.
She sure is some bird!
Beda, look!
She is a bird, she sure is...
She's a widow.
When she got pregnant
she married a rich old geezer
and he pegged out.
The kid is really Vencas's?
But not a word to anyone!
Girls, come quick!
Hey, hey, hey!
Wait for me!
I'll come last again.
I'll wait for you there!
Venca?
Nonsense, Mrs Kelisova.
May I go to West Germany
if I'm lying!
Eva said so,
showed me the photo.
With that peroxide hussy
who ran you down.
Poor Blazena.
Venca always was the village bull.
A typical Venca.
I keep saying that.
All this fornication!
This sinful man wants to enter
into marriage.
And there also...
Sodom and Gomorrah.
Do your duty, sisters!
Take your places, girls!
Did she tell you
who's the father?
I promised not to tell.
You can tell me, come on!
See, tell me. It is all the same.
- I cannot.
I tell you everything too.
Well, don't be silly.
But I really can't!
Beda just told me
the kid is Venca's.
No!
...lawfully wedded.
Now it's out, I suppose...
I knew my clown
wasn't up to it.
Miluna, be my guest.
Well, sorry!
That's OK.
Be glad.
- Poor Blazena.
You're right.
- My God, I cannot drink this!
I'm so happy!
What is it, auntie.
Gimme some chewing-gum,
I'll go.
What?
What child?
What are you gabbing about?
If I'm gabbing...
Come on!
With a driving-school instructor,
she lives in Prague now.
What?
Miluna can tell you more,
she's been talking to her.
I don't believe it.
Hello Marenka!
- Don't call me Marenka!
They received a double zero.
- Swallow it up, the double zero.
That rascal of yours had
better watch out!
The shame of it!
They'll be drawing blood today.
Damn you!
Mrs. Matousova! Again?!
Isn't it enough for you that
you have been shot down twice already?
A handful of shit again!
She'd have knocked me down.
BBC emergency, this.
Witches' gathering!
To hell!
Tell me! That child!
The truth or I'll bash you one!
Don't shout at me,
ask them that know.
You talked to
that hussy from Prague!
Mrs, Feyfar.
And so what?
What is up?
Whose is that child?
Why don't you ask
your future son-in-law.
Son-in-law...
She spoke to Beda too,
left a message for Venca.
This is their Wendy.
Dear God!
God in heaven!
She's the image of him.
Show me!
- Take a look!
Well, really, it is so.
Christ in heaven!
See you tonight.
Good morning.
What's wrong?
Tonight, then.
Ciao.
What's the crowd outside?
Where've you been?
- With Venca.
Do you know her?
Sure.
You know her!
Will someone tell me
what happened?
Ask your Mum!
What happened?
Ask dear Venca
what happened!
Let that bull of an ox tell you!
He's got a bastard with some slut!
What's a slut, Mum?
You idiot!
Nonsense!
I keep telling you!
Shame on you,
lying to your own mother!
She told Miluna.
Ask in the cooperative.
She came here by car
and looked for him.
She left him a message and photograph!
It could be you
as a child!
Look at her nose!
Leave me alone!
Little nose...
Dad, tell her she's daft.
He needn't tell me anything, me!
It's you
he should bash up!
I shan't outlive the same of it!
Was it not enough?
First with Miluna,
now this.
And now this.
It's just gossip,
I'll ask him.
Don't you dare go to him!
I would have to break your legs
if you went there again!
Let him come and own up!
- And why own up, tell me?!
I'm telling you,
I had nothing on with her!
I'll have it out with Beda and Miluna!
Where're you going!
- To Venca's!
Back, I tell you, Blazena!
Blazena!
- You're not going!
Noooo...
Over my dead body!
- Mummy...
Such goings-on.
And you offered to do
a church wedding...
Blaza, please,
it's just silly gossip!
So whose is the child?
- How would I know?!
His!
And there's proof!
You can't go by a photo,
and Venca swears!
- Swears, yeah...
You're staying in!
Don't make such a scene...
What scene?
- The whole village's watching!
Let them see
what's going on,
better than on television!
And that's that.
She's doing this on purpose,
a week before the wedding.
What's she doing on purpose?
I'm defending the family honour
against that... that...
I hate saying what!
Now just say it, say it!
Who knows the whole truth.
Maybe you only needed my Venca
to save the girl's honour!
Shut up, will you?!
Of course!
Who knows,
the kid could be anyone's!
It stinks to high heaven,
all these men around!
What did you say?
I can smell blood, Father.
Help me up, girls!
'T would be small wonder!
That engineer you buttered up,
pushing the girl into his bed!
What?!
- Just ignore her, woman.
I'll kill her!
She'd say this about my girl?
I'm not scared of you!
Smell my fist!
Hold me back! Where are you?
Or I'll make her mug uglier still!
Look at her getting an attack!
Isn't she a crazy Marianne?
I bet I hit on it, it's true!
Lovely!
Hold me, girls!
Leave her alone,
or you'll be ill.
Let me go!
- Calm down,
your heart'll act up!
I can't stand this!
Ever ready, Father.
Let me go!
Don't let her provoke you!
Bloody filth.
Mum!
Let him marry
his Prague slut!
Venca's no catch for you, Blazena.
Blaza!
Don't demean yourself, son!
You'll be paying alimony anyway!
No alimony!
Who knows who's the father!
Mummy, please!
That widow from Prague's better!
A nice car, bags of money...
We'll build an extension at last!
If you build an extension,
we'll add a whole floor!
And we'll tile the front!
And find a better match
for Blazena!
You won't become Mrs Konopnik!
You gave me a fright.
How did all this come about?!
What? What do you mean?
You mean... her?
We had coffee...
What did she say?
What she said...
She said to be in Prague now.
And that her man died, or so.
That she earns good money...
And the child?
Wendy's her name?
I'd never have thought
you and she...
Do not start the same, you...
It's like a put-up job!
Excuse me, but...
Excuse me.
If I had her here I'd...
She's gone to Vienna
for 10 days.
- Ten days...
So you and she
really didn't...?
She laid just anyone.
You know her, don't you
- Do not tell me...
But I didn't...!
I'd rather hide somewhere!
So it could've been anyone's
and she throws it at you.
But what will you do now?
Blazena won't have you,
and you will surely not marry her,
will you.
You'd be a fool to.
So what now...?
Leave me alone!
You're as bad as the priest's old hags!
I should've known
it's your kid!
What would she want me for?
Just look at me!
Who'd marry me except some...
Some what?
A crazy short-sighted farmhand.
Crazy, short-sighted.
Telling you's like using a loudspeaker.
A good gossip's your scene,
instead of cooking a hot meal.
I made hamburgers yesterday!
That's all you ever make!
It is healthy.
- Yes, that's true.
Why get married anyway?
I am asking myself.
I don't need anything.
You monster.
Of course...
I can't look Venca
in the eyes now.
I told you not to tell -
but off you go, a - trumpeting.
My reputation now!
Imagine yourself in Blazena's shoes.
I'd drown, poison and hang myself.
Better and better...
You'd get rid if me.
You see...
You won't tell Eva,
will you?
There's nothing to tell. - What do you
mean there is nothing to tell?
D'you mean to say Gaby told you
Venca's the kid's a father?
Who else, surely not you?
Surely not you?
That would be the hell of a choice...
Yeah, she told me too
that it was Venca s.
You see.
Any problems?
No.
Turn the light off!
Go to sleep.
He'll marry the woman from Prague!
To spite them!
Well, well...
Your Blazena can take a running jump!
I can't sleep.
What a nuissance!
I'll take another pill.
It's so late
and Christ alive, the shame of it.
Shame across the village!
Stop snoring,
I'm thinking!
What am I supposed to do at night?
Do some thinking with me!
- I am thinking.
So I hear!
We'd do best to move away.
The shame of it!
Everybody knows, so what.
Such a pretty little girl.
And the boy says nothing,
fool as he is.
And her mother's elegant.
I like the looks of her.
Better than Blazena...
I'll have it out with her.
Me push my girl
into somebody's bed?!
How can you fool - such a shame!
Ph... shame!
Our Blazena is going to make
a good match.
I shall to that.
You'll go green with envy!
You three-coloured engineer... and...
And that's that.
I can't fall asleep.
My home, sweet home...
Send out telegrams:
"Wedding postponed because of illness".
Why go into details.
Hallo, mummy, we are here.
Now then, careful...
Here's the list of addresses.
Okay, okay... - And the money, do you
have it? Mind you're back by lunch -
no loitering about!
- Okay, okay...
Now your feet, Mum.
Our neighbours have stopped existing.
Don't you dare look that way!
We'll never talk to them again!
Jirka II see to you.
Just hold him tight. That s it. Jirka!
No, I'm going with Dad!
- No!
Help me with Gran!
I'll turn her round to make sure.
Slowly!
- Down, quickly!
Turn... Feet forwards!
You're as stupid as your Dad...
Slowly, you rascal!
Me again?!
Some summer holiday!
Don't kick Gran
or I'll land you such a slap!
She's peeping out, that old cow.
- What a bitch!
Here are the addresses
and remember: You write -
"The wedding is off,
the mother-in-law's gone mad."
Yes, all right.
Such talk...
Gone mad I will!
Stuff it down your throat.
You may need it
for that lady engineer.
We need no trash from you!
And write what you want
into the telegrams!
Such a beautiful pram!
But she will destroy it like this!
I'd rather sit in the dark.
Jesus...
Piss off with your china.
- Jezismarja!
The dirty bastards!
Turn me round!
Come here!
You're a s heavy as a tank.
Old junk as presents!
It hardly work!
She's going to break it!
Watch it yourself!
We have not asked you for that!
And that's it!
Daddy has given a bribe to
the head of the electrical shop.
We're buying a colour set anyway!
I'd rather throw it to the pigs!
No! That's ours!
- Mine!
Ours!
Pull yourselves together, girls!
What is, Father?
Think of the unborn child
and sin no more!
There is nothing to do here
your dignity.
As the mother I refuse
to give my only son
to such people - look at her!
What if she starts beating him?
Your only son can piss off.
The bastard s off with any skirt!
Why should our Blazena
marry such a whore-monger, Father?
What language, dear God...
I heard nothing.
Do not make hasty decisions.
Let the young people talk it out
and make their decision.
There's nothing to decide.
The wedding's off!
No, the wedding's on!
He's not the only man around.
I shan t let the girl suffer in shame.
I'll see she makes a good match!
This can't go on.
This is too much!
This!
How would I explain
when I'm called to make accounts?
It must be clarified!
And now!
Venca!
I want a word with you!
Help!
God alive, what is it?
What are you doing? Be careful!
Switch me off, for God's sake!
Take me down!
A miracle, Father!
You're alight!
Cecily!
Somebody...! Take me down!
Miracle!
All right?
Hold on, carefully...
Are you all right?
Thank you, what a fright...
You wanted something?
Make it up with Blazena.
The unborn babe does not deserve
for you to scorn it.
I don't.
Just leave it to us!
Hold on to me!
Carefully now!
- Ouch!
I'll make a poultice...
Let's make it...
Halloooo!
Hand me that!
Come here!
Gimme, you little bastard!
Gran!
D you know this?
Something stupid again?
A game, see.
Put it down - and jerk it back.
You have a try.
Put it down, jerk it back.
That'll be fun!
And now watch me!
That's mine, you little bastard!
Give it to me, you rascal! My God
they take everything,
the shitty bastards!
I want to show you!
Watch... take a stone
and wrap it into a banknote
wind the thread round it
and throw...
Then lie in wait
for who falls for it!
I'll lie in wait!
I'm off with the boys,
you just lie in wait!
Take a stone...
wrap it up
twist and twist...
Don't cry, it's only gossip.
Here you are.
The things I have to listen to!
Venca didn't come,
didn't say a thing.
Give it to me!
I will...
Maybe your folks didn't let him.
It'll work out all right.
Venca isn't such a...
Sure he is!
Everyone's saying that kid
on the photo's like him!
I don't want him!
I'm so unhappy.
- Well, take it easy...
Scram, Joseph!
I must talk to her.
You stay here, Pepa!
No, he can scram, the traitor!
It really is just gossip,
cross my heart or hope to die!
I don't believe a word!
When I find out who caused this
I'll kill him on the spot!
Even if I get a life sentence.
Go away!
I do not even want to see you again!
Why re you screaming?
You heard, Venca, didn't you?!
Was that meant for me?
- Of course.
The bastard!
You're quite a man.
You stop howling! Or I will give you
more to have a reason!
Come and have coffee, Joe -
come for a talk this afternoon.
And I wanted to ask you...
Where's my car!
That bed's always in the way.
What...?
What a fun!
Stupid tricks,
at your age, shame on you!
He fell for it!
Just imagine, her mother
has another suitor
lined up!
Ouch!
- Higher up!
Whom?
Fat Joseph.
Fat... yea, yea, yea. Yea?
What a scandal!
Now gargle, Father.
You can't keep squeaking like this.
I'm here!
Come in!
Come in, don't be shy!
The house is Blazena s.
And she also has a garden.
90 thousand in the bank,
all hers...
Lumbago, that hurts!
I know that to do!
Mummy, hurry!
Come and have a look!
What is?
- Quickly!
Come and see this!
What on earth?
It look s like they're...
But the other way round...?
I don't know this one...
She won't want me,
I'm too fat.
- Fat? Where?
Do not worry, Pepi!
Just leave it to me.
How about a drink?
I don't believe it!
The girls said so.
- My goodness!
Look at that!
You're going to marry Joseph!
- I'd rather be an unwed mother.
I wouldn't outlive the shame!
I do not want people pointing at us...
What do you want? Joseph...
Such a decent man,
doesn't sit at the pub,
he's got his own flat,
car and video -
what more do you want?
That's not everything...
You shut up!
Your brain's bloated with beer!
What did you say?!
- Just the truth!
He's so fat!
- Of course he is fat,
but nice.
Who'll have you, pregnant?
So he's stout,
you get fat types on TV too!
And why? Because they are prosperous.
But I...
I don't love him! - She says
she does not love him any more!
You'll marry him, that's that!
I can't even eat in peace!
We have the wedding as planned.
In the morning you made me
call it all off and now...
And ignore that bastard next door!
His mother brags
about their wonderful bride.
Let them have as many as they want!
You'll get married too.
But decently!
Not another word!
I want a drink!
Or I'll peg out!
We are here
to reveal sin,
fight and erase sin.
What?
- We've got to erase it.
Because it is written:
Let not the weeds impure
seize the well-kept field
lest it suffocate the useful plants.
Cecily, pour out the grog,
I'll put a tape on.
The Song of Bernadette.
Stop smacking you lips!
Stop hitting me!
Smack yours too!
But you do not have any, do you?
- You witch...
Fear me not, dear chld,
come to me!
Come closer.
It's me, you idiot,
down!
Here!
Blazena!
What was that?
I'm not snoring!
I'm not even asleep...
Open up, it's me!
Don't be so silly!
Silly, is she?!
Just you try coming again!
Tear him up, Pinda!
Sweet home...
Chief...!
Shall I recite a poem for you?
One day in the park
I found a coin, a mark.
Nobody could care less
it was East German, careless!
Shut up, you'll end up in jail...
And here they come!
So... check in...
"This isn't the barracks; the Co-op."
Just a moment.
Television!
Yes, speaking.
Czechoslovak Television.
And so what.
On the 18th.
It is Saturday comrade.
Saturday is a working-day for us anyway.
The harvest's on!
We'll be expecting you.
I'm Radl, the Chief.
Understand? OK.
Saturday morning then, early.
And come as soon as you can!
Bye bye, salute.
- On Friday...
So they will come on the eighteenth.
We'll be in the news?
- It's about the people
who most helped
our victory in the milk league
through the Simon method.
So they won't take office shots.
You can listen in,
Joseph II arrange the equipment.
You beast!
Do you happen to know, chairman
we sing that Walkyrie song, and how?!
In the year sixty six
when peace will be everywhere
and you will be an engineer
and we will be going out together
along the path to Protivin,
which is so short. - What are you doing?
See, I don't need any equipment.
The best collective?
That'll be something.
It's either the Skopek
or Konopnik woman!
How'll you decide?!
Heavens above!
LAST D AYS OF POMPE Y
No!
- Chairman!
It'll be a fiasco!
Which of em works better this week
will be on television!