even more crazy summer comedy (SUBTITLES ripped by RZ)
SUN, HAY
AND A SLAP
Story and Screenplay by
The Cast
Stage designer
Music by
Performed by:
Sound editor
Continuity
Production Manager
Cameramen
Directed by
Film authors thank
for cooperation to:
Made by
Hi.
- Ciao!
Good morning.
- Good morning... Hi... Good morning
Where´re you off to, Blazenka?
l want to show the girls...
Do show us too!
My wedding invitations,
my Mum said to deliver them.
Mm... Mm...
- That´s up-side-down.
Mm, Mm. Yea, yea....
l can´t see a thing,
l sat on my glasses.
When is it to be?
- Soon, the Saturday after next.
Sure,
it´s knocking on your belly-button!
Great fun, this.
Hello!
- Ciao.
May l?
Thanks.
All the best.
They smiled at each other,
did you see?
- But if looks could kill...
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You got one too?
Very nice, all gold.
Pity l can´t see.
How much did it cost?
l wouldn´t know.
No shot-gun wedding for me.
No, but she had two abortions,
the slut.
Don´t stare at me!
Now then be good, Mum!
Don´t keep making me mad!
For how long will l be held up here
like this?
Come on up at once!
- No!
The Doctor´ll get angry.
- No. lt does not matter...
Just let him get angry!
He´ll go away and that´s that!
Let him go, so what.
No one asked him.
He can take his own filthy medicine.
- Just try to pour it away...!
They´d do me in,
with such poisons!
Such horrible stuff!
She has poured it out... Of course!
This filthy, disgusting staff! My God...
You dare try that on me!
And you too with the filth!
The bastards all guzzle beer
and make me drink this!
l know why you go mad like this!
l bet the kids´ve brought you beer
and you´re drunk!
Drunk - from what?
You don´t give me food or drink -
more often than not.
Shame on you, Mum,
saying we don´t feed you!
- lt´s true!
Don´t pretend,
l´m an old woman
you need to get rid of me,
so you feed me on filth!
Come on, just,
just keep your mouth shut, mummy.
We give you the choice bits,
how can you say such things?!
Well, but it is true!
Like the soup today,
disgusting, gone off it was.
lt was sour-cream soup!
lt was supposed to be sour!
Say
what you want next time!
lt was horrible muck.
But you ate it all!
Can you hear this, doctor?
- You never give me schnitzel!
You´ve got no teeth to chew it with!
l haven´t, l haven´t... Well, l have.
My teeth are in the side-board drawer.
They´ve been there for 15 years!
So how would you chew?
Make some goulash, then.
You know it gives you diarrhoea!
She always shits her bed afterwards.
Please stop it! Not in front of this.
l know what´s behind it...
- And what?
Your old man´s the same.
Meaning what?
l know he isn´t worth a shit
but he´s my husband!
A drunkard, and so are you!
How dare you, me and drunk?
- Yea, yea, yea!
You´re the one who gets tipsy.
- You too.
Shame on you,
in front of the Doctor.
Dear God, l don´t deserve
such a daughter!
You´ve got what you made
so don´t complain!
Swallow this and shut up!
Why fight, l always win.
Just you dare spit it out!
She does it all the time.
l´m more of an animal-tamer
than loving daughter!
All this screaming,
the neighbours´ll think
we beat you!
They want to get rid of me...
l´d rather go to the old peoples home
than this here.
What do l have here? Real purgatory.
- Well, granny...
Now then, today l´ll give you
a better-tasting medicine!
You´ll be up on the wedding-day!
You and your shitty medicines!
l told you not to talk that way
and damm it all
you keep swearing!
Why don´t you feel ashamed?!
So old you could
to know better.
- l will not.
We do our best for you!
And what do you do?
lf l did not tidy your scarf up
you´d disappear in there!
She has finished her rampage.
l´ll have peace for minute.
the wedding-cakes,
Blaza´s made some already, Doctor.
Come along.
We´re so busy and this...
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Here´s the wedding-invitation,
all gold,
isn´t it lovely?!
lt cost a mint!
ls that supposed to be a ´´K´´?!
Leave me alone!
That´s a fine ´´K´´,
if you saw mine...
You´re educated, Doctor,
the chemist can read your handwriting,
but this?
He can´t even write the addresses!
Christ, Bavorov with a small ´´b´´ !
Put it down, you idiot.
All you´re good at is guzzling beer!
Where´s the beautiful bride?
She´s delivering the invitations.
This is the real stuff, from Moravia.
Well, doctor...
But Mrs Skopkova, l don´t drink.
This isn´t drink, Doctor.
This is medicine!
Just sniff!
You must drink Blazenka´s health!
You´ve had enough.
Here.
Don´t hesitate,
drink up!
Well then to Blazenka.
And bottoms up!
Ouch, it burns!
Now down the other leg!
Pity she´s out,
l brought her something.
How beautiful!
What a waste,
the garden´s full of flowers!
An orchid, look!
Blazena doesn´t deserve it.
Do not say that, Mrs. Skopkova.
lf l found such a girl,
l´d cherish her!
l know.
Where´re you off to now?
l´m working like an idiot,
- And why?
everyone´s down by the river...
lt won´t ...
- Hurry up!
lt won´t kill you.
Let´s go.
- Well.
lt won´t kill you.
Venca!
What´s up?!
The invitations!
Come and look at them!
Okay.
At ease, Joseph.
Great, aren´t they?
- Mmmm.
Such pretty turtle-doves!
They give me ideas.
Stop it, Joseph´s here.
He´ll turn round.
Stop it!
Look, he´s watching!
All right then...
Holy Elijah!
Crikey!
Away, impure thoughts.
Christ, what is it?
Apage, can you hear me?
Help!
Sodom and Gomorrah.
Christ´s foot forwards!
Let him leave me! Let him leave me!
But l suppose
they may, now.
Let´s go home.
Mother of God...
Dear old man, are you hurt?
An angel. A real angel!
Look where you´re going, old fool!
Look, it´s scratched.
Fuck it all!
Don´t ride bikes if you´re clumsy!
Be glad l didn´t flatten you out!
So - are you okay?
Okay.
Let me help you.
That´s all right, just mud.
Take it easy!
Very much.
l´ll show you!
Let´s go, girls!
l´ll drive you to the village.
lt´s only a few steps.
Come on, climb in.
Wait!
- Let´s go!
My brolly.
Virgin Mary, see this?
Your brolly and let´s go.
God will repay.
- Yeah.
And my basket.
My bicycle!
Well, isn´t he crazy...
Wasn´t that the priest?
- ln whose car?
Okay.
Let´s go girls.
What happened, Father?
You look a sight, Father!
lsn´t it horrible?
- Who was it?
A face like an angel
words tender and gentle
as she dusted my cassock
with a fragrant hand.
Some nightmare.
Mrs. Teacher!
Hello!
What are you doing here?
l knocked down some old geezer,
his bike scratched my car.
And such a lovely car!
Our old sinner Otto the priest.
ls he agonner?
A couple of bruises.
l need some coffee
quick!
- Sure, come in.
Two small lemonades.
You bought some in the shop!
But these are yellow.
Who´s that?
A woman engineer from Prague.
She´s on her way to Vienna.
To Vienna?
Open one for me!
How does Miluna know her?
Turn the radio off,
l can´t hear.
Her name´s Wendy.
lsn´t she the image of her Dad?
You´ve knocked the breath out of me.
He´s nothing much.
But she´s got your beauty.
You always were special.
Good old Strakonice days.
Hubby left me the car
and some money.
But that´s it.
The hell of a work!
Where can l find him?
Somewhere round the farm.
But probably in the office now.
Good morning.
- Goodbye.
Bye.
- l´ll be back.
Hi.
- Look what l´ve done.
Pretty, isn´t it?
- Show me!
Well, look.
But there should be a poem.
Beda and me,
we´ll have:
Go with him
who loves you.
That´s nice.
D´you know
what the idiot told me?
That he´d be run off his feet!
Maybe there´s something in it,
look.
Who´s that?
- l don´t know.
Let me!
You wrote
that you´d parted!
That you´ll take us home.
Bigmouth!
Yes, but ...
- Well?
lt didn´t work out.
What?
She´s so sensitive.
l see. Sensitive?
Whilst your child isn´t.
You betrayed us once before.
- So l betrayed you?!
So l have betrayed? You say?
You married that rich old fart!
l wasn´t good enough.
A mere farmer.
That´s her, let´s move!
This is stupid, here, like this...
- What taste you have now.
But l´d like to meet her.
You have got mad...
Hello, Miss Eva!
- Hello.
Good morning.
Give me a couple of days. - But
after than you will marry me, won´t you?
Yes, l´ll tell Eva myself.
With Evik... - Well,
and before you return from Vienna,
l will be free again, and so...
after that... - The poor girl.
On the 18th, then.
- Well, bye.
Do it by then
or else...
This village´ll never have seen such
a scene!
´Bye.
That is a loss.
That´s a face well slapped.
Again.
Who was she?
Don´t go mad!
Confess!
Gaby.
l mean Mrs Feyfar.
Where d´you know her from?
Driving-school.
She taught me,
Venca and Miluna.
What is she to you?
Me? Nothing.
And what´s this?
Well, what...
A friendly kiss.
lt´s normal for friends to kiss.
lt may be normal elsewhere
but not here in Hostice.
How come she knew my name?
- By name?
She called me Miss Eva!
Even knew l´m still single.
l told her about you,
that we´re going to marry.
And what´s this?
- That´s Wendy!
Mrs Feyfar just hands out
photos of her child?
Gaby ...
l mean Mrs Feyfar!
... left it ...
... for ...
For whom?
For Venca Konopnik.
For him, but with you?!
He´s getting married
so she couldn´t very well...
She asked me
to give it to him and say
they think of him.
Well, that is all, or is there
anything else? What else?
Christ - poor Blazena!
Why´s the light on?
l keep on about energy conservation...
Hi, Chief.
Where´s everyone?
What´s the matter now?
- Nothing.
´´For Daddy from Wendy´´ - Who is that?
lmagine!
Venca Konopnik has a child with a woman
from Prague.
That´s her, that´s the kid.
She sure is some bird!
Beda, look!
She is a bird, she sure is...
She´s a widow.
When she got pregnant
she married a rich old geezer
and he pegged out.
The kid is really Vencas´s?
But not a word to anyone!
Girls, come quick!
Hey, hey, hey!
Wait for me!
l´ll come last again.
l´ll wait for you there!
Venca?
Nonsense, Mrs Kelisova.
May l go to West Germany
if l´m lying!
Eva said so,
showed me the photo.
With that peroxide hussy
who ran you down.
Poor Blazena.
Venca always was the village bull.
A typical Venca.
l keep saying that.
All this fornication!
This sinful man wants to enter
into marriage.
And there also...
Sodom and Gomorrah.
Do your duty, sisters!
Take your places, girls!
Did she tell you
who´s the father?
l promised not to tell.
You can tell me, come on!
See, tell me. lt is all the same.
- l cannot.
l tell you everything too.
Well, don´t be silly.
But l really can´t!
Beda just told me
the kid is Venca´s.
No!
... lawfully wedded.
Now it´s out, l suppose...
l knew my clown
wasn´t up to it.
Miluna, be my guest.
Well, sorry!
That´s OK.
Be glad.
- Poor Blazena.
You´re right.
- My God, l cannot drink this!
l´m so happy!
What is it, auntie.
Gimme some chewing-gum,
l´ll go.
What?
What child?
What are you gabbing about?
lf l´m gabbing...
Come on!
With a driving-school instructor,
she lives in Prague now.
What?
Miluna can tell you more,
she´s been talking to her.
l don´t believe it.
Hello Marenka!
- Don´t call me Marenka!
They received a double zero.
- Swallow it up, the double zero.
That rascal of yours had
better watch out!
The shame of it!
They´ll be drawing blood today.
Damn you!
Mrs. Matousova! Again?!
lsn´t it enough for you that
you have been shot down twice already?
A handful of shit again!
She´d have knocked me down.
BBC emergency, this.
Witches´ gathering!
To hell!
Tell me! That child!
The truth or l´ll bash you one!
Don´t shout at me,
ask them that know.
You talked to
that hussy from Prague!
Mrs, Feyfar.
And so what?
What is up?
Whose is that child?
Why don´t you ask
your future son-in-law.
Son-in-law...
She spoke to Beda too,
left a message for Venca.
This is their Wendy.
Dear God!
God in heaven!
She´s the image of him.
Show me!
- Take a look!
Well, really, it is so.
Christ in heaven!
See you tonight.
Good morning.
What´s wrong?
Tonight, then.
Ciao.
What´s the crowd outside?
Where´ve you been?
- With Venca.
Do you know her?
Sure.
You know her!
Will someone tell me
what happened?
Ask your Mum!
What happened?
Ask dear Venca
what happened!
Let that bull of an ox tell you!
He´s got a bastard with some slut!
What´s a slut, Mum?
You idiot!
Nonsense!
l keep telling you!
Shame on you,
lying to your own mother!
She told Miluna.
Ask in the cooperative.
She came here by car
and looked for him.
She left him a message and photograph!
lt could be you
as a child!
Look at her nose!
Leave me alone!
Little nose...
Dad, tell her she´s daft.
He needn´t tell me anything, me!
lt´s you
he should bash up!
l shan´t outlive the same of it!
Was it not enough?
First with Miluna,
now this.
And now this.
lt´s just gossip,
l´ll ask him.
Don´t you dare go to him!
l would have to break your legs
if you went there again!
Let him come and own up!
- And why own up, tell me?!
l´m telling you,
l had nothing on with her!
l´ll have it out with Beda and Miluna!
Where´re you going!
- To Venca´s!
Back, l tell you, Blazena!
Blazena!
- You´re not going!
Noooo...
Over my dead body!
- Mummy...
Such goings-on.
And you offered to do
a church wedding...
Blaza, please,
it´s just silly gossip!
So whose is the child?
- How would l know?!
His!
And there´s proof!
You can´t go by a photo,
and Venca swears!
- Swears, yeah...
You´re staying in!
Don´t make such a scene...
What scene?...
- The whole village´s watching!
Let them see
what´s going on,
better than on television!
And that´s that.
She´s doing this on purpose,
a week before the wedding.
What´s she doing on purpose?
l´m defending the family honour
against that ... that ...
l hate saying what!
Now just say it, say it!
Who knows the whole truth.
Maybe you only needed my Venca
to save the girl´s honour!
Shut up, will you?!
Of course!
Who knows,
the kid could be anyone´s!
lt stinks to high heaven,
all these men around!
What did you say?
l can smell blood, Father.
Help me up, girls!
´t would be small wonder!
That engineer you buttered up,
pushing the girl into his bed!
What?!
- Just ignore her, woman.
l´ll kill her!
She´d say this about my girl?
l´m not scared of you!
Smell my fist!
Hold me back! Where are you?
Or l´ll make her mug uglier still!
Look at her getting an attack!
lsn´t she a crazy Marianne?
l bet l hit on it, it´s true!
Lovely!
Hold me, girls!
Leave her alone,
or you´ll be ill.
Let me go!
- Calm down,
your heart´ll act up!
l can´t stand this!
Ever ready, Father.
Let me go!
Don´t let her provoke you!
Bloody filth.
Mum!
Let him marry
his Prague slut!
Venca´s no catch for you, Blazena.
Blaza!
Don´t demean yourself, son!
You´ll be paying alimony anyway!
No alimony!
Who knows who´s the father!
Mummy, please!
That widow from Prague´s better!
A nice car, bags of money...
We´ll build an extension at last!
lf you build an extension,
we´ll add a whole floor!
And we´ll tile the front!
And find a better match
for Blazena!
You won´t become Mrs Konopnik!
You gave me a fright.
How did all this come about?!
What? What do you mean?
You mean ... her?
We had coffee...
What did she say?
What she said...
She said to be in Prague now.
And that her man died, or so.
That she earns good money...
And the child?
Wendy´s her name?
l´d never have thought
you and she...
Do not start the same, you...
lt´s like a put-up job!
Excuse me, but...
Excuse me.
lf l had her here l´d...
She´s gone to Vienna
for 10 days.
- Ten days...
So you and she
really didn´t...?
She laid just anyone.
You know her, don´t you
- Do not tell me...
But l didn´t...!
l´d rather hide somewhere!
So it could´ve been anyone´s
and she throws it at you.
But what will you do now?
Blazena won´t have you,
and you will surely not marry her,
will you.
You´d be a fool to.
So what now...?
Leave me alone!
You´re as bad as the priest´s old hags!
l should´ve known
it´s your kid!
What would she want me for?
Just look at me!
Who´d marry me except some...
Some what?
A crazy short-sighted farmhand.
Crazy, short-sighted.
Telling you´s like using a loudspeaker.
A good gossip´s your scene,
instead of cooking a hot meal.
l made hamburgers yesterday!
That´s all you ever make!
lt is healthy.
- Yes, that´s true.
Why get married anyway?
l am asking myself.
l don´t need anything.
You monster.
Of course...
l can´t look Venca
in the eyes now.
l told you not to tell -
but off you go, a - trumpeting.
My reputation now!
lmagine yourself in Blazena´s shoes.
l´d drown, poison and hang myself.
Better and better...
You´d get rid if me.
You see...
You won´t tell Eva,
will you?
There´s nothing to tell. - What do you
mean there is nothing to tell?
D´you mean to say Gaby told you
Venca´s the kid´s a father?
Who else, surely not you?
Surely not you?
That would be the hell of a choice...
Yeah, she told me too
that it was Venca s.
You see.
Any problems?
No.
Turn the light off!
Go to sleep.
He´ll marry the woman from Prague!
To spite them!
Well, well...
Your Blazena can take a running jump!
l can´t sleep.
What a nuissance!
l´ll take another pill.
lt´s so late
and Christ alive, the shame of it.
Shame across the village!
Stop snoring,
l´m thinking!
What am l supposed to do at night?
Do some thinking with me!
- l am thinking.
So l hear!
We´d do best to move away.
The shame of it!
Everybody knows, so what.
Such a pretty little girl.
And the boy says nothing,
fool as he is.
And her mother´s elegant.
l like the looks of her.
Better than Blazena...
l´ll have it out with her.
Me push my girl
into somebody´s bed?!
How can you fool - such a shame!
Ph ... shame!
Our Blazena is going to make
a good match.
l shall to that.
You´ll go green with envy!
You three-coloured engineer... and ...
And that´s that.
l can´t fall asleep.
My home, sweet home...
Send out telegrams:
´´Wedding postponed because of illness´´.
Why go into details.
Hallo, mummy, we are here.
Now then, careful ...
Here´s the list of addresses.
Okay, okay... - And the money, do you
have it? Mind you´re back by lunch -
no loitering about!
- Okay, okay...
Now your feet, Mum.
Our neighbours have stopped existing.
Don´t you dare look that way!
We´ll never talk to them again!
Jirka ll see to you.
Just hold him tight. That s it. Jirka!
No, l´m going with Dad!
- No!
Help me with Gran!
l´ll turn her round to make sure.
Slowly!
- Down, quickly!
Turn ... Feet forwards!
You´re as stupid as your Dad...
Slowly, you rascal!
Me again?!
Some summer holiday!
Don´t kick Gran
or l´ll land you such a slap!
She´s peeping out, that old cow.
- What a bitch!
Here are the addresses
and remember: you write -
´´The wedding is off,
the mother-in-law´s gone mad.´´
Yes, all right.
Such talk...
Gone mad l will!
Stuff it down your throat.
You may need it
for that lady engineer.
We need no trash from you!
And write what you want
into the telegrams!
Such a beautiful pram!
But she will destroy it like this!
l´d rather sit in the dark.
Jesus...
Piss off with your china.
- Jezismarja!
The dirty bastards!
Turn me round!
Come here!
You´re a s heavy as a tank.
Old junk as presents!
lt hardly work!
She´s going to break it!
Watch it yourself!
We have not asked you for that!
And that´s it!
Daddy has given a bribe to
the head of the electrical shop.
We´re buying a colour set anyway!
l´d rather throw it to the pigs!
No! That´s ours!
- Mine!
Ours!
Pull yourselves together, girls!
What is, Father?
Think of the unborn child
and sin no more!
There is nothing to do here
your dignity.
As the mother l refuse
to give my only son
to such people - look at her!
What if she starts beating him?
Your only son can piss off.
The bastard s off with any skirt!
Why should our Blazena
marry such a whore-monger, Father?
What language, dear God...
l heard nothing.
Do not make hasty decisions.
Let the young people talk it out
and make their decision.
There´s nothing to decide.
The wedding´s off!
No, the wedding´s on!
He´s not the only man around.
l shan t let the girl suffer in shame.
l´ll see she makes a good match!
This can´t go on.
This is too much!
This!
How would l explain
when l´m called to make accounts?
lt must be clarified!
And now!
Venca!
l want a word with you!
Help!
God alive, what is it?
What are you doing? Be careful!
Switch me off, for God´s sake!
Take me down!
A miracle, Father!
You´re alight!
Cecily!
Somebody ...! Take me down!
Miracle!
All right?
Hold on, carefully ...
Are you all right?
Thank you, what a fright...
You wanted something?
Make it up with Blazena.
The unborn babe does not deserve
for you to scorn it.
l don´t.
Just leave it to us!
Hold on to me!
Carefully now!
- Ouch!
l´ll make a poultice...
Let´s make it ...
Halloooo!
Hand me that!
Come here!
Gimme, you little bastard!
Gran!
D you know this?
Something stupid again?
A game, see.
Put it down - and jerk it back.
You have a try.
Put it down, jerk it back.
That´ll be fun!
And now watch me!
That´s mine, you little bastard!
Give it to me, you rascal! My God
they take everything,
the shitty bastards!
l want to show you!
Watch...take a stone
and wrap it into a banknote
wind the thread round it
and throw ...
Then lie in wait
for who falls for it!
l´ll lie in wait!
l´m off with the boys,
you just lie in wait!
Take a stone ...
wrap it up
twist and twist ...
Don´t cry, it´s only gossip.
Here you are.
The things l have to listen to!
Venca didn´t come,
didn´t say a thing.
Give it to me!
l will ...
Maybe your folks didn´t let him.
lt´ll work out all right.
Venca isn´t such a ...
Sure he is!
Everyone´s saying that kid
on the photo´s like him!
l don´t want him!
l´m so unhappy.
- Well, take it easy...
Scram, Joseph!
l must talk to her.
You stay here, Pepa!
No, he can scram, the traitor!
lt really is just gossip,
cross my heart or hope to die!
l don´t believe a word!
When l find out who caused this
l´ll kill him on the spot!
Even if l get a life sentence.
Go away!
l do not even want to see you again!
Why re you screaming?
You heard, Venca, didn´t you?!
Was that meant for me?
- Of course.
The bastard!
You´re quite a man.
You stop howling! Or l will give you
more to have a reason!
Come and have coffee, Joe -
come for a talk this afternoon.
And l wanted to ask you ...
Where´s my car!
That bed´s always in the way.
What ...?
What a fun!
Stupid tricks,
at your age, shame on you!
He fell for it!
Just imagine, her mother
has another suitor
lined up!
Ouch!
- Higher up!
Whom?
Fat Joseph.
Fat... yea, yea, yea. Yea?
What a scandal!
Now gargle, Father.
You can´t keep squeaking like this.
l´m here!
Come in!
Come in, don´t be shy!
The house is Blazena s.
And she also has a garden.
90 thousand in the bank,
all hers...
Lumbago, that hurts!
l know that to do!
Mummy, hurry!
Come and have a look!
What is?
- Quickly!
Come and see this!
What on earth?
lt look s like they´re ...
But the other way round ...?
l don´t know this one ...
She won´t want me,
l´m too fat.
- Fat? Where?
Do not worry, Pepi!
Just leave it to me.
How about a drink?
l don´t believe it!
The girls said so.
- My goodness!
Look at that!
You´re going to marry Joseph!
- l´d rather be an unwed mother.
l wouldn´t outlive the shame!
l do not want people pointing at us...
What do you want? Joseph...
Such a decent man,
doesn´t sit at the pub,
he´s got his own flat,
car and video -
what more do you want?
That´s not everything...
You shut up!
Your brain´s bloated with beer!
What did you say?!
- Just the truth!
He´s so fat!
- Of course he is fat,
but nice.
Who´ll have you, pregnant?
So he´s stout,
you get fat types on TV too!
And why? Because they are prosperous.
But l ...
l don´t love him! - She says
she does not love him any more!
You´ll marry him, that´s that!
l can´t even eat in peace!
We have the wedding as planned.
ln the morning you made me
call it all off and now...
And ignore that bastard next door!
His mother brags
about their wonderful bride.
Let them have as many as they want!
You´ll get married too.
But decently!
Not another word!
l want a drink!
Or l´ll peg out!
We are here
to reveal sin,
fight and erase sin.
What?
- We´ve got to erase it.
Because it is written:
Let not the weeds impure
seize the well-kept field
lest it suffocate the useful plants.
Cecily, pour out the grog,
l´ll put a tape on.
The Song of Bernadette.
Stop smacking you lips!
Stop hitting me!
Smack yours too!
But you do not have any, do you?
- You witch...
Fear me not, dear child,
come to me!
Come closer,
lt´s me, you idiot,
down!
Here!
Blazena!
What was that?
l´m not snoring!
l´m not even asleep...
Open up, it´s me!
Don´t be so silly!
Silly, is she?!
Just you try coming again!
Tear him up, Pinda!
Sweet home ...
Chief ...!
Shall l recite a poem for you?
One day in the park
l found a coin, a mark.
Nobody could care less
it was East German, careless!
Shut up, you´ll end up in jail...
And here they come!
So ... check in...
´´This isn´t the barracks; the Co-op.´´
Just a moment.
Television!
Yes, speaking.
Czechoslovak Television.
And so what.
On the 18th.
lt is Saturday comrade.
Saturday is a working-day for us anyway.
The harvest´s on!
We´ll be expecting you.
l´m Radl, the Chief.
Understand? OK.
Saturday morning then, early.
And come as soon as you can!
Bye bye, salute.
- On Friday...
So they will come on the eighteenth.
We´ll be in the news?
- lt´s about the people
who most helped
our victory in the milk league
through the Simon method.
So they won´t take office shots.
You can listen in,
Joseph ll arrange the equipment.
You beast!
Do you happen to know, chairman
we sing that Walkyrie song, and how?!
ln the year sixty six
when peace will be everywhere
and you will be an engineer
and we will be going out together
along the path to Protivin,
which is so short. - What are you doing?
See, l don´t need any equipment.
The best collective?
That´ll be something.
lt´s either the Skopek
or Konopnik woman!
How´ll you decide?!
Heavens above!
LAST DAYS OF POMPEY
No!
- Chairman!
lt´ll be a fiasco!
Which of em works better this week
will be on television!
What do you mean work better?
When they hear,
they´ll jerk off the cows udders!
Television.
Just what we needed...
You two will see
to decorations.
Some banners, greenery ...
... Flowers
- flowers...and
... decorative paper
- and all that stuff.
Sweep the yard properly,
for once!
- Okay... Certainly...
Dear Newsreel ...
This is not possible...
What´s the matter with you women?
An average of hardly 4 litres!
l don´t believe it!
- Just look...
Come here, girl!
ls it playing?
lt is.
- Here too.
So what´s wrong?
And they?
Normal,
even above normal.
- This is strange, this...
We shan t be on TV this way!
We´ll see to it!
- Women, for God´s sake...
Why don´t they milk the cows?
What does that mean?
l´m playing, as usual.
And what are you playing to them,
Joseph? Your tapes -
Heavy Metal, Folk ...
A bit of opera ...
- And what do you play for them?
The same stuff.
Let´s go! Let´s go!
Let´s go, girls!
So whose fault is it?
Come on, girls!
Well, well...
- l´m leaving
But comrades, girls, remember...
l refuse to be insulted!
l´m ignoring you.
Just see to your cows.
l do nothing but!
l bet she cast a spell on them!
She´s staring like a bull, the witch!
What?!
- Where´s your common sense?!
What would the TV people think?!
Seeing you rioting like this!
Or the district council people!
l do not mind what they think, chairman.
l am not greedy, as some...
l don´t care about showing off,
like some.
But l won´t have her insult me!
Who is insulting you?!
You´re such a sight,
they wouldn´t put you on TV anyway!
You know...!
Enough that you will be there!
They can take a shot of you all
for a real socialist family -
he ever drunk,
the girl a baggage of shame...
God, this about my girl?!
And who got her that way?!
l´ll show her what for!
Enough!
Silence!
Back to work, damn you!
Back to your position!
- Come on, girls!
You think he´s up to some trick?
He´s hand in glove with them.
Skopkova!
Come on!
Good evening.
- Good evening.
But the music was on?
- This is it.
We couldn´t prove anything.
By the time they tore in,
l´d switched it back!
No.
The cows who like brass bands
l gave opera,
- l see.
the symphony buffs got rock!
Serves her right.
Watch her on television,
l´d throw the set out the window!
Help yourself.
And Blazena?
- What? Blaza?
She can´t want me, l´m fat.
You´re a man!
Want you or not. Come!
Blazena?
Are you there?
Open up at once!
Quick!
She is not allowed to go out.
lt´s me, Joseph!
Quick!
You dare lock yourself in?!
Don´t do it again.
Hi.
- Hi.
Come on, children...
Here you are.
- Well, thanks.
You can´t go through the window...
My Lord!
- What is up?
You´re like an excavator!
See that?
Come and have a look!
She locked them in together!
She´s certainly determined!
Forget her, dear,
marry Gaby, she´s educated,
well-travelled ...
... has a car and pots of money...
You fool.
Don´t cry! l´m not mad at you.
l still love him, l´m stupid.
Not really.
You´re great, but l ...
l know.
What´ll you tell my Mum?
That l´m too fat for you!
Skopkova!
Forget her, then.
l wouldn´t mind your having a child.
l haven´t got a child.
l never had an affair with Feyfar!
l know that, you´re my tiger.
l didn´t mean her.
The third pump broken.
What a confusion!
Now l can´t stick my face out at all.
Stop it, you are all shame, confusion...
l told you he´s too fat for her!
Where´ll l find somebody else?!
She´ll find her own man
when she wants one.
Somebody like him again!
l´m off.
Ciao.
That´s him all over...
And l have to do the thinking
and if l did not take care of them
they´d just rot in filth.
They don´t care.
l´m coming.
So how long will l have to wait here?!
Must you make me mad every time?
Climb out immediately!
l know you are there!
l´m too busy for this.
What´s this - stones?
That is too much, mummy!
What do you need stones in bed for?
You´ve got your cars,
your Boyo magazines ...
l´ll give you a spanking, Mum!
l´ll cal the Doctor
to give you a shot!
The Doctor!
Doctor! Just doctor.
My fairy queen ... my fairy queen ...
Come with me, come with me...
Eva dear, l must make a call.
lf you want the Doctor,
he´s at old Ma Potuznice s.
All that way?
l´ll have to run. Ciao.
- Bye.
Come in, Doctor!
Good morning.
- Hello, Jirka.
What´s this?
He throws darts at her!
Good Lord, doctor, look.
if it hit her eye
she´d be blind till her dying day!
Children have to play.
One cannot leave them alone for a minute
they immediately become mad.
But l will settle accounts with you.
Mind my word.
l´ll beat you up when the Doctor´s gone
he´d say it´s unhealthy.
Come in, Doctor!
Do not take off your shoes!
Make yourself at home...
l´m telling you straight out.
You know the situation.
lf you want her, she´s yours.
The wedding can be next Saturday.
- l do not want to believe it...
Why can´t you believe it?
- When l tell you it is true.
lt would be too wonderful for me.
Wonderful?
lt´s only Blazena...
So - cheers!
You must call me by my fist name now -
l´m Marena, you´re Karel, right?
Have another.
But l don´t drink!
But this is to Blaza,
and your great happiness.
Doctor, Karl, to Marenka
to Blaza, to happiness.
Could she possibly love me?
She has to!
You have always been her secret wish.
Such a silly girl and a Doctor!
So enjoy it, these are wedding cakes...
Have one!
Am l not too old for her?
Old? You?
You are the best age!
Mature - and handsome!
- Please stop it...
Truly.
lntelligent, handsome...
That damned bastard!
But l will settle accounts with him!
Folks!
Father!
Such deep wounds!
This´ll be my death.
Sodom and Gomorra.
The third suitor this week!
Can´t keep up with the latest!
This looks like a message
about groom status in the Czech Lands...
lt cost me my blood...
That´s true, Father.
lt cost her a glass-full.
l´ll show you
The Torture of St Sebastian.
He suffered even more.
Sit down, Kelisova.
No thanks, l´ll stand.
A martyr.
My life is Christ´s,
You made your choice!
You´ll enjoy this.
He was so young and handsome.
l cry every time.
No, l cannot,
Courage! Obey your master!
Shoot!
l entrust my soul to you, oh Lord,
Ouch!
Mend, mend...
Don´t be scared, l´m with you.
- l do not know, my dear...
Locked herself in again.
l´ll beat it out of her!
Up you go, Karel.
Do you think, Marus?
- Of course,
be a man!
l´ll climb up, then.
- C´mon!
Don´t be so naughty, Mum!
Well, well, doctor!
Come and get it!
She´s spying on us again.
Up you go, Doctor dear!
lt´s me, Karel!
l don´t suppose she´s there.
Try again, properly.
l probably love you, dear.
l´ll probably marry you.
Open up or l´m coming in!
Are you okay?
Come on up!
Just come here, Kaja, are you alive?
l seem to be alive...
l will rescue you, do not be afraid!
Wait a moment, l will help you!
Let me help you.
What´s up?
l don´t feel like going home.
ln trouble?
l am always in trouble,
you take it easy.
What is?
Mum´s after another man for Blazena.
She´s trying the Doctor?
He fell off the ladder to her loft.
lsn´t she there with them?
- She´s sulking.
l´ll tell you where,
for a cigarette.
Tell me, then.
Matches.
You´ll shit your trousers.
Up in the loft, where else.
Mind you don´t say
l told you!
Sure. Thanks!
Switch it off, you ass!
Come and see!
She´s been at the Doctor
even shoved him off the ladder!
Let us have a smoke.
No thanks, l tried when l was a girl,
and the result was horrible.
Do not tell me...
- All right, it´s a special day...
Well, well.
Marus...
You´ll shit your knickers!
Marus, now, what´s the matter
with you...
lf they catch the Doctor
you´ll marry the lady engineer!
Done.
Leave me alone!
Leave me alone...
Nononononononono ...
But l´d rather you didn´t.
Lady engineer - ha!
Come help me!
Light, moonlight, starlight ...
Leave me alone!
He´s our boy!
Must l drive him home?
Not happy about it, l tell you!
Shut up and go,
and don´t say l´m tipsy!
Shine, moon, shine ...
l am shining, l am starlight.
Where´s he got the keys?
- Have a look!
Want me to search him?! - Just
have a look, shut up and look for them!
Hold him up!
- l am!
Stupid, this!
Getting him drunk...
He did his own drinking.
He could´ve spent the night
on the kitchen sofa.
Can´t find them?
Watch me, then!
Hold him up!
Karel Kroupa M.D. and Blazena Skopkova
announce their wedding on ...
Drive slowly
so he doesn´t vomit.
Just wait and see, Blazena,
when you come down!
Damn...
l mean ...
They got him drunk and raped him!
This is what the family is like!
Don´t tell me, Vlasta!
l saw it with my own eyes!
That is not possible.
- Yes it is possible.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
l wish everyone well,
but...
Can you keep a secret?
Will you do me a favour?
For you - anything.
A big secret...
What disgusting is going on?
Ladies!
That´s for the Chief to say.
Good morning.
- Morning.
What is it now?
- l´d like to ask the TV people
to the wedding.
A real South-Bohemian wedding!
They could make a shock.
Shot. - Well, l say,
like the news headlines ...
... for the ´´topical events´´ program!
Super, l adore weddings!
l really do, Dear!
Me too.
- Am l right, Beda?
Well...
Will they be done by eleven?
There is nothing more to do
in the cowshed.
They´ll soon be done, the cows,
us and that´s it!
And who´s marrying Blazena?
Don´t you know?
The Doctor!
- Mr. Kroupa...
Kaja...
Dr Kroupa?
What a match for her...
Fantastic!
lt´s back in fashion now!
But what is rising over me...
There is sunrise in the window,
and Julie is the sun.
Rise, smart sun, and beat the moon
he is already pale with envy anyway,
that you are more beautiful,
as his servant.
When he is so envious, do not serve him.
Shit, there´s a spot here,
but it´s nylon,
it´ll wash out.
Why didn´t you marry?
He was married, two kids,
and the bastard hated opera.
So what shall l do with him?
Slip into the shoes!
They´re lovely!
Do they fit?
Fine!
l wish it were over with.
Mum´ll get a heart attack...
No she won´t,
leave that to me.
l´ll lend her
my Romeo and Juliet.
Here it is, look.
That´s too thick for her.
She´ll murder us in the first act...
l´m ever so pleased!
l always loved a bit of intrigue.
Don´t worry, l am in it with you now.
We´ll show those pig-heads
and act out some Shakespeare!
Better not.
Kroupa...
you can hardly tell.
l´m to copy that 57 times?!
Shut up and write!
You deserve worse punishment
for your darts!
And you stop snuffling
like a wild boar!
Leave me alone at last!
You´ve cut out my beer,
now my breathing - what a life...!
You can breathe all you want.
Just don´t snuffle!
Leave me alone and write your stuff!
Don´t dig that pen in so!
l heard!
- Come on!
We´re inviting half the county.
lmpossible. So many addresses...
The postage it´ll cost!
The price of 3 crates of beer.
That´s all you think of,
instead of your daughter´s future.
Well, yes...
Of course!
What do you see in drink?
lf l tell you,
you´ll drink too!
We´ve got to move now
we caught the Doctor
before he backs out like Pepa.
You´d hound up someone else.
Hounded´em up? Next you´ll be saying
l hounded you up too!
What are you writing there?
There´s a double ´´d´´ in wedding!
l see...
Think of the spelling a little.
Remember your spelling lessons
at school!
l wonder
what they teach children at school today...
l´m thirsty,
l want a drink!
Here l come, Mum!
l am rushing! l am here...
Here is your tea.
Look at Gran -
one´s made to learn things
only to forget´em again.
Did your Mum slap you around too?
No. Only yours does.
You´ll write to that engineer lady.
Can you hear me?
- l do.
Or l´ll do it myself, you twit!
ls Blazena around?
- ln the cowshed.
Blazena! Blazena!
What´s up?
l am going downtown for the decorations.
Well, chairman said to take her with me.
Why doesn´t Eva go?
- Evicka has always done this.
Their computer´s in the shits,
she cant´s.
Mind you´re back soon!
Good afternoon to you.
Travelling, are you?
To my aunt´s in Bavorov -
with the laundry.
This way to Bavorov?!
Fat Joseph is giving me a lift.
So l´m waiting ...
l see.
- ... and talking bullshit...
Joseph?
What´s he doing there?
Chasing the gals.
Here he is!
You´d better step back.
Hello, Father!
Mushrooming?
There are no mushrooms here.
Would you like a lift?
No! God forbid!
l´ve got that tape for you.
The Temptations of St Anthony?
Send Cecily over for it!
The sisters will be pleased.
May God repay you!
Bavorov, indeed...
Come!
Sodom and Gomorrah!
Time enough for this!
Let´s get dressed, quickly!
Take your clothes off!
Sodom and Gomorrah - my word!
You get undressed too!
What are you waiting for?!
Stop your silly nonsense!
Horrors...
True and faithful love
overcome all
barriers
you have promised each other
you love will last
for ever
always faithful
always true
eternal love
for you...
Virgin Mary, do you see this?
... and l proclaim you man and wife.
Please exchange rings.
Now your first kiss newlyweds.
l owe you a favour now, thanks!
Ciao.
That´s all right -
but watch it!
You see, l nearly forgot...
- Good luck!
20 kilos of flour,
rice, eggs -
steaks are in the´ fridge ...
God... The liver!
Please get the rest from the car.
Gherkins...
Hi.
- Hi.
Why were you in Bavorov so long?
The wedding´s day after tomorrow
and you´re off instead of helping!
Well, we must go out...
for...
l want to tell you something.
- And let us prepare the garlic...
l´m not marrying the Doctor.
What?
Say that again!
Hold me back, Fanny!
Marus!
l can´t really.
Forget it, you must!
You´re going to marry him
if l pull you there
by your hair!
Don´t piss me off, Blazena!
We´ve spent thousands,
sent out invitations 3 times -
yes - no -
yes - no...
l wangle such a match for you
and you say you won´t marry him...
l swear
you will!
As you like,
l meant well.
She meant well?
Open this!
Here we are!
l´m going to be so embarrassed!
You always say that...
Who gave you this watch?
l bought it from the Vietnamese.
lt is a diving watch.
Oh yes, of course...
Here we go!
How about some coffee?
Me...
- Here too, here.
Stop it, you animal!
lt´s the overture...
l´ve never seen a porno film.
That l don´t believe you.
What my eyes have seen today -
rimmed them red with tears.
l begged St Anthony
for the strength of silence.
But it is a real test.
l beg you
to be ready
by day and by night -
the hour of punishment
is high, am l right, Matouskova...
Amen.
Let us imbibe strength
from the suffering of the saints.
Dear sisters...
lt is going to be
an unforgettable experience.
Dear God,,,
Heavens,,,
What is it?
- Suffering.
My dear Lord,,,
God,,,
Give me strength
to overcome temptation ,,,
What did you put on, Joseph?!
- Great, isn´t it!
Well, that lS great...
Nothing but praying saints...
No boobs at all...
Try taking me out again...
lt´s not my fault!
- ls it?
l was expecting hard-core porno!
And now this!...
- Saints?
The shit´s hit the fan!
God oh God,,,
l´ve come!
What did she say?
What is that?!
They´re naked!
Shut up, sisters!
This is a horror, Father!
Get me some glasses,
l want to see!
Good Lord!
Do something, Father!
Sodom and Gomorrah!
And in our house!
Cecily!
Well, l do not know ...
No kicks today for us!
For you!
- No boobs for you, either!
Dammit,
which idiot did this?!
Where´s the torch?
ln the dresser drawer.
Where are you?
l´m scared.
l´m here,
and don´t bother me!
Dammit all,
where´s the torch?
Do l know? l am not using it!
- Light a candle, then!
Okay, but where is that?
- l do not know
Aren´t they beautiful?
What wedding-night!
Any complaints, Madam?
Plenty...
What´s wrong?
l´m getting pricked.
Really?
- Everywhere...
Absolutely everywhere?
- Absolutely...
... your will be done on Earth
as it is in Heaven. ...
This is no good either...
... Give us
our daily bread ...
... l can´t bash the thing...
... Lead us not into temptation...
Get off,
you swine!
Stop it right away
or you will see!
Scram, you bastard!
She´s losing her voice!
Father!
What is up?
- D´you hear?
She´s losing her voice!
Today of all days!
The hour of punishment is close.
Priest, priest...
- Come, Cecily!
... l am alone in my own estate...
- No, l don´t drink.
But Cecily will.
One drink...
Well then only.
- And one more...
Dear God...
Will you have one? Here.
What a pity.
- You cannot escape. So come on.
He slipped him this filthy thing...
Do not tell me... Pepa?
Saw it with my own eyes!
They were quite naked!
Why aren´t you dressed yet?
You should be ready now!
Surely you don´t want a drink?!
Well, let her be...
- Why should?!
She´s a bit tearful, so what?
- And l am a bit hard!
Goodness...
When l was getting married ...
Stop it!
- What is Liddy doing there?
Heavens above!
- Stop it! Stop it!
Out of the way!
We have visitors!
How nice to see you.
Welcome.
Hello, mother dear!
How are you?
How well you look!
God! You see...
l don´t believe it!
- Marenka!
Annie my lovely...
l´m so glad to see you!
Where´s Rose?
- They went by train.
Come on in.
Hostice!
We´re not stopping, we´re late!
You will get off in Volyne.
Stop, we´re attending a wedding!
lf you´re good at jumping off
l´ll slow her down.
Okay.
- What? l´m to jump?!
Jump!
Hurry, we´re late!
Rùza, do not be afraid, you must follow
the direction... Jump, l will catch you!
Great... Are you OK?
Whose wedding?
Go to the devil!
All this running about...
Give them my best wishes!
My, you´re taking your time... Jump!
You could be free, like...
We should have told them.
There´s no talking to them.
... like fish in the stream...
Mother´s going to kill me...
Get along with you...
Some loss of face
might do those pig-heads some good.
That poor Doctor -
no more ear-drops from him.
Come right in.
Mother,
what have you done now...
Just come in.
Comrade engineer...
- Mrs. Skopkova...
What an honour for us!
And your son?
- ln the army now.
l see, he is serving ...
- ... serving his country.
May l introduce my wife...
My new wife.
My pleasure, madam.
but you shouldn´t have...
Well...
- Take it, Dad!
To your health... Have some.
Do come in!
Yes, thank you.
Son!
- Marenka...!
My son! My son!
This is my Mum.
- Good morning, madam. Come in.
We came by train...
- So stop crying!
Rùza!
- My Vlastik... lsn´t he handsome?
Yes, he is. Go wash yourself!
What´s this?
This surely....was enough...
- l´ll slap your face for you!
Take it and go!
- They´ve arrived! -Who?
Television! ln the cowshed!
- No!? - Yes!
The Chief´ll stand here ...
Like this? Mister...
Are you mad?
Nonsense,
the other way!
Like a stupid cow!
Get ready, friends...
Come on! Let´s start! Camera!
Ouch!
You´ll break her leg, idiot!
You idiot!
Camera!
- Three hundred and seventy ...
How they managed these flasks ...
... tasks ...
hell, again!
These tasks were taken in hand
and we came to Hostice to see.
You won the State Milk Prize.
You even did better than Slusovice!
Wherein lies your success?
Well, come on...
We gave an opportunity to the young,
to those who work instead of gabbing!
The famous Planicka method is yours?
Me not ... Well, yes ... l ...
l typed it out for him.
l was correcting mistakes
in spelling.
Are you the famous Planicka?
l´m his father, he´s in the army.
- How moving!
What do you say, as his father?
lt is the merit
of the whole collective...
What´s this idiotic thing here?!
What do the cowshed nurses think?
Ouch!
Three hundred and seventy three.
And what comrades cowgirls
think about it?
Mrs Konopnik and Mrs Skopkova.
What made your village famous?
l think ...
- l think... lt´s because
we give
our cows headphones
we give them all sorts of music
and then milk them.
They give milk
the biggest yield in the country.
We got a ...
And then ...
And they made
a film here -
´´Sun, hay, strawberries´´
lt was on in the cinema...
And back to the method...
Could other co-operatives use
your method?
Yes,
it´s significant
for the Reconstruction ...
... the animal reconstruction ...
How ... well ... that ...
Did l say anything wrong?
No ... l ... l would like to say that
here reconstruction is so fast
that we are better off today
than tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow.
Yesterday.
You said that yesterday, Chief!
That´s enough, thank you.
Cut to the cows with earphones.
But you mustn´t go!
We were looking forward so much...
The bride...
Come and join us, see a South-Bohemian
wedding - the real thing!
Cakes, girls!
The great day has arrived.
Unforgettable moments -
join us too, dear television viewers!
How many have you had?!
Let´s go, let´s go!
Why don´t we walk over?
l want to show them we can afford it!
Smile!
Come and get into the cars!
Thank you, doctor, thank you.
Stand up so they can see you!
But Marenka, leave her alone.
Such an expensive dress
and she´d plonk herself down...
New shot!
- Three hundred and seventy six!
The wedding procession has arrived
at the local mansion
and the wedding-hall.
Bridesmaids here!
Good morning. Good morning.
- Let´s move,
we´ll be on television...
l´ll give you a slap,
television´s shooting this!
Come on out!
We´re on television...
l´ll see to it.
Doctor, television wants you here...
Don´t look that way!
l´ll sock you one!
Television is shooting this,
comb your hair who´s got a comb!
Line up both sides...
Quickly!
Comb your hair... Smile...
And watch TV in the evening...
Come here! Where are you running?
From here!
Get ready!
Smile or l´ll slap face!
Three hundred and seventy seven!
Action!
Dammit all!
What´s the matter with you?
Pardon me! Sorry... A little bit...
What´s that?
You broke your promise!
- Pardon me?!
Eva, right?
Hello.
Did Beda tell you we´re getting married?
Eva!...
- That must be a mistake, mustn´t it?!
- No mistake.
Beda´ll tell you himself.
What´s going on here?!
Excuse me, just one minute.
What? A minute?
Save me, somebody!
Let us save him, dear viewers!
People...
Well?
- Well, Beda...
l was willing to marry you
but l won´t let you make a fool of me.
Never!
- What are you talking about?
That Wendy isn´t my child,
but Venca´s!
You said so, to Miluna!
Venca?
Nonsense!
l told Miluna Wendy´s yours!
That is not true!
Watch out, l do karate!
So you say something!
l hate you!
So Miluna said...
Did Gaby tell you Wendy was Venca´s?
What´s all this?
You made them believe it!
l just ... made no comment.
l´ll kill you, you bitch!
Don´t you touch him!
l´ll beat him up myself!
Evika, Evika, control yourself!
Out of the way, you scum!
And you piss off,
or l will break your jaw!
Dad, after her! After her!
Eva, control yourself!
- You forced me...
ln the name of the Town Hall -
for Christ´s sake, stop!
You pushed your bastard on me?!
Bastard?
Just say that again!
Calm down, children!
Cecilka, Cecilka...
Didn´t l say so, Father?
When she tried to sing this morning.
Wait. Mum, we´ll wait!
Yes, a real South-Bohemian...
You slut!
- Who is a slut for you?!
Venca, home!
The shame of it!
Leave me alone,
l´ve got nothing to do with it!
Stop it, you nasty idiot...!
lt´s your fault,
had you believed our Venca...
You shut up!
Hit her, Dad!
You kept on about the lady engineer!
lf only you had kept quiet!
We didn´t force her like you did -
both Joseph and the Doctor!
How dare you?
Leave him to me, Mum!
Silence!
You stand here!
You read this!
There´ll be no wedding, sorry.
The bride
is already married.
What?!
Yes, to Venca Konopnik.
Never! l´d rather kill you!
Blazena, go home!
Stop it, everyone!
What´ll the TV viewers thinks?!
Pepa, where are you? ... Be brave!
you´re the Chief!
Your mistake dear, it´s me...
The hour of punishment has arrived.
Courage, sisters!
Virgin Mary, look at that!
Blazenka, let´s go!
Excuse me, comrades!
Think l´m scared of you?!
What ... what you...
l´m sorry.
l´ll show you, sorry...
Headmaster, you look a sight!
Thank you, doctor...
Come,
l´ll show you my garden.
Why should not we rejoice,
why should not we rejoice
when we are healthy,
when we are healthy,,,
They´re fighting!
l said they´d beat each other up!