Subtitles ripped by Worst
For chrissake,
why am I making my life so difficult?
I've a good mind to pack it in!
A crazy summer comedy
SUN, HAY, STRAWBERRIES
Story and screenplay by
Starring (title strip)
Simon
Venca
Blazena
Miluna
The Kalis Woman
Mrs. Skopkova
Mr. Skopek
Granny
Jirka
Chairman
Bedrich, Chief of Animal Husbandry
Secretary
Evicka
Priest
Cecilka
Helenka, conductor
Zvonicek
Mr. Sobotka
Mrs. Sobotkova
Mrs. Hubickova, Headmistress
Eda, driver's mate
Jarousek, landlord
Josef
Chairman's wife
Planicka
Planicka's wife
With
Assistant director
Continuity
Assistants to Production Manager
Assistant Cameraman
Assistant Art Director
Costumes
Wardrobe Mistress
Properties
Production Team
Music by
Lyrics
Singers
Played by
Make-up Artist
Sound Recordist
Art Director
Film Editor
Production Manager
Director of Photography
Directed by
"Creative Youth",
Script Writers & Production Group No. 6,
under the supervising of
Script Editor
Produced at the Barrandov Film
Studios, Holder of the February Victory
Order and the Labour Order
The Barrandov Film Studios
Distribution copies made at
the Barrandov Film Laboratories,
Holder of the Contribution
to Construction Award
Lean over, lean over, quickly
to the left,
c'mon, quickly, quickly
so we don't overturn!
Lean over, keep balance, balance I say.
C'mon, chop, chop!
Okay fine,
we can go back to our places.
I?s your first time here, isn't it?
- Er... um... y... yes!
- I don't know you.
Don't worry,
we haven't overturned yet.
And I've been here since March!
- Excuse me, is this Hostice?
- Yes, but we're not stopping,
Don't get out, we're not stopping,
we're late, we'll keep on going!
We'll only get out in Volyne!
We're not stopping!
We're late!
Wha?s your business in Hostice?
Buying the mill?
- The mill?
Yes, this one over there.
Even the singer Charlie Gott wanted
to buy it, only i?s haunted.
Sure it is!
A big black dog and dead sexton.
There have already been
a load of people here after it.
We're not stopping, we're running late!
- I see, but...
- So jump out!
- But...!
- I'll slow down for you.
Or are scared?
- For chrissake, Helenka, stop it!
I must see a doctor, my leg's broken,
I just can't walk!
- Can't do! I mean, we really are late!
- To hell with you, half-wit!
I've a good mind to give up!
Wait, wait, take me along to Volyne!
I must see a doctor!
My leg's broken in two places
and I've bruised four ribs!
Don't worry, you'll get a tip!
- Careful!
- Tha?s not the way to jump!
Keep to the direction
the bus's going in! Tha?s it.
But she mus?ve fancied otherwise
she wouldn't have slowed down for you.
People here jump out at full speed,
but then they've got the hang of it.
Are you that Sobotka
who wants to see my mill?
Look at it, a beauty, eh?
I'm not asking much for it.
- But I've already bought a tent.
- So aren't you Sobotka from Prague?
Hells bells!
- But the conductor said,
it was haunted!
I mean the mill.
- Fiddlesticks!
I've lived here for three hundred years
and haven't seen a ghost yet!
St. John of Nepomuk,
St. Mary protect me!
Help!
Anything happened you? Good morning.
- Gee - wha?s this?
They let the air out of my bicycle tyre,
threw away the valves
and broke up my basket!
Young man, re-direct your steps
and hasten away from this place,
where sin lurks whichever way you turn!
While there is still time!
- But I've come to work here as
a part-timer. On the cooperative farm.
- What, a part-timer?
Oh Lord, so young and so courageous?
- Could you show me the way
to the village?
- This way - that way.
Follow me,
if you insist.
Cecily!
- Who did this to you, Father?
- Sodom and Gomorrah, Cecilka.
Go and invite the villagers
to the evening session.
God bless you, young man.
If there is anything
you need you know where to come.
This is a new part-timer on the farm.
Show him the way, Cecilka!
- C'mon!
Tha?s the way.
- Thank you.
- If there's anything,
just whistle and I'll fix it.
Good morning.
- Hi.
I... I'm... I'...
I've got here...
So you're a part-timer?
Right?
Experimental, end-of-term paper
on the milk yield of cows
dependent on the environment.
- I've been the chief
of animal husbandry for eight years
but I've never heard anything so daft!
- I've got it perfectly thought-out.
If you just let me test my method
in practise,
it will bring benefits not just
to your cooperative, but to everyone.
- Chairman, we can't afford
any experiments,
let alone where milk's concerned!
- We're expecting a delegation
from the Regional Council,
tha?s a big things, sonny!
- Two or three cows will do!
- You know something?
Go and settle down,
look around the village,
try some of our cherries and come here
tomorrow a sensible talk, how about it?
Evi!
- Yes!
Gee, who is he?
- He'll tell you all himself.
Look, go and put him up somewhere.
But, Evi, mind you're good to him!
- Where can I put him up if all
the beds've been taken
by those combined-harvester chaps!
- Evi, please!
- Really, Chairman.
Well, I'll... Okay then!
Blimey.
A pack of Clea, as usual?
- No.
Look, have the people who came here
on holiday last year arrived yet?
No and they're not likely to come.
Dad said he was in prison
and Mum wouldn't
have her alone here for love or money.
- Tell Mum then to taken in
our new young part-timer
for at least a few days,
Mr... Wha?s your?
- Planicka. Simon Planicka.
- Yes, Simon Planicka.
Go and tell her at least for a few days,
I'll fix it with Mum later.
C'mon, get going!
- See you. Thanks.
- See you! Bye!
- Evi, you little cunning vixen!
- Go home, Animal!
I'll give you an umbrella, Mother.
An umbrella and a baret!
Right.
And mind you don't take it off!
Like last time, there'd be a show-down,
see?
- Oh no! Leave me alone!
- You know me, don't you?
- Where're you off to, Molly?
- To Volyne, to have my hair done,
i?s like a haystack.
Hey, Dad, drive it out for me!
- Just me some peace, you're...
For Goïs sake!
- Hey, Vlasta,
want to come along?
- I'll do it myself,
why bother?
- But why, the boy'll give you
a lift there this afternoon, won't he?
I keep telling Blazena
to spruce it up at least in front,
but no way...
- Brm! Brm! Brm! Drink! Drink!
- Ad him - always the same!
Swilling down beer all the time!
But they do it on purpose,
when you need something
you have to beg for it like a beggar!
Leave me alone, will you!
- Why should I?
I told you not to drink the beer
as you'd drive me to Volyne!
And you - i?s like talking
to a brick wall!
- Tha?s normal - Dad - Mum.
- Good morning.
- Who is he?
- Simon, he's to stay with us,
he's a part-timer.
The chairman'll explain it to you later.
- Good morning.
- They wouldn't give us a loan
to repair the house, no they wouldn't,
and now they're turning it into a hotel!
But, Dad, you'll tell the chairman this,
you will. Blazena!
- Yes!
- He'll stay with us, for the moment.
Look, take him in, give him some clean
bed linen. And water the house plants!
- Sure!
- Yes, sure!
Thanks a lot!
- Yeah!
I wouldn't come in the car with her
for love or money.
Good idea of yours to say
Venca'll drive me.
- I'm surprised,
she's not finished up in a ditch yet!
You're terrible!
- Sure, I will!
So who is he?
- Why don't you ask him?
- Wha?s he after?
- Not me, clever!
- I'd have to kill him!
The moment he lays a finger on you!
- Ah come on...
My dear little murderer!
Jealous are you?
- M'm.
Actually, he's quite all right,
you know?
- M'm?
- Hey, wha?s got into you?
- I'll fix him anyway!
Make love to me, Nicolas,
make love to me.
Come.
I want you to be the first.
Someone young, handsome, fresh,
tender, try to be tender!
- Love!
My love!
- Hey, stop snoring, ïyou hear me?
All right, stop snoring for chrissake!
- I'm deep in thought.
- When you're deep in thought,
the whole village can hear you!
Turn on your side at least!
- Nagging me all the time!
- Hi.
Where's Simon, is he asleep?
- Come off it now, be quiet!
Warm up the noodles with ham!
- Why are you yelling again?
- Because...
- He's quite nice, isn't he?
- Yeah, he went with Jirka
to pick some cherries.
Wha?re you doing to the electricity,
I'd like to know!
- Nothing, there's a power cut!
- Now, when the going was...
Hm, well...
- But i?s a repeat.
- Look, Blazena, fetch a candle!
But I haven't seen it and you -
stop snoring!
What a mess, do something,
ïyou hear me?
- What is it again?
- Wha?s up with you the whole time?
Look at the meter,
maybe i?s the fuses!
- I can't find it!
- They'll turn it on again.
The whole village's like this.
- Gee, I'm scared!
- The whole village's like what?
She's starting again,
go and talk to her, will you?
- Why should I?
If you hadn't given her beer...
- Is she your Mum? Yes, she is!
- It is my mum...
I told you not to give her beer
when she's sitting in the sun!
As you've given her beer
while she was out in the sun,
you go on listening to her.
Wha?ve I got to do with it?
Just listen to her.
- Don't drip that candle on me!
- What are you on about?
Well, Mum, Mum, don't be afraid!
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Mum, I'm not a ghost,
I'm your daughter!
Don't be afraid!
I'll give her an electric torch.
Where's the torch, I wonder?
- Want some noodles?
- Yeah.
To think there's just one candle
in the whole house!
I?ll be a hot day,
Cecilka, a hot, day!
The headmaster's girl's tuning up
her soprano.
Mum...
- Wait a minute, I'll...
- Mum, but, Mum, don't, i?ll do you
good to get some fresh air.
There we are!
Le?s have the feet!
- Just to get rid of me, nothing more...
- C'mon, Mum, le?s lie down like this.
Fetch her some newspaper
to while away her time.
- You always find something
to while away my time!
You'd leave an old woman to drop dead!
I know, I know!
Good morning, Mrs Skopkova.
- Hells bells, bloody hell,
you gave me a fright!
- Sorry, I didn't want to!
- Tha?s all right!
- Hi, Simon!
- Hi!
- Wha?ll you have?
Tea or milk?
- Oh no, thank you, don't go
into any expense for me,
I'll get something from
the General Store!
- No way, people'd gossip
that we weren't hospitable.
As for expenses, leave them up
to the chairman.
I'll see to it he foots the bill!
C'mon, le?s go!
There're streaks all over the place,
blast it! I?s going to look a sight!
- There's not enough time to whitewash
it. You bet there isn't, chairman!
- When did you start, I'd like to know?
Going like this, you won't be ready
before New Year's Eve!
- You know something, chairman?
Let those folks do it
who've pinched the spraying gun
and messed up the whitewash!
Look, I can easily pack it in,
no problem!
I?s easy to criticize,
anyone can do it!
- Wha?d you mean, criticize?
Nitwit!
Hi, chairman! Hi, Billy!
- Hi!
- Where did you get this this from?
This is oversized even for our Mum.
- So take it in then!
I?s a woman's job!
- Yes, i?s a woman's job!
- Ouch!
Hey, keep your hands off!
Private property!
- No, you can't, Josef!
We've paid you a hundred and eighty!
So make sure i?s finished!
- So take it and go
and get some wallpaper
and the Fragrance of the Forest spray!
- Oh, come off it now!
- Yeah.
The dung conveyor keeps breaking down
and as for the water mains, we've been
piddling with it for at least two years!
- Look, Chairman, we could dress up
as angels.
- Such baggies!
- Don't you bloody start!
- Don't we look like we belong
to the Red Cross?
- C'mon, girls,
we must do something about it!
- I'd finish it.
- But what about...
- Actually, i?s part of my paper -
quality of the environment and...
- Well, if you think so,
here you are.
Venca'll show you where to get
whitewash and other... things.
Venca, come here!
He's our plumber - a superb fellow!
He's able to fix a fridge, a car,
anything you can think of!
They've written twice about him
in the newspaper!
- Simon.
- M'm.
- This is Venca, see?
- Wenceslas.
Wenceslas for strangers!
- Sorry.
Hi.
Hey, Miluna, got some cigs?
Come off it, as if you didn't know.
A pack of Sparta!
- I don't know, honest,
I haven't looked.
- Have a look then.
- These are my old man's.
- He'll give them to you, Milikin.
- Milikin?
M'm.
- Look, I'm in a hurry,
they've put this millstone
of a new part-timer around my neck!
Are you listening?
Stop being clever!
- But there're some at home.
We can go and look.
- Yes, but...
- Scared, eh?
- Scared, yeah right.
- Scared of Blazena, I'd like to know!
- Come off it, me afraid of Blazena?!
- So that doesn't see you driving me to
my place.
- Pooh!
Why're you telling me all this crap?
- So you'll drive me to town this
afternoon, right?
- I told you I was on duty.
Next time.
- But you'd give a lift to Blazena
if she felt like it.
Never mind, I'll ask someone else.
- I see, Venca, sonny.
Broken down, eh?
- Well, something's wrong
with the engine...
- There you are, i?s right again.
So you'll give me a lift.
No way could I manage to carry such
a heavy weight!
- I'm off to the cow shed
and you haven't got a crash helmet.
- So what? I?s a just a little way off
and you're going that way anyway!
I wouldn't be able to carry it
and I've got a bad arm,
remember how I tripped once
and fell in front of the store?
And I had to carry it around
in a plaster cast all?
- Yes, but tha?s a long time ago.
- Yes, i?s a long time ago
but i?s a still not strong enough.
- Hi, I'll just drive Auntie
and the beer home...
- Oh no, I'll manage.
I had no idea you were waiting here
for Miluska.
- Stay where you are!
- Isn't that so?
- You said you were still not strong
enough. Hold tight!
- Thank you, Venca, sonny.
And sorry for troubling you.
- Tha?s all right.
- Miluska's a very nice girl.
And I thought
that you and Blazena...
Well, I must be confused.
- Yeah.
I guess so, Aunt.
- I guess so... just you wait! You stud!
Just you wait!
But really, sir, oh no,
seriously,
the invoice doesn't really belong to us!
- Humpty dumpty!
- Chairman, he's kissed me again!
Chair... sir, it is from somewhere else,
someone's jammed the line.
I'm sorry, Ev, but try to see
my position -
the harves?s the main worry and
I can't cope with everything on my own.
- So what?
As far as we are concerned,
the delegation is welcome
to come any time. Ain't I right, Ev?
- I've heard Josef's packed
the whitewashing in.
- As if you didn't know him!
The new one'll finish it off.
True, he's nuts...
Ev!
...but at least he won't do any harm
with a brush in his hand.
Look, Ev...
Look, secretary, we've seen worse.
- What did you say
was the name of the new chap?
- Simon.
Simon Planicka.
Just like the famous goalkeeper.
- I see!
I thought the name rang a bell!
- Noon!
Knocking off!
- Coming!
- Chairman, tell him to lay off!
Take him along, take him
to the cow shed!
She asked him
if he would give her a lift to town
and he said: No -
some other time.
But even then he was stripping her
with his eyes.
She was not wearing much
to strip anyway!
I'm sure they've patched it up again.
Now she'll be jumping into the sack
with them both.
Upon my soul, Father,
I've got a hang for such things.
- But Mrs. Kalis...
- You know me, don't you?
Hold it properly, or I'll box your ear!
- I'll puke!
- As long as you don't shit into your
pants!
- Rabbit again!
We have a rabbit every day,
even Spot doesn't want it anymore,
isn't it so, Spot?
Aren't you fed up witch rabbits, eh?
- Don't Spot me, or you'll see!
And pick it up, for chrissake!
Such a nice rabbit,
kids in Africa would be over the moon,
just you watch TV, they show it
all the time, how starved they are!
But you're so debauched nothing's good
enough for you.
- I'll hold it for you, Mrs Skopkova,
I don't mind.
- Let him, it won't do him any harm!
- I'll remember that, mate!
- No horsing around! Go home and do
your homework! And you-hold is properly!
Tell me, then, what are you,
wha?s your job, who are your parents?
- Does someone have a cow
in the village?
- A cow?
You're very kind, Father!
- Don't mention it.
- They all tell me i?s nonsense...
- Well, everything's is our Lorïs will,
son,
this is...
Daisy's at your disposal,
do what you think fit!
Cecilka, we're handing Daisy over
into the service of the scientific and
technological revolution!
- Le?s say, borrowing, Father!
- Don't worry.
Will you let me?
Miss Cecilka, please!
What she had, she's given.
I?s magic, this is magic!
- A miracle! Miracle!
A miracle's happened!
- A miracle, folks, where are you?
A miracle's happened, a miracle indeed!
Sandokan, Sandokan...
- He's a creep!
I didn't like him right from the start!
- What will people from the Council say?
Did it have to be the parson's cow?
- And which one, I wonder?
Nobody else's got a cow here
and didn't let him use
the cooperative cows! Poor chap!
- Never mind that!
He shoulïve asked our advice!
He'll pack up his things tomorrow
and go!
- No, i?s not his fault!
- Too bad, isn't it?
- Twenty-two liters from one cow!
- Gripe! Who knows what they're up to
and we'll fall for it, hook,
line and sinker!
As if we didn't know them.
- But maybe he didn't mean any harm,
this Planicek.
- Planicka.
Simon Planicka.
Twenty-two, single, student
and - contrary to some people -
a decent and good-Iooking fellow.
And he smells nice.
- Planicka i?s impossible!
He's the director of the regional
agricultural administration!
And he's got a son!
- D'you think he's been sent here as...
- I do.
Yes, as the vanguard!
- The vanguard of what?
- The regional delegation,
I'm telling you!
His father's sure a member of it!
- Well, as long as i?s him.
- Tha?s what we must find out
as soon as possible!
Discreetly, of course!
Not a word to anyone, is that clear?
- Pilatova!
- There!
I?s so hushed-up
that he could even be a spy!
Are you listening to me?
- Sure.
- Why should we keep a spy in the house...
free, I wonder?
You'll tell the chairman tomorrow.
I can't even drop off now.
I say such a skinny,
half-baked character,
but they are usually the worst!
Still water runs deep.
- C'mon then!
Molly, what did you feed
the rabbits with?
- What ïyou mean?
- Two of them are lying there
stretched out, bloated!
I keep telling you,
don't give them wet clover,
now they're lying there,
two of them bloated...
- D'you think I'm daft giving them
wet clover?
Bloated... Well, I feed them with grass
from the cooperative.
- Go and have a look then!
- Yes, and I gave them at lunchtime...
Listen, don't breathe at me,
you reek of beer and your feet stink!
Go and have a wash, you pig!
What a life!
I?s going to be bloody hot again,
blast it!
Oh no, you don't say so!
- I?s true,
otherwise I wouldn't be telling you,
if it were not true!
Don't you know it, his father's
a big fish in the Regional Council!
- You don't say so!
Only i?s not the Council,
Pilatova said it was the Ministry!
- For chrissake!
Only i?s not the Ministry, they say
he's at the top level... Well, you know!
I know, chairman, I know!
I'll hush up, I'll be quiet like
a tombstone, you know me! What?
Hey, engineer, sir!
- Blazena!
Blazena, everything's at stake now!
Bedrich'll tell you.
- Good morning.
- Stop pestering the engineer!
D'you think he's your playmate, or what?
- No engineer, Mrs. Skopkova,
i?s still far away!
- Never mind far away, he's an engineer
and tha?s a fact!
- What is it, Mum?
Want to go to the potty?
- You dump me...
- Dump me, tha?s right!
Look, fetch her a newspaper
to while away her time. Here you are!
- Not the Young Reader, she'll tear it
to pieces, like last time!
- Here you are, go on in!
Well, at last!
I've been waiting all this time!
I'm waiting here and I've nothing to do.
I don't want a newspaper,
I want the pictures.
- No, you're not getting them!
- I want the pictures,
I don't care for this!
For chrissake, i?s an old newspaper!
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You look smart today, Blazenka,
did you make it yourself?
- Well, I had a go at it,
I don't really know...
- What a lovely dress,
you look smashing in it!
They remade an old dress,
her mother used to wear this rag
to school in nineteen forty-six!
I?s not the music alone!
I?s a mere link,
which, applied in practise...
In short, a clean environment
or indifference
or a reckless attitude,
they are all interlinked!
- Sure, sure, i?s true! And from now
on you won't use the parson's cow!
You'll have a chance now to repeat
that experiment of yours!
- Unfortunately, a tape recorder's not
sufficient for my experiment.
I needs some appropriate equipment.
Some amplifiers!
- But look, amplifiers cost the earth,
but...
Hey, tha?s an idea,
what if the women sang something...
...a sort of choir, you know!
- For chrissake!
- What about it?
- Well...
Well.
- There you are -
le?s give it a try.
Fetch the headmistress Hubickova,
we'll get hold of some kids
and women in the village and we'll see,
won't we?
- As if we didn't have enough to do!
- C'mon!
- What an idea, chairman!
- Good, isn't it?
Watch the chairman, he's having you on!
You must find out from him
who he really is
and what he's actually after in Hostice!
Yeah?
But do it inconspicuously,
otherwise i?s a fuck... I mean botch-up!
- Well, what if I botch it up?
- If you botch it up, anyone will!
- I'll give it a try then.
- Tha?s a good girl!
You must do you damnedest, get it?
Give it your all!
I?s in the interest of the cooperative.
- Okay, then.
- I'll be damned if he doesn't fall
for such a dish!
He he...
Hi there!
What was that?
- You saw, didn't you?
- He was feeling you!
- You're kidding!
- Kidding - come off it!
I saw him feeling you, like this!
- Ouch, wha?re you doing?
Look at the bruise!
- What were you doing there?
- I?s a secret!
- I'm asking you
what you were doing there?
- You're a terrible, jealous nutter!
I'm really fed up with you!
- I'll bash his teeth in!
- My sweet little murderer!
- Jump on!
- Wha?re you up to?
- Jump on a keep quiet!
- Next time.
- Stop kidding and climb on!
- I really can't, it is in the interest
of the cooperative.
I can't tell you more!
- Not interested!
But listen:
If anything happens,
you'll both be in for it...
- You're a funny guy.
Okay, so just a quickie, right?
Leave me alone!
- We only have light ale.
- Shoe, give me my shoe, ïyou hear me?
Give it to me!
I?s my shoe, give it to me!
C'mon!
Leave me alone!
- Still at it, Miluna?
There are others available here.
- I?s something you don't understand.
- Yes, there are others around!
- Leave me alone!
- Others I'm telling you!
...our Willy's ploughing a field,
he's got spotty bullocks.
When he's done ploughing...
- Get going, beast!
...he'll call out to me,
he'll know me from afar.
When he's done ploughing,
...young Pioneers, smashing kids.
- Another one!
Keep on dancing, keep on dancing...
...smashing kids.
- The oven crashed down...
...i?s flying, i?s flying...
- Tra la la la, tra la la la...
I can't look at it such fooling around,
just like in our cow shed!
Some gave more milk,
but some gave less than usual.
Sure...
- They each respond to a different song!
- So that the average milk
yield dropped...
- By how much?
- By seven per cent, seven per cent.
- A song, I see.
- Don't be cross with me, please,
I... don't be cross, I...
- But tha?s all right, just carry on!
I?ll improve with time.
- Well, if we get a good tape-recorder
and amplifiers, then...
- And if that doesn't turn out right,
than we'll... Right?
- Right?
- There you are then.
Drink, drink, they'd let me perish!
I want a drink, drink, drink!
- Fetch her a drink!
Hey, where you are?
He's been back for ages and there's
no food in the house.
I'm going for a pint!
And you're to give him lunch,
Mum's orders.
- Sure, don't worry,
i?s part of my job description.
- Well, at last, someone's good enough
to appear!
You'd let me perish here!
- Cheers, Granny,
You're still the best off anyway!
We're going to toil, get it?
To toil - with these hands, get it?
- Bloody hell!
- You don't cheerio, then!
Drink then.
Can you leave it for a moment?
I've come for a little talk.
- Hm.
What about?
- About you, for example. You've stayed
with us for nearly five days
and I still don't know anything
about you.
- But there's nothing interesting.
- Maybe there is.
Where you come from and so on.
Hey, wha?s this, whose crazy idea
this is?
For chrissake, they will not leave me
in peace!
Are you having me on, or what?
- Look, I'm sorry, le?s talk
some other time. Yeah?
I must finish this.
...I think I'd rather leave!
- Pity!
I may not be in the mood next time.
What is it again?
Wonderful! Sure, a desirable match!
Daïs upstairs...
Who brinks his breakfast into his bed?
Mum.
- You're absolutely impossible.
- Well, suit yourself!
- Brm, brm, brm, brm...
- I'm coming with you!
- You haven't a crash helmet!
- Not interested!
- Where are they? Where are they?
Where are they?
Our aldermen...
Eh?
Blimey...
- Lady, shall I give you a push?
- I want to go there, there, there!
- Hurrah! Hurrah!
Hurrah!
- Annie's gone to fetch some cabbage...
- She must want to kill herself!
...fetch some cabbage...
- Hey, folks, come here!
Come and catch her! Come here, don't let
her kill herself! She's a wild one!
Look, she's driving like mad!
I can't catch her!
Hey, excuse me!
- Hello!
- Yes, i?s old Zvonicek.
But i?s haunted!
- Haunted?
- A big black dog and a dead sexton.
Jaro, you're rude!
- Le?s go back!
A dead sexton!
- But why, she's plastered,
can't you see it?
Haunted - today...
You're like a little kid.
Where can I find him?
Hey, where can I find this Mr Zvonecek?
- He says Zvonecek - tha?s good!
- C'mon, c'mon!
- I?s daft,
I've been saying that from the start!
Soon he'll lead the whole village by
the nose!
- But we have to look into it.
I?s no slapdash job.
- No wonder the beer's warm!
- What do you want me to do about it...
Can you see it, can you see it?
Can you see them?
- Hi!
Hi!
- I?s clear, eh?
- Sure.
The moment you leave the house for
a while - poor Granny,
What a shock!
- But why, she was laughing.
- Laughing, but what if a car
bumped into her
on the road?
Or if she'd crashed it?
Stop picking at it and eat up!
- I don't want anymore!
- Whadja mean, don't want anymore?!
You'll eat it even if you had to stay
up all night! Remember that!
And you too...
Dad, come!
Come to the table,
or i?ll be cold like a dog's nose!
The girl's the same -
never at home in time!
Such a tasty rabbit!
Simon's enjoyed it so
and he's used to other things!
But what about you -
have at least the foreleg!
- But I particularly don't like
the foreleg!
- Listen, you'll eat the foreleg in
a flash, get it?
Put the beer down.
Haven't you had enough?
For chrissake, take off your socks!
- Lay off me for once!
- The stink'd make one drop dead!
- Hm.
What did you give the rabbits again, eh?
- What could give them?
- Two of them are lying there,
all bloated!
I keep telling you, don't give them
wet clover, but you won't listen!
Two of them are lying there now,
all bloated...
- What ïyou think I give them?
I gave them cut grass
and they also got
cut grass at lunchtime!
- It mus?ve been damp then!
- Am I so daft or young
to be such a fool
as to give them damp grass?
Well, if they're bloated,
go and kill them.
So I can make at least minced meat.
I'll put some nettles in so i?s tasty!
- We had it last week,
we always have minced meat!
- You shut up and eat up, you've been
nibbling at it the whole evening!
But mark my words, you'll eat up,
have a wash and go to bed, get it?
- Eat up, c'mon, eat up!
- Go on eat it! For Chris?s sake,
go and do something about your feet,
the stink'd make one drop dead!
Have a wash and hurry up, will you!
- They're clean!
- So we are not the last!
- For chrissake, I'm thirsty.
Give me a drink!
- Jesus Christ!
...she didn't even know,
trnky, brnky, trnky, brnky,
what her little lacy skirt looked like.
Trnky, brnky, trnky, brnky,
...she didn't even know
what it look like,
what her little lacy skirt looked like.
She didn't know which
trnky, brnky, trnky, brnky,
Honza's got a black horse,
trnky, brnky, trnky, brnky.
She didn't know which
Honza's got a black horse.
Then she found out which,
trnky, brnky, trnky, brnky,
Honza's got a black horse.
Trnky, brnky, trnky, brnky.
Then she found out which
Honza's got a black horse.
- Perfect!
- I?s that big!
- Let me thank our ladies for this
musical piece
with which they opened our ladies'ball
and for this reason the next piece
will also belong to our ladies.
A Ladies'Request Dance!
- Tha?s the way!
- Wait, in the interest
of the cooperative tha?s your dancer.
- Wha?s up?
Well, he's sulking!
- Leave it out!
- Oh, right!
Yeah, just as I said,
she's an old...
- Come off it and put it all here!
- Look, but I'm not much good!
- Never mind,
the banïs good for nothing.
A disco in Malenice, tha?s
a different kettle of fish!
Gee, they're not half making
the place rock!
Oh, sorry!
- What did you say?
- Well, tha?s something!
- C'mon!
- Don't be silly, I can't!
- Come off it!
Sure.
Hi!
Look, look, she's dancing with this...
- This? Well I never!
He'll kick his teeth in!
Well, folks, you have to see it!
A well-preserved millstone,
eight big rooms...
Get off me for Goïs sake,
wait a minute!
Wait I'm telling you!
All right, wait!
- Dear me!
A beer!
Was there a fight?
Was there a fight? Was there a fight?
Le?s go, eh?
- May I ask you?
- What?
Is Miluna dancing with someone else?
Well I never,
why don't you throttle his oxygen
tubes a little, this wise guy!
- He's making a stooge of you!
Kornuto!
- I can't look at it.
- Well, you know -
a more desirable match!
- Just like women... You live across
the backyard, he's under the same roof.
- Say it once again!
- There's a fight, I told you so!
- Wha?s going on?
- There's a fire, folks, a fire, a fire!
A disaster Sosnovec's on fire!
Sosnovec's on fire!
- What, there's a fire in the forest?!
- Joe!
Joe, don't go!
- Please, don't go anywhere!
- Listen, Sosnovec's on fire!
Joe, don't you dare go there in this
suit, ïyou hear me?
Don't pretend you don't, I know
you can hear me!
- Miluna! Miluna! Come back!
You must take the money before they're
all gone!
- Sure. Time's up, we're closing,
there's a fire!
- A fire! A fire! A fire!
Dear me,
when the pig-sty caught fire
in fifty-nine,
that was hell!
- Those who're not helping won't get
a drink. The bill's 158.80!
- We're not going to help,
for we haven't set anything on fire.
We're going to have a look
at the mill!
- Sure, the mill!
I must be dreaming!
Surely not!
- The bloody Kalis woman!
- Little moon,
in the deep...
- Shut up,
the teacher's singing!
...skies,
- So the Kalis woman was sitting
in front of the pub...
- Don't be daft, come on.
- I know.
- I did pay for the beers!
- Shut up,
the teacher's singing!
...your light can reach afar.
You wander throughout
the wide world,
looking into people's
homes.
- Beautiful,
really beautiful!
- You wander throughout
the wide world,
looking
into people's
home.
Moon, stand still
a while,
tell me
where my
love is.
Moon, stand still
a while,
tell me
where my
love is.
- Nice, Miss, very nice!
- Thank you, thank you.
I'm so happy.
I?s the first time they're clapping
for me like this.
- Hey, folks,
i?s quite nice here, isn't it?
...there's velvety green grass,
just winding, just rolling,
my love accompanies me.
Just winding, just rolling...
- Why, ïyou want to go
through the wood, Mr. Zvonicek?
- I?s a short-cut,
we'll get there in no time!
- Where are you off to?
Blazena!
- Blazena, my foot,
when i?s dark like this!
- Maybe they've gone for a walk.
- Who?
Who's gone for a walk?
D'you hear what I'm telling you?
- You had too much!
- What did I have?
C'mon, who's gone for a walk?
- Come, c'mon!
- Let me have a glass of lemonade too,
right?
- You've had enough!
I'll take the money and we'll go!
She's made up her own mind,
so what?
- Wha?s this stuff I'm drinking,
this is...
- And so I got this idea that
if I divided the cows into sections
according to their response
to a particular song...
- I see.
- All it needs is a little time
and patience.
I'm sure the idea's right.
Got it?
- Have you got a girlfriend?
- Well, my father's also convinced
that i?s bunkum,
but I'll prove to him it isn't!
- Is your father interested too?
- No, tha?s the problem.
- What does he do?
Gee!
- Are you all right?
- I was worried that all you were
interested in was this school of yours.
You're so strange, mysterious, you know?
- What ïyou mean, mysterious?
- Give me a kiss.
Watch it, the boys!
- What would they be doing here
by the river?
- Maybe they dragged him into the wood,
eh?
- Hold it, I said!
- We'd need an electric torch.
- Torch, so that they could spot us?
Clever!
- They're not going to be there,
come this way.
- Crazy idea...
They're coming for you!
Blast it, damned old geezer,
to think he'll disappear, of all places!
- I'm telling you, he disappeared right
in front of my eyes,
just like The Invisible Man!
Rudi!
- The Invisible Man, my foot!
- I want to go back to Prague!
Back to Prague!
- Back to Prague, eh?
We must get out of here first!
- Rudi, promise not to buy the mill,
right?
Promise me!
- Wha?re you scared of all the time?
I can't go through life explaining to
you that ghosts do not exist!
- But they do, I know they do!
- Hey, get him!
- Rudi, come here.
Please, Rudi!
C'mon, come here!
Come here I tell you, come here!
Please, Rudi!
- Tha?s it - you see.
Le?s go home, c'mon.
There's going to be a downpour.
What about piling up the hay, Father?
- Do it, Cecilka, do it.
It looks like hail.
- Right.
You want to make a shit here,
you rascal, just you wait!
I know you're up to some mischief,
you rogue!
- Poor old father, so i?s twelve years
since he passed away!
It wouldn't do you any harm to go to
church once if...
...if I've paid for the service.
- Leave me alone!
- D'you have any idea how much we owe
father for?!
At least when i?s his anniversary...
And have breakfast, the scones
are in the cupboard, ïyou hear me?
- Sure.
- Christ, what a mess.
We'll roast you and we'll gobble you up.
You rascal!
You're off somewhere, you're off!
How many time have I told you, Mum,
not to take the cockerel with you
into the bed! There you are - now...
- Oh, oh, oh! Ah, this is...
- So i?s shit, so what?
As if I had nothing better to do then
the washing and cleaning! There!
...If you gave him proper grub...
- You've got into this funny habit
of taking everything with you
into the bed!
- Okay, so we'll gobble him up!
- Gobble him up, gobble him up...
Once i?s a cat, the other time
i?s a cockerel,
if i?s not a cockerel,
then i?s the dog!
A good thing we haven't got a cow!
The headmistress can't come singing.
If it rains, put away Granny. Listen,
don't let her get wet, ïyou hear me?
- Sure.
- Yes, sure!
Alena.
- Raining, raining, raining,
raining, raining!
And I'll tell on you that you've let me
get wet
and you'll get a licking!
- You what?
Where were you?
I was in the cow shed and...
- I'm off duty!
- Yes, you are, aren't you!
- You're a regular jealous buffoon,
if you want to know something!
I told you I had to fix something up in
the interest of the cooperative.
- Was it in the interest
of the cooperative
when you dragged him into the wood?
- Me dragging him?
What ïyou think I am?
- I saw you embracing him!
I couldn't have let him alone like...
- So you had to rally your chums, eh?
D'you think I'm your private property,
or what?
I'll tell you this:
I think you're a regular shit
and you don't reach even up
to his ankles!
- I see!
Just like that!
As long as I know where I stand, but
no one's going to make a stooge of me,
get it? Neither you, nor themselves!
Remember that!
Well?
Have you got something?
And did you look everywhere?
Carefully?
And what about yesterday?
Did he say anything?
- He kept talking about his thesis
and that he had a fight with his father
over it...
- What happened next?
- Nothing.
- So you used a wrong tack!
- You go and tackle him yourself
if you're so clever!
I'm fed up!
- What about us - ïyou think we're
enjoying ourselves?
So we'll pack it in and we'll lose our
image,
special bonus and all we'll have left
will be ridicule
from the rest of the district!
We can't let this happen.
- You know something?
Le?s help him
with this nonsense of his.
Simon!
- Go and give him a hand!
Let me, I'll hold it for you.
- Simon, come here!
If it fails now, they'll lock us all up.
Fiddlesticks.
- Crazy, horsing around with cows!
Stop nagging us.
- But I won't go inside, not me!
- But...
- I'm slaving like a dog...
C'mon, you're too slow.
Gee, no, not here!
Don't!
Mind the step.
We'll turn on the tape-recorder
and we'll talk...
Gee, there are some sausages at home
with pickled onions... C'mon!
- Well, sausage you say, you bitch?
Get up!
Don't be mad, Blazena,
I'm terribly in love with you.
If I manage all right, I'll stop at the
dentis?s.
Is this fit for driving to town
and for parking it there?
I keep telling you...
I always wash it, so you can give it
a wash for a change!
- Come on, what the hell... this...
You keep putting it into the barn,
there are the hens, but I won't let
this upset me!
- The hens're yours,
the rabbits are mine!
- If you didn't guzzle the beer
all the time,
everything'd be plain sailing.
- Look, for chrissake, go, go, go!
- Stop fussing!
- Molly?
Wha?re you up to?
- Mum!
Mum!
- I'm surprised, Molly, that you passed
your driving test!
- She's not here! Mum!
That teacher must have been blind.
- Bang, bang!
- I?s alive!
C'mon, yes, bang.
- The stove's fallen down, fallen down...
- It sure's fallen down.
You were turning and tossing and
the stove's fallen down.
Our poor little girl!
- You wanted to do me in!
- We didn't, we didn't!
Don't cry!
He's a nitwit!
- You go on, I'm all right.
- There...
I'll fetch the whip, why should I be
using my hand,
Will I or won't I?
C'mon, look at me, look at me!
- Aniline paints.
- What? What paints?
- Those we're using at school,
the poisonous ones.
- Got forbid, he wants to poison us all!
Good lord, wha?re you punishing me for?
How many did you give them?
- Only green and blue.
- This is annoying,
you try to get something to eat
you get poisoned by toxic green paints!
Poisons!
But I'm not going to lose my nerves with
you!
Just you wait when Dad gets sober,
you'll get a proper licking!
Poor little things!
You little bugger!
Why do you do this to an old woman?
Who's fond of you and has always stood
up for you?
Pffft, pffft, what a mess!
Christ, this is awful!
Wha?re you up to again, Mum?
Come on, show me!
Under the eiderdown,
Mum, stop pretending,
I know very well you're not asleep.
Well, c'mon!
Show me the hand!
No, not this one, the other one!
The one under the eiderdown!
- No, for chrissake!
- Don't chrissake me!
What is it you've got there
under the eiderdown? D'you hear me!
- Just you wait, I'll die,
you'll lose my pension
and you'll start pining for me.
- Why're you yelling,
nobody's doing you any harm,
you're not going to... again...
It was twenty years last Christmas,
I know it all only too well,
show me the hand!
What is it you've got there
under the eiderdown?
Don't annoy me, Mum!
- Listen, leave her alone!
You're kicking up such a rumpus as
if you were killing a bullock!
- You bet I will!
She's got something under the eiderdown.
- Oh, shit!
- Yes, she's got it there!
Vladimir! Vladimir, she's got it there!
She's got a shit! On my life!
- So I've got a shit, so what?
- Dear me, you'll drive me mad!
It can't be true, i?s impossible,
Please be so kind as,
to shut up!
What a place for a person to be!
Who do you think is going to
wash that for you again?
What do you mean I'm beating you?
Me, beat you?
I'll give you such a slap!
- I'm going to the cow shed.
Hey, hey, you're talking your time,
mate!
- Don't hey me, what ïyou mean, taking
my time, we all have our worries,
but I don't talk about mine.
C'mon, get into the back seat!
All right.
C'mon!
Le?s go!
I must be dreaming!
- Le?s go!
- But this was not my idea!
- Is it in keeping with raising
the quality of the environment?
Yes, it is!
Will it help this experiment of yours?
It will!
Are we supposed to help Simon, chairman?
Yes, we are!
Gee, what a beauty, engineer,
nobody else has a cow shed like this!
Get going then!
Well done, sonny, well done!
- Well, Simon?
Well, chaps?
- Eighteen per cent above average!
If it goes on like this, then, then,
i?s an award for us, chairman!
- Congratulations, Simon,
you know I've always believed in you!
I'll tell you something though,
but for our colleague secretary here...
No, no, no, no, don't say anything,
come off it, well!
- My father was also convinced
that it was daft!
- What?
Chairman, i?s not working again!
Chairman, they've switched it off again!
- Look, a power cut again,
i?s impossible, mate!
- Where are the fuses I wonder?
Hey, come and have a look at it, right?
Venca!
- What is it? I'm busy!
Didn't you hear me?
- Venca!
- There's something I want to tell you...
- Look, stop kidding me!
I?s an old story!
- I'm not kidding you!
And should be nice to me.
- So what is it?
- Here, here he is and i?s going to be
a boy, tha?s for sure.
- God forbid!
- What?
- Well, a baby!
- You mean i?s mine?
- Who else's?
- You bet it is!
- You think I'm a tart or what?
- Look, nobody's going to make a stooge
of me! I've told you before!
- You bastard! You pompous brat!
I'll never forgive you as long
as I live!
- Blame it on this blue-eyed boy
of yours who's got himself in trouble!
Hey, Venca, wha?re you doing?
- The fuses!
Miluna!
- Hi!
- Jump on, quick!
- Look, whadya think you're doing?
You stud!
What is it you're telling me, woman?!
- Let the earth swallow me up if I'm
kidding!
Let my hand dry up and let me lose
the sight of both my eyes...
- I know! Rather just one eye, eh?
- He was yelling it like mad!
They mus?ve heard him
in the cow shed too!
What a disgrace, Father!
- Kalis!
Stop showing yourself,
I say you're making an exhibition
of yourself!
- What ïyou mean, I'm showing off!
- You sure are not, but I can see you
making an exhibition of yourself
in the window!
- Okay, so I can be seen!
- Tha?s what I say, you're showing off!
Where're you off to in such a hurry?
- Going out.
- Make sure you're back in an hour!
Hey, mate, go and tell Simon
I'll meet him in the coppice tonight,
I must talk to him!
We'll manage, don't worry!
But please, just stop crying!
- You don't know Venca!
He's as stubborn as a mule!
You to explain it to him!
They're all afraid of you here.
- Of me?
- They say, you're the vanguard
and your father's in the Ministry.
- What?
What made you think so?
- The whole village says so!
That you're sending secret coded
messages through Helenka to the town.
They're afraid to lose the award.
- What?
Me and secret coded messages?
Listen, if my father knew I was here,
working on my paper,
he'd go off his head.
I only write Mum, pretending I'm our
aunt who lives near Volyne.
C'mon, we'll think of something!
But I never got involved with him!
- You did, you didn't,
the whole village's gossiping about it,
so it must be true!
- Indeed!
- Have you any idea how they'll envy you
when you become Mrs. Planickova?
- What ïyou mean, Planickova?
I love Venca!
- Just you dare!
This brute,
he's a disgrace to the village!
- Indeed!
But you didn't mind him fixing the car,
fridge and TV for you, eh?
A nice, handy boy...
- Simon's a somebody!
- I don't want him,
he's got a girlfriend in Prague!
- Never mind!
You leave this up to me!
Jirka,
hand the bunch of flowers to the lady
who'll get out of the poshest car
and mind you make a beeline for home
that very minute! Come here!
And don't you dare stay horsing around
in this outfit.
There you are and be off with you!
Hey, take an umbrella for her to shade
off the heat.
Pfffft!
C'mon!
Hi.
- Hi.
Just a moment, young man!
Don't worry, Simon, don't worry!
Look, I'm here to offer you help!
I?s my Christian duty,
ïyou understand?
- Help? Why?
- In your, ehem, precarious situation,
wha?s been done cannot be undone!
Fortunately, there is the sacrament
of matrimony.
And the wedding can practically take
place straight away!
In our little church,
I've already taken the necessary steps.
And everything will be as it should!
- Is that all?
- What more ïyou need?
Dear me!
Public opinion will calm down
and love and peace...
- Thank you for your kind offer, Father,
but I don't want to marry yet.
Let alone in church.
And I'm leaving today.
- Our Lady, can you see that?
I'll never!
Hold it!
He's not acceptable!
Cecilka!
- Yes, Father.
Call the operator to put as through to
the Regional Agricultural Board,
priority treatment!
- For chrissake!
Hand me the fern!
We'll fix it up here with a wire.
- Good morning.
- Good morning!
- Good morning, engineer!
- Simon, they tell me you're thinking
of settling down here.
Or am I wrong?
- Who told you?
- The grapevine.
When you finish school, we'll give you
a job, see?
What we need are young, promising
specialists!
You'll get a good salary to start with,
a good flat, so how about it?
- D'you happen to know where I can find
Venca?
- Venca?
- Venca's over there.
- Over there in the back!
When?
- At one.
- I'll be there at one on the dot.
So she sees I keep my word!
Pair up!
Yeah!
Tha?s them, tha?s them,
they're coming, they're coming!
Coming, gosh, coming, coming!
Coming, coming, oh, oh, oh!
Joe!
- What is it?
- Pull your tummy in!
- Oh come on!
- D'you hear me, pull your tummy in!
- Stop nagging me!
- And spit the chewing gum out!
- If I can't smoke,
at least let me chew!
- Just like you!
Just like her, she must be the first!
Smile!
Mezerova, get in line!
I'm the odd one out, Miss!
- Le?s start running!
Smile!
Welcome, Director, glad to see you.
- So am I.
- Thank you.
- Come on then.
- I've a favour to ask.
- Sure, sure.
- Tell me where this rogue of mine is.
Hi, hi!
- Pardon?
- My son Simon.
They phoned this morning to say that he
was up to a lot of mischief here!
- You don't say so.
Mischief, comrades, that can't be true!
- On the contrary, Simon's been
very helpful to the cooperative.
Sure, helpful.
Thanks to him we've put an experiment
into practice: The influence
of the quality of the environment
increase in the milk yield.
Yeah, didn't we?
And there you are - you've appreciated
the result yourself.
- So he did succeed in the end, rascal!
Welcome.
- Sweet little things!
- Would you like some...
- No, thank you.
- Glad to have you with us.
- Thank you.
They say he's been, ehem,
up to some mischief
with a local girl.
- You don't say so!
- Yes.
- I don't know anything about it.
- There's been a fight, eh?
Has there been a fight, eh?
Has there been a fight?
- So you say he's waiting
in the cow shed, right?
- Yes.
- Oh no, not in the cow shed,
I saw them a while ago,
driving towards the coppice over there.
- Coppice?
- Sure, the coppice.
- They were driving, are driving
in the... towards the coppice.
We said one, didn't we?
- Have you any idea how crowded
the doctor's surgery was?
- I see. Well, if you've dragged me
all this way just to tell me that
you're having an abortion,
you count me out!
- Have you got it?
Show it to him then.
He really is a terrible fathead!
- But I love him all the same!
- Save your tears,
I was not born yesterday.
What is it?
- A certificate.
- I can see that!
- Saying that I'm three months pregnant.
And when did I arrive here?
They're after you, the whole village!
Clear off, quickly!
- Which's the shortest way
to the station?
- You can't make it,
they'll surround it in a moment!
- Take me bike!
Jirka'll show you the way,
we'll stay behind for a while.
There they are! There they are!
Quickly!
Tha?s them! Tha?s them! What a shame!
- We just caught them when...
Pfffft!
Bloody hell!
Who are they?
I can't see without my specs.
- Wha?s this supposed to mean?
- I can't see him.
- Sorry!
What a disgrace! I'll kill you!
- Oh no.
You'd be murdering your own grandson
though, grandma!
- What?
On your way home!
Young love - what paradise!
Give it back to him with my thanks.
Cheerio!
- Cheerio, mate! And come back...
- Don't worry,
I've still got my things here!
But not a word to anyone!
- We're not stopping!
We're not stopping! Hoops!
THE END