Sun, hay and erotica
I'm sweating like the barn door.
That's a disgrace!
I've a good mind to pack it in!
-She's right. Undress it.
Take off the sweater.
Where are you looking again?
Don't make a mess.
Shame on her! She just wants to
make men to look at her.
And she even stands up!
Shame on you!
Nothing to be ashamed for.
She wants to seduce our men!
Like it's worthy.
Father, close your eyes.
Say something to her.
-Why are you staring at me?
Look forward and won't get sick.
It's so blatant.
See that, Father?
I don't see. I better not to.
Where are you going, Father?
You don't have to, you are ours.
They said all men, Kelišová.
Yeah.
Don't undress, shame on you!
Father, don't you dare!
-What can I do?
They could do, right?
-Gee
The one with glasses looks good.
I fancy the driver.
Hi.
I have my backpack there.
-Hubby, here I am.
Pepa! Where is Pepa?
-Went to hotel for keys.
I wanna room with balcony.
-You bet.
I wanna view to the sea.
-Anyone could say that.
Jesus, it's so nice here!
Like in Krumlov.
Father...
-What about Josef. -Sure.
Me with Josef? No, never.
To be in one room with that infidel?
Never!
I protest!
-You're right, Father.
With such amoral scum!
I bet he snores.
So you sleep with him, Kelišová.
Only two more rooms and you are three.
For chrissake,
are you nuts?
With that filthy pig?
I'd rather sleep under tree!
Did you hear that, Father?
-What?
Don't yell here, you aren't
in village anymore.
The only possibility is with Kelišová then.
Holy Mary,can you hear?
How can man of purity
share a bed with woman?
Play heads or tails, but quickly.
What will they think of us?
Czechs and can't settle.
Let's go...
God, where did you sent me this time?
Father, I'll roll myself to the wall
so I won't tempt you.
I ordered new swimmsuit, yellow one..
Jesus Christ!
It moves!
Yuck, that's some sea creature!
Take it away!
-Hubby, don't touch that!
Jesus, what's that?
-It blinked!
And the potatoes move as well.
-Oh yeah.
Stop screaming, women!
We aren't oafs.
You wanted some Italian specials
so here you are.
I wonder who'll eat it now.
Who? All of us.
We aren't yokels.
Or are we?
That's awful.
Tomatoes, I know that.
And this is seaweed.
Look, look!
Chrissake, here!
Take this, you ugly bastard!
That's disgrace, Father.
Where we ended up?
See?
Can't, I'm full.
I've a good mind to pack it in! Thank God
we have supplies from home.
Otherwise we'd starved to death.
-Kelišová, where are you going?
With God's help.
Pepo, don't you dare!
If you take it to your mouth,
I won't kiss you anymore.
Representation my leg.
Much ado for nothing.
Jesus, she's a pig.
Scusi, signore.
Father, gonna throw up.
E, ciao, signorine!
Man, it's them.
Mafia, I bet.
-Don't say.
We know each other already, right?
How could they find us?
Let's leave, quickly.
Where to, cuties?
We are tourists.
Miluna!
No!
Come...
Bernardo, hit it!
Pericoloso!
To walk alone in the foreign town
isn't very wise.
You need la protezione.
-Si. -Protection.
And that's us!
Bene, good! And now, ladies,
we invite you to drink, si?
That's not proper, we don't know
each other yet.
Mi scuso, signorine!
Io sono Bernardo.
-Vincenzo.
I'm Evièka,
You can call me Evík.
Evík! Miluna!
-Evík, Miluna...
Ciao!
Ciao, Bernardo!
-Ciao...
Vincenzo!
Amici, what can I do for you?
-Come sempre, like the usual.
Do it really well today.
-Si, si, everything's gonna be ok.
Filippo!
Don't say.
Jaroušek would be envious.
-Jaroušek, and eveyone.
Che cosa?
Perfetto.
-Perfetto! Filippo, presto!
Cin cin!
-Cin cin...
You wanna run away?
Yeah.
They just ordered us dinner.
What if they slip some drugs in it?
Drugs?
-They'll put into sleep, kidnap you...
I don't know.
Don't say!
You can't tell what mafia do.
They asked you?
Bullshit!
-What did you tell them?
That you are indeed the local mafia bosses.
You cretin!
So I should tell them you work as
servicemen here at the farm?
Think.
They'll let you do things
and then you'll thank me.
They can think anything,
the truth is we can use it.
Ok, but I'm capo.
OK.
The truth is we can use it..
Yeah!
Blažena, Gábina.
That's it.
But can we talk them into?
Don't worry.
Are they into us? They are.
Are we cute girls?
We are. That's it.
Miluna!
You are beautiful. I think I love you.
You bet.
-I swear on my soul.
If you really love me you could do
something for me.
Anything.
-You don't have to, I'm modest.
Like Lenin. I can do with little.
I hate one woman.
You don't know her, she's
such a bitch.
She destroyed my life.
Non piangere, non piangere!
Cara Eviku.
-Mila, say something.
Damn, me too. The other one.
-Other one?
There are two, due puttane.
Due!
Both are terrible.
So if they kidnap them, likvidate them...
You'll do a good deed.
-Kidnap?
Come?
Nevermind. We'll find others if you are afraid.
Evik, let's go.
Who's afraid?
Say it again!
I'll offer you all of my Slavic charm
if you kidnap those two bitches.
Signori!
One moment.
Not now, only after! Let's go.
You made fine mess, cretin!
Thank you very much.
Ugly violet thing!
-Brr!
I still see that.
Thank God we don't have sea.
Gimme.
-Open your own.
All I want is a sip!
Don't think you'll finish it by yourself.
There is still the tomorrow.
What?
I'm looking for sheets.
Under the bed?
Italians have to cover themselves somehow.
But there's nothing.
So what, it's hot.
-I'm gonna ask.
Where are you going? -Máòa, so you can't
find anything to cover yourself, too?
I looked everywhere.
This hotel is weird.
I bet we'll have to sleep dressed.
-Thank God we brought the sweaters.
Halo, halo!
Halo?
How do you say halo in Italian?
Hello!
- Si, signora.
Eh, uh... Come here!
Our room here...
But there is...
Buonasera, signore. -Here.
No sheet.
Si, capisco.
But your bed is ready.
-Show me, then.
Permesso.
Like that, madame.
So I have to suck in
or we together?
Momento, madame, I'll show.
What, what...
What's going on?
You'd like that, right?
Did you wanna see how to get inside,
so she shows.
This isn't hotel but bordello!
It was, madame, but sadly
they closed it down.
That's a lot of water...
-Don't stare and eat.
Leave me alone.
Are you nuts, people?
Why you eat so much?
We are invited to dinner.
That will be something.
Like yesterday. Monsters pulled from the sea.
Oh please.
-You're right!
Eat what you can, we have
all morning for that.
Don't go anywhere, Father.
You know you can't fight.
Don't start again, Kelišová.
-Right!
They show it all the time on tv,
they fight here.
That's Iraq and Iran, we are in Italy.
No matter, it starts on "I", too.
Aunt, you won't go to water?
To catch some AIDS? Now, when I'm old?
Blažena!
Don't swimm too deep.
Don't you dare!
The edge is enough.
God, have mercy and avert the temptation
from your servant.
This is supposed to be stables?
Chairman, that can't be!
Buongiorno, cari amici!
Don't be oafs.
And when you do wonder,
shut your mouth, Kelišová!
Benvenuti, welcome!
Don't say!
They can go everywhere.
True Mafia.
I'm presidento.
-Nice to meet you. Rádl Josef.
It's like at home.
-Stop undermine everything!
Let me there too.
Wait, I was here first.
Moment, brothers.
Si, benvenuto, padre.
That's enough...
Presidento!
All the world talks about you.
-No! -Si!
It's pleasure to say
that thanks to your experiment
"The Plánièka System"
our farm is the most famous
in the whole Italy.
Bravo!
-The whole Italy.
Vincenzo!
This is our chief engineer Vincenzo.
He's the best.
Can repair TV screen, fridge...
He was twice on TV.
Buongiorno!
Make yourself presentable and then come upstairs.
You'll dine with us. - Si, presidente, si.
Bernardo!
This is our animal specialist, Bernardo.
He'll show you the department of
milk production.
Ciao!
Hi.
Prego, this way!
The cleansiness is everything for us.
-Yeah, Yeah.
That's why we produce the highest
quality milk. Here!
That's wonderful.
Cecilka would be surprised.
So you wash the cows every day?
Twice a day.
And we twice a year.
Nagger!
Plánièka's method.
We just widen it slightly.
Slightly, hm.
Can't eat anymore, hun.
Unfasten your belt, then.
We can't leave it here.
Right, it'd be waste.
Too bad we ate all the home-made
schnitzels. -Shut up.
The Czech farmer won't retreat from
the dining table.
Hm, thou shall not steal, Kelišová.
Shit, Father.
What if someone else steals it?
We'll have evening meal.
Wine?
So?
Aspetto.
Si, si.
Uno momento, cara.
Bernardo!
Antonio, presto!
-Move it.
Do you have money?
Brothers said they won't do a thing.
No money, no job.
Chiaro?
-La merda!
Here's the advance, the rest after
we got salary.
We are broke.
-And when will you show them to me?
Come upstairs in a bit.
Those I'll pour wine for.
And just for sure,
I'll do this.
Clear?
Wine?
Hubby, you got off your shoes.
Only a bit.
On my soul, he did.
Such a stench!
Get it on now!
Hun!
I can't find it.
Get under the table and find his shoe
before everyone dies of stench.
Why me again?
-Shut up and get under.
Well, how to put it.
I put this hair style first time
on my head thanks to bed
and this is looks it how.
Oh, mom.
-In the farm's intention...
La salute, cheers!
It's done.
We'll see.
Friends, amici, to the success of our
future project
and to your brave Slavic women.
Hear, hear!
Vivat!
This isn't sleep!
It's disgusting, I'm all flat.
No wonder the Italian women are
so thin.
I'm out of blanket.
Where are you going?
-Leave me alone.
Well, the last one.
I wish we are back home.
Here, drink.
Hubby, I miss your snoring.
Those cicades yells like cows.
-You have always problems.
How can you even live
in this world?
Sleeping with you is terrible.
Praise the Lord we return tomorrow.
-And I didn't do any shopping.
Jaruško, I see them there.
I don't know the size.
Size.
Come la signora?
Cosí, cosí, cosí?
-Oh, boobs.
Like this.
-Father!
Father!
Heaven sends me you!
I'm trying to find sweater for Cecilka
but I don't know the size and
Keliška is missing.
Don't you have something
for the average person,
like me?
Signora, I've got something better!
Come.
Thank you, then. Grazie.
Father, come with us, he has
some goods.
Imported stuff, but cheap...
No, Father, ladies only.
-But yeah, Father is ours.
Our friend.
- Amico, si.
We wanna have some man with us.
-Let's go!
Presto, presto!
-Don't worry, we are quick.
Here, ladies.
Thank God!
That's what I'm looking for.
-See what happens when you help.
We bring him with and he takes the best...
Hello, where are you?
Where are cloths?
-There.
You git!
Giuseppe, Giuseppe!
So that's your sweaters!
You bastard!
Giuseppe, Giuseppe!
Help!
Vincenzo!
Give it to me!
Unfortunately, your friends won't
show up in the bus.
What are we waiting for?
-Wait!
So both of them are...
-I hope not.
But I bet they're in unpleasant situation.
355 :24,456
Miluna!
Ce... cí... lie... je... je...
Silence!
Zip!
Damn bastards, one can't leave
home
or they kidnap someone.
Evik!
Look!
Miluna!
You!
Rude pigs.
That's for the sweaters.
Father, slap him, too.
Let his teeth fall off for what he dared!
It was the other one.
Giuseppe!
Come here!
I'll show you, bastard!
Kneel!
Beg for mercy and turn the other cheek!
Well, Padre?
So?
Where's that pink sweater?
They're cretins.
Miluna, Evik, so...
They're cretins! This could never happen
to us!
I swear, we love you.
Miluna, Evik.
That's your fault, idiot!
-Don't push me!
It was well-thought..
-The shit it was.
Look at them!
Ahhh!
Miluna!
My dear...
My dear, where are you...
Where are you...
Bravo!
Padre, eat whatever you want.
Too bad you can't be here at sunday.
So this is the unpleasant situation?
Hello, girls!
How come you are here?
Imagine, they kidnapped us!
By mistake.
But they're very nice people.
They killed chickens, cooked them...
gave us watermelons...
They even lifted me!
They're gits, but I already
slapped them.
But they promised never do that again.
Right, youths?
Can't you reply?
Madonna mia, you are too kind to them.
Thank goodness.
I'm just old, weak woman who can't
handle them alone.
Don't stare! Bring the salad.
At least you're okay!
They hit my head with shoe!.
Girls!
-That's beautiful! -My size!
Where did you get it?
-You have to know places.
And bargain!
Thank you for the visit,
cari amici.
I believe we'll see each other
more often.
We thank you too and believe
That we can welcome you soon in Hoštice.
Si, si, we gladly accept.
Is it okay at the end of the month?
Which one?
-This one.
Say... 28th, Saturday.
Can't do sooner.
Evik!
-Miluna, don't be angry at me.
Not my fault I'm not with mafia.
-But you are doublecrosser. Bye.
Czech boys are best.
-Miluna!
You can't leave me like that.
Per favore,
where can we find Padre Otík?
What?
Father, some monks are looking for you.
What are you asking me for, dear brothers?
Father Superior gives his greetings
and sends you little present.
To support the Church in Bohemia, Moravia,
Silesia..
And Slovakia, too.
-Too...
Computer.
-PC.
Computer... Thousand thanks to
Father Superior
I'll send letter of thanks.
No, I'll do it myself.
What will you do with that, Father?
You'll be very surprised.
I think I love him nevertheless.
-Me too.
So much.
Such a mess.
Strange... Can you see what you didn't
see before?
Or rather didn't want to see.
-Stop it, Josef
You are in our comitee as a people's opinion.
True, it's democracy now, but you
won't undermine everything.
Eeek!
Don't worry, mom,
it's just a comitee.
Chrissake!
Comrades aren't here for you, mom.
We aren't comrades anymore, gran.
We know each other!
-You!
I told you many times not to give her
my son's toys!
Do I give it to her?
You lost a soldier here.
Evík, write.
Clean the yard,
cover the dung...
and all the stuff is in disorder.
Disorder, you say?
We are building here!
Stuff in disorder
-Disorder...
There isn't Y in disorder!
We are building!
And do something with all this
chickenshit.
And you have carpets on your right, eh?
Carpets!
It's about presentation.
What'll those Italians think about us?
That we live here in shit!
-Hubby!
Don't write this!
She erased "live".
Cretin.
We have to improve this as well.
But how?
That's easy.
-Another of your ideas?
We'll put hose with a brush...
and we'll have the washing machine
like they have.
We have mud spa everythime it rains...
And then those small Dior sprays...
Stop the bullshit and build us a toilet, finally!
Women, what do you say?
-Right.
Toilet. Fourty years you gone
behind the barn
and now you want better.
You can't be allowed abroad.
Comrades, please... Girls!
That's why we are here.
We have to improve all this
in no time.
Otherwise the Italians won't
join our business.
Konopníková, we were at your yard.
It's not nice. -Chairman,
I didn't invite any Italians.
They arrive and I'll hide and that's it.
It seems that in our village
only church and graveyard are ok.
Mostly the graveyard.
-So we'll show them mostly this.
Josef...
-Let him,
We already took his benefits.
Don't piss me, Josef.
We all know where we went with communism.
But how can we get out of this?
Hallo, hallo.
Town hall and the comitee invite
all citizens to the extraordinary
meeting to the pub today at six PM.
Arrive at time.
-Do you hear that, Father?
Free beer is served during the main topic.
A public meeting
- Repeat...
Exceptionaly extraordinary
or extraordinary exceptionaly.
I don't know, but it's in the pub.
-We don't need meetings anymore.
We have everything in order.
Well, not me. I still have to
clean the sacristy
whiten the stables.
They'll visit it anyway.
And where would be this method
without or Dolly.
You are right, Cecilie.
Father, I'd go there anyway.
Good to know what's happening.
Milunka, Milunka!
Give us one.
Or rather two.
Just a sec, aunt, I'll be with you right away.
-She does it on purpose.
Friens, in conclusion,
I say it again.
Every idea, every thought
how to improve things here
is welcomed.
With this I end the topic and open
the discussion.
Here...
Wait, what does it mean?
-You heard, end of topic
now you pay it by youselves.
-And when did I order!
They won't notice elderly
even if she died of thirst.
Right, Cecilka, so the world repays.
Speak, people!
Usually you have mouth full of talk
and now your lips are sealed.
Frankly.
If we want to prevent bankrupcy
we can't do without Italians.
I have suggestion.
So...
Get them drunk right away
and they'll sign whatever we want.
Write it down, Evik,
there is something into it.
Get Italians drunk.
We have to do it anyway.
Well, I... Me and Gabby think,
that we need to show Italians something...
that will show them we can be worldly.
Right, Gabby?
I think, I think...
Let Jaruš and Wendy sing in national dresses...
And I have got bagpipes.
Bagpipes, today!
We have to shock them!
Bagpipes, please.
-Me and Gabby think...
that we should found...
how to say it politely?
-Don't know.
Well...
-Nudist beach.
What's that?
-Sodom and Gomorrah, Patoèková.
Phew, no!
-We won't approve.
Say something, Father.
-Going commando, that's healthy.
Right, doctor?
-True.
Don't start.
-You'd like that!
Ogle nude women. -Like we haven't
ever seen one.
My words.
-Shut up!
Shame on you, men, don't you have
enough at home?
Isn't that right, women?
I think it would be classy.
Classy, my leg!
Go there and I'll broke yours!
We want into Europe. Even naked.
I'm for that.
-Hubby!
But we won't go too far with
the nudity.
E.g. women could be nude only
from here to there.
And men from sack below.
Nice work, chairman.
That will shock the Italians
for good.
Holy Virgin, what they
came up with again!
It's not enough for them to be...
where they are.
End of the world.
I'm still off balance.
What can we do?
-The best defense is attack, Cecílie.
Call in the sisters... and we'll see.
At night?
The martyrs brought sacrifices, too.
They didn't mind the day- or nighttime.
I have to catch my breath.
I bet they murdered someone.
Girls, who wants grog?
Shame!
-True.
We are ready, Father.
See?
We can't step into Europe with
such material.
I'd sell hot dogs in the shack.
Some boutics around.
And the hedge from bonsai trees around.
What are you doing?
Practicing for Olympics, moron.
-Just wait!
Don't you think you'll walk the beach like this.
Disgusting egotist!
And you want to be in charge of international
business?
And this nudist beach was your idea anyway.
Who else should set the example
but your wife?
Yeah. But you heard the chairman.
Naked woman from here to there.
-You moralist.
What are you doing?
I'm doing something...
Now I can't see.
Are you crazy?
I hit my head, you idiot!
Am I some kind of mattress?
-What an moron of a man I've got!
I can't live with you since you've
seen  Emmanuelle.
It's you who call for Emmanuelle.
-Bullshit.
My god...
Where did you get it, chairman?
We had a discussion at home...
Beat it.
But in the end I persuaded her.
This is architect Svinutý.
Pilátová Eva, Pleased to meet you. Secretary.
Svinutý.
-Béd'a.
This is the object?
-Yeah, that's it.
Half of the 17th century.
Are you stupid?
You'll make it nice for us,
right. Mr. Architect?
And when it should be done?
-Until 28th.
28th of what?
-This month.
Dam sings, river does magic,
moon above the river...
And the mornings are quiet.
Mr. Architect!
Mr. Architecht, don't trust him
and don't go inside!
Kelišová, you thwart the
official act.
We could make it very unpleasant for you.
I'd give a shit.
Incarcerate me!
I had to warn him, that's my christian duty.
From what?
If I may inquire.
-They didn't tell you?
The mill is haunted.
Our department of construction is
accustomed to horrors.
Let it go
-she? When she dies.
She's nightmare, the hag!
So much work here.
28th you say?
-Few small rooms would be enough.
For dressing, showers, too...
My first guess is...
Around one and half million.
Million?
-Yeah. -Chrissake!
Such a sum.
Where could they get it?
Kelišová, dammit!
We can spare around 35 thousands,
right, Chairman?
In that case, don't do any reconstruction.
Pay the amateur actors to paint the scenery.
35 000 would be enough for that.
Told you.
What an idea!
Good day, aunt.
-G'day.
What did you bring me, Vašík?
-Lime, aunt. From the co-op.
You ought to whiten your house.
All of it? With this brush?
They said at least the front side.
-And who's gonna do that?
Likely you, aunt.
-Me, an old woman?
Should I climb up? I can't even
stay on the ladder.
Don't know, aunt.
Bye.
-Lazy git.
Crissake! I miss the Communist.
They never wanted one to do things.
And even if the house crashed on my head,
they wouldn't notice me at all.
In Italy, they have open marked in
every village. Here's nothing.
Good day.
-Good day.
Open market. Whe used to have
great fairs.
Ládík, say something.
-Don't tell me.
I don't know why we abolished them.
Pretzels, are you out of your mind?
-You used to have bakery, right?
Yeah, but you took it from us in 1948.
-Us?
It was Communists.
Comrade secretary, don't tell me.
And the oven is ruined anyway.
No matter, Aunt. Old Vacík
should build you a new one.
He's lucky to even breathe.
And leave me alone.
No discussion, Krajánková!
You'll bake such pretzels that
Italians won't ever forget.
Hurry, aunt, hurry!
They'll come as soon as 28th.
Let's go, it's no use.
-And think it of as political mission!
Goodbye.
And I'd denounce it, Father.
To whom?
-To the Italians.
People here are no good.
I'm no denouncer, but it must be told.
Right you are, Maøenka.
You forget about Josef, Father.
That git was there, too.
You're right, Cecilka.
J-o-s-e-f.
And we have them all.
They invited the architect from
Budìjovice.
But he'd a good mind to pack it in.
I told him the mill is haunted.
Well, that huge black dog and
the dead sexton.
Cecilka!
I've got letter for you
-Thanks -Bye.
She writes again.
Maria, Maria!
And what's she writing about, Father?
Nothing important.
About the procession etc.
And she greets you.
-Thanks. -You're welcome.
Cutie, I suppose?
-Well, cutie...
... rather short one and wild.
-Wild one?
And ugly as hell.
Ugly?
Really?
The Lord gave so much beauty to everyone
as he saw fit, Kelišová.
Big black dog, you say?
Technology marches on, Chairman.
Moves alone, walks alone, see?
Better than some computing stuff.
Leave it be, Josef.
You already have one PC.
Calculator more likely.
They have PC!
They have... You are like the
women from the barn.
Chairman, they've got swimming pools.
Chairman, the've got toilet.
Where can get money for it
when the farm is bankrupted!
And you demand computer.
Ask the priest to lend it to you.
You are in commitee now
so do your best.
-Wish I could see that.
To him.
Grow up!
I wonder why he needs PC.
A priest.
The thing is to get money from
Italians.
Or even ten PCs won't help us.
-Stop him poking.
Better send the lazyass to the mill
paintig the scenery.
Leave me alone.
-Lád'a...
Evik, I've got something for you.
Thanks.
Can't...
Can't be... Bernarndo mio!
He wants to marry me but first
he has to talk with his mom.
Bought two rings and the honeymoon
should be in Nigeria.
Miluna, I'll go crazy.
Don't cry, Yours will write you, too.
_He won't.
I was too mean for him.
I'll never marry.
-Milu, don't cry.
Know what?
I won't marry to Italy without you.
Promise.
You're so good to me.
-I know.
Travel agency!
Not a bad idea.
I'm telling you all afternoon.
Think of Vachout family.
They have camp next to river.
We should see into that.
We should visit people in village
and offer them to get clients.
No troubles for them and we'll
get bonus. Not bad.
Live in the tent all the sumer long?
Ill kidneys, ovaries and mosquitos.
Don't do that.
Sweethearts, I baked buns for you.
They're burnt a bit, but you'll
like them nevertheless.
I'd be fat.
-Oh, please.
Gabby, it's pure chemistry.
Vendy and Jaruš will eat them in no time.
Sugar, please.
I'll bring it immediatelly, honey.
Sugar's coming.
Vendy, Gabby, eat quickly
or it'll go cold.
Say you like it.
What a mess.
Where did I put it?
Kája, didn't you see the red notepad?
Vendy, coming.
Here, baby.
-Thanks.
Let's do it in great style.
Hello girls.
Hey, that's the amazing burnt ones?
But the great style calls for...
Well?
-PC
Tss. Don't tell me.
-I have idea.
Otík.
-He won't lend you a thing.
Why not buy it for ourselves?
He says all the time it's a win.
Let's buy it in Germany.
Please, no more garbage to house.
It's not.
Have you seen the Italians?
They had everything programmed.
Feeding, milking, everything.
PC is half of the job.
For the handful of rabbits?
They'll die in no time.
Handful? We decided to go in
great style!
What would you do with so much rabbits?
Thought it through ages ago.
Look:
School trips, hospital in Volynì,
hospice...
not to mention pubs.
Where do you get money?
You need foreign money to buy PC.
Do you have it? Shit.
Who needs foreign money?
We still have mom's teeth.
Vahotova: Stole vegetables.
Jirka: Lying, smokes, skips school.
Radlova: gazes on other men.
The chairman lent the boy scouts
seven times.
used the same speech for October revolution
Anniversary - 22x
borrowed the church chairs for the meetings
11x - no, 12x.
And when they returned it,
there were all puked over.
Right you are, Cecilie. Puked over.
Is this allright, Father?
What do you say?
What?
Please, Lord, not yet!
Not yet!
Christ, what's wrong?
It's me, your Cecilka.
Where did you get it?
In the attic. Americans left it here
in 1945.
Mom, dad, the mill is haunted!
-Haunted my leg!
Sit and eat, it's cold already.
Look, there's light.
I bet Josef is painting the scenery.
She swallowed water...
Chrissake..
Hu, huu!
Dude, you look awful.
Come here and take a sip.
Do you know me?
-Sure, dude.
Lenin!
Here, drink. Don't have this at home
anymore.
Drink...
Wait, what about me?
Don't you dare to finish it alone.
Lenin!
With my bottle, too!
Lenin, where are you? Lenin?
Vladimir Ilyich Lenin
-I don't get it, Karel.
Pay no heed to it, mom.
I bet it's just some provoking.
Come.
Jaruš, tell them
it's the last one.
If they need more, send them to
town hall.
Drive carefuly, they're brand new.
Nobody ever read it.
Professor!
Proffesor!
What?
You lost some Gottwald!
-I see.
Pepíèek?
Pepíèek, come here, please.
Go pick up the comrade president.
This is thrilling.
Jaruška, please!
Classics to the barn?
What to do with it?
I vote for burning it.
-We democrats don't burn books.
Vendy said that not even the used books
shop will buy it,
so before we throw it away,
it will serve to good purpose.
Ladies, lesson number one.
Body posture and the nudist beach
walking with smile.
With the help of these books.
Let's put them on heads, ladies,
and step out.
Nicely, charmingly, show your breasts
and let's go.
One, two, three...
Ladies, go, go.
That's right...
Nice. Next lady...
Smile, show your teeth...
Well done.
If the books slips, don't worry,
we have plenty. Next one...
Charmingly, ladies,
show the breasts...
Next one, go...
When Italians see this,
they'll give us everything
and run away.
Represent!
Ladies did it wonderfully.
They are naturals.
Sorry.
Ja, bitte...
Hubby, some bull.
Yeah, yeah.
Isn't that too small for the price?
Well...
How can rabbits fit in?
That's allright.
-And won't it speak German?
We'd understand shit.
Sorry?
-Will you pay cheque or cash?
In gold.
Na bitte.
Genuine gold.
Na ja, gold, aber...
What aber?
Is it gold or what?
Count it quickly, we have no time.
That's too little.
Little? When was the last time
you've seen so much gold?
These are teeth from my father.
From the Austrian empire.
And that was some gold.
You have to pay more.
Pay more?
How much more he wants for that junk?
Genuine Gottwald.
125 Marks...
125? It's worth more, my dear German boy.
Bitte, ein Gottwald ist fünf mark.
Not fünf, but acht - eight!
I know it well.
From Rosie. She was in Austria
and they gave them eight!
Understand?
We are no cheats.
How to say it in German?
Unter wassermen, understand?
We are honest farmers from Hoštice!
Verstehen? Acht!
Dad!
God help you!
Pay attention, I write.
-That's what I call art.
It looks almost alive.
After so many years and
finally it's possible.
Nach links, ja?
To whom they belong to?
How can I tell?
They are ours and they like it very much.
They'll come again next year.
OK.
If this continues, one can't
understand anymore.
I'm old and don't wish to learn German.
Promise me everyting is allright
before Bernardo arrives.
What day is today? -Tuesday.
25., Let's do salary.
Oh! Nettle! Cut it down!
We were to...
I know, Grüssgott.
Munich.
Don't hit it so hard.
Did you washed your hands?
-Leave me alone.
Now I lost it!
I told you not to let him.
It's easy.
We play games at school on it.
Play games on such expensive machine?
Don't you dare or I'll break your arms.
Look, there's some icon now.
-I can see that, but what for?
It's written there.
Press return and continue.
I told you it will emit in German.
Do you know how to say rabbit in German?
Wait...
Here you are. And now you can
use it as the typewriter.
Dad.
-What?
You've got typo there.
-Where?
Chrissake, female with two ee!
What's wrong with feemale?
It looks stupid with single e.
Females. Five females.
When you have doubts,
think of similar words.
Feelings, feeble, fee...
You already forgot everything
that you learned at school.
Do you have any feemale there?
-There!
The only thing female needs to be long
is her hair!
Cover it, they don't need to know
we've got computer.
Why? We haven't steal it.
-They don't need to know. Enter!
Hello.
Hi.
-I'll be quick.
I saw you returning from
Germany so I wanted to ask
if you want to sign the deal with
our travel agency called Solstice.
What kind of deal?
-Rent the house for summer.
Germans, French, other foreigners.
-We need to think it through.
40 Marks per night.
3/4 of the village already signed.
Chairman as well?
Solstice works dependably.
We observe the thing with Italians-
they'll stay in houses of our
clients
and afterwards plenty of
Westerners will be interested.
In the meantime we should stay
in the attic?
In tent near the river. Mind of
Vachout family, how they prosper.
And they can't speak German nor English.
Speak!
You'll let everything as it is
and make it available for tourists.
The thing is to make them feel
at home.
Let's clean this place, whiten the
facade, flowers at windows..
Riverside is warm at summer,
we can endure it for time.
Others endured, so we will.
Where should I sign it?
Cecilie, for God's sake,
where did you get this beast?
Told you I prepared something.
Old Jeremiah woman lent him to me.
He could kill a man easilly!
-Father, he's just a pup.
Puppy my leg!
-Make it go outside, Cecilka!
Let's go Broèek. Did you hear?
You're stroke squad indeed!
-Yeah.
If only he howls.
Howl, Broèek, howl!
Like this: Hoo! Hoo!
-You call this howling?
You have to do it right, deeply.
Like this:
Hoo...
-Low pitch, not high!
Chrissake, they don't know where
to put me. I wanna downstairs!
I'm scared!
-Of what?
We are all present!
It's just a test of endurance.
Tomorrow we'll be in tent next to river.
C'mon.
We do it for our well-being.
I'll run away! I'm afraid.
Be glad we lifted you up here.
Chrissake...
Do you hear that too? Suspicious.
-Just dogs from the village.
They sing to the moon.
-So weird? It's scary.
Bro, catch.
-It feels like at wartime.
You wouldn't eat so well at wartime.
Give me bread for mom.
Mom!
Jesus, where did she go?
Where did you burrow?
You drive me mad!
Jesus! My back hurts!
Since morning.
I bet it's the sun erections.
That's the black dog from mill.
I'm scared!
I wish he wants to eat you!
-But the howling is weird anyway.
That's it!
Nothing on this world would
howl like that.
Father!
Chrissake, Father!
-It's Maøenka.
Open up!
-Something happened.
Open up, Father!
What's going on, Kelišová?
-Open up!
Father, the mill is haunted
for sure.
Beat it, woman!
There are no spooks.
Maøenka...
-Aaaa...
See?
That's weird.
-Strange.
Let's go, guys.
-Keep it.
Come here, dude. Look.
-Don't shout, they'll hear us.
There are spooks for sure.
Aaaa!
Girls from the village!
Jiøina, Anèa!
That's our Anèa! I'll slap your ass,
you'll see at home.
Look!
It's a mask.
Aaaa!
I thought I died, Father.
-Hm.
You both drink it.
Where are the pills for sweating?
In the cupboard, under St. Therese.
Under Therese.
If only you could see that...
-What?
The blonde...
He looked just like my dead husband.
Bless you.
-Right.
Where should I put it?
-There.
Here you have another.
Pedestrians not allowed!
And don't run so fast here.
Why you bring it here?
Just in front of our tent!
The decision about the beach
was made, so what?
Just following orders.
-What orders?
This land belongs to Co-op.
Be glad we let you set your
tents here and for free!
Yeah.
You can remain here under single
condition.
You have to be naked.
Read the sign.
Chrissake, he's crazy!
Who's crazy? You vote for it
and here you are.
They move one out of his house
to eat the dirt
and even demand our nudity!
I find it very usual.
You're so backwards!
Jesus!
-Naked?
See that, mom?
See? No problem, girls.
I can undress as well, nothing
to be ashamed for. -God, no!
What do you say?
Come, hubby!
Me too, me too!
-Don't start!
You'll get me to the asylum!
Healty spirit in healthy body, ladies.
-You, doctor?
Nudes!
Hubby, I never undressed
in front of so many men!
So what, shit happens.
Oh!
Chrissake! Sodom and Gomorrah!
What's going on?
-Everybody's nuts!
They're all naked and
want us as well.
Don't cry.
So we move our stuff beyond the signs.
It doesn't apply beyond this line.
Great idea, Hubby.
Right?
You moron!
Father, Father!
It's happening!
Father, it's happening!
Father, it's here!
What's here, Kelišová?
-Father! -What?
Sodom and Gomorrah! They're undressing.
-No!
Men, women, together and nude!
Hurry, Kelišová!
Jump on.
Hurry, Father.
Like in good times!
-Yeah.
Attention.
We ask all who participate
at nudist beach training
to go immediatelly into
the mill for public test.
I repeat.
Nudist beach trainees
imediatelly to the mill.
I wonder who appears first.
Not me.
No one's sending you.
I won't go first.
Right. Get out with it.
For aerobic. Got it in Rome.
I promised help, cooking, cleaning,
but won't appear nude!
We're here for Italians and not for
Hoštice. Villagers are peeking!
You practiced so long and now
you won't do it?
We weren't naked.
It was just a test.
But we weren't naked back then.
And now you will. So what.
Peace, girls.
How we studied it?
Get ready. Smile and show all the world
that even simple Czech woman
can behave like lady.
No Italian won't faint seeing
you in boots and with pitchforks.
I'm out of here.
Let the young girls do that.
Right.
-Wait here.
That wasn't the deal.
Don't you dare!
You'll get benefits anyway.
Let us go.
-Deal's the deal.
You're terrible.
They undressed in the morning
and nobody minded.
You misunderstood. Don't you dare, Gabby!
Stop it or I'll
divorce you!
He wants us undressed but not his wife!
Let the bastard undress himself!
-Are you nuts?
Help! Help me!
Help! Ow, Matoušková! Ow!
That's unheard of!
-Silence!
Look, it's started.
Are you nuts?
Open up, women! You hear me?
Let me go. That's a mistake.
This shouldn't happen.
The boy's life is endangered!
C'mon, open up!
That's not my fault!
Chrissake!
-Help!
Ow! What's wrong with you?
The Italians will love it.
Damn!
Do it again! Do it again!
Patience, please.
Friends, due the technical
dificulties
our program begins with parade
of beach hostesses.
Let's go, girls.
Don't be shy.
Chairman!
What? Chairman, we're screwed?
-Why so?
Italians in the village!
-Wait.
How so?
You have to take it.
The national's commitee ordered
and I don't want any trouble.
Grazie, signora.
Don't you have something
to drink?
Didn't say anything about drink.
The well is there.
- Grazie.
Signora Maria!
-Padre! -Signora!
It's good to see you again!
-Maria!
This is my Cecilka.
Cecilia...
Padre spoke highly of you.
Pepa, amico!
Pepo, are you surprised we're already here?
Yeah.
Girls, go.
Smile, we learned that.
Don't be shy...
Sodom and Gomorrah!
-I know that.
They're part-timers.
It's art and their hobby.
It's our new tradition.
-Split.
First you wanted us wordly and now
you don't.
Girls, let's have shot.
- Presidento mio!
Bernardo, Bernardo mio!
-Evik!
Miluna mia!
-Vincenzo! -Amore.
I'm satisfied.
We can sign the contract
immediatelly.
But we couldn't even set it right.
No, no, let it be.
How so?
You haven't seen a thing yet.
We know it all.
We researched you
and now we know even what's not true.
We want to make museum out of your farm.
Museum.
Natural museum.
And the whole world would come to see
in what enviroment began
the Plánièka method.
And tourists mean money.
And we'll use your toxic milk
to make buttons.
Perfect business.
-Bravo!
What will happen to us?
-How should I know?
Nothing, exactly how it was.
Even the personnel.
Agree?
Well...
-Wait!
Know what it means?
We'll be clowns for the whole Europe!
We did it forty years for free,
so now we'll be at least paid!
Don't wait!
Don't stare and write!
Pepa...
-Glasses.
Right hand!
So!
Amici, bravo!
Long live the president!
God, it's here!
It's here!
It's here! It's here!
It's here...
Mom, I'll make the pillow
so soft
you'll think you're in paradise.
There...
And the hair...
Kiss!
Dominik, Dominik...
Venca, did you cut the grass?
-Don't bother me with grass.
Rabbits will be hungry in the evening.
Brmbrm...
Lady.
-I can see.
Hi.
May I?
Thanks.
Nice.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Bye, lady, bye.
Don't cry! You have Venca
and the baby.
That is car allright.
Wish I had it...
You'll have, and better one.
We'll have it all.
The future will be so bright
we didn't even dream of.
I can see it clearly.
Earth's paradise. Happy future.
Three cars here.
Swimming pool with air-condition.
We'll have phone even in the barn.
And the whole world will be amazed
what we Czechs are like.
We're saavy.
Especialy when we are one step
in Europe.