THE SNOWDROPS AND THE WISE GUYS
Boys, wait, wait!
Oh, Vicky, wait!
Wait for us!
My god, I forgot my health certificate!
Hi, where's your girl-friend? Okay?
Do you see what I see?
Who is it?
I see what you see but I don't know.
Hey, careful there, I've got a camera
in there!
Now will you please be quiet.
We II have a roll call: Bubeníkov*...
- Here!
Cabadaj!
Knitlová!
Well, Knitlov*...
Yes, here!
John.
- Here!
Novák!
- Yes, luv?
Since when are you from the north?
Well, in that case okay.
Some beginning, eh?
Whose is this?
- I've got my health certificate!
What's going on?
I asked whose is this?
Well?
I don't understand, sir.
Probably my mother or sister must have...
She always wants me to have a good time.
Be quiet!
I want this to be quite clear.
This is an obligatory school course
with strict rules.
If from this moment on I find someone in
possession of alcoholic beverages,
that person will immediately
be expelled from the course.
Daddy, can I put this in?
- Sure.
Story & Screenplay
Acting
Keep marching on and bugger off forever
in this cursed town,
you'd never happy be.
The sheriff here is not a man to play
with
and so this morning could be a really
ugly one for you.
Keep marching on and continue your
journey
and try to clear off in some transit
train.
The sheriff here is strong and rough
and sturdy
and when he sees a hobo, he starts
raging like a shrew.
Keep marching on and continue your
journey
and try to clear off in some transit
train.
The sheriff here is strong and rough
and sturdy
and when he sees a hobo, he starts
raging like a shrew.
Wait!
Stop!
Stop the bus!
Charles is sick!
- Hurry up, Charles is sick!
What d'you mean, sick?
- He wants to puke!
Assistant director
Script
Director's assistant
Hold on, Charlie!
The world's eyes are on you!
Makeup
Set-up
Come on, Charlie!
Leave me here, miss.
I think I d rather walk the rest
of the way.
Don't be silly.
This can happen to anybody.
You'll get a pill, Charles,
and sit up front.
Send it to Charlie.
Charlie, this is from Karda's daughter.
Go sit down,
Costume design
Chief costumer
you'll be all right.
The road's straight now.
Further co-operating
Art director
Music
Recorded by
Conducted by
Sound
Editing
Chief producer
Camera
Directed by
Dramaturgy
Whose ski poles are these?
The snowmobile driver is as drunk as
a newt.
He won't go.
Will everyone be quiet, please!
Because of technical difficulties
the snowmobile cannot take our
things up so we'll have to walk it.
I refuse to walk!
And Bob's your uncle!
Let's go, let's go!
Gee, this is inhuman.
- I don't want to walk.
Can't the bus go any higher?
- This requires fitness.
Step on it, step on it,
get going, creeps!
Well, the locusts are here again, chief!
- Get lost!
Seeing I'm not wanted, I'm going.
Stop it, will you?
Now, girls, which one of you will make
my bed?
Annie?
- No, no way...
What kind of joke is this?
Who's the smart aleck?
All right here?
How are things?
Okay.
Look, girls,
I have a suggestion for you.
Which one of you'll make my bed?
And what do I get for it?
Well, what would you think...
Watch it!
Look, they're having a party in room 6!
- No, no way!
We'll all be sent home.
This is asking for trouble.
Come off it!
- Get out, get out. Let s go!
Marika, will you have one with us?
No, thank you, I don't drink.
Your bad luck...
Ski instructor Titch will show you the
downhill.
What did you say his name was?
Tits?
Wouldn't Vladimír do, sir?
- As you like.
What's the rush?
Wait your turn.
Aaaa...!
Which one, sir?
The third, since we don't have a fourth
one.
Well, gentlemen, this looks like
a decent set up.
Attention!
Order of the day number two.
Ptáèek on duty.
Here.
...Nìmcová.
Here!
- Schedule for tomorrow:
- 6.30 a.m. reveille, 6.45
a.m. to 7 a.m. morning work-out,
- 7.30 a.m. breakfast...
And Bob's your uncle!
...9 a.m. line-up for morning activities.
12 to 1 p.m. lunch,
...9.30 p.m. body hygiene and 10 p.m.
Lights out.
Everybody sit down.
- This will be as much fun as a funeral...
Are there any questions?
Well?
Please, sir, can we synchronize our
watches to your time?
Yes, and when will we be able to go out
shopping, sir?
Can I make a telephone call to Prague?
And do we get any time off here?
Yes and when will we be able to build
that snowman?
Silence!
I said be quiet!
We're not getting anywhere.
Elect a representative from among you
who'll pass on to me
your individual requests.
Vicky!
I'm for Vicky!
Who's in favour?
- Sure.
Vicky! Vicky!
- Vicky's number one!
Any other suggestions?
With your permission, sir,
I d like to point out that all were
in favour.
Cabadaj, I'm surely not going
to discuss it with you!
That's a pity.
Then Radek in my place.
All right.
So let it be Radek.
And now Betty wants to say a few words.
- Yes.
I'd like to say a few words.
Will you please pay attention for a few
moments, concerning our lodgings.
So... well, what is it, Radek?
I'd like to submit the first request.
When will we be able to build that
snowman?
Some set-up, isn't it?
You can build the snowman between five
and six in the afternoon,
during your time off.
Is that sufficient?
Thank you.
It is sufficient.
Well...
I have a heavy breath
and my head is aching,
I'm fat as a sack
and my legs are hardly bearing me.
And so I'm leaving
and in fact I don't know where to.
But I don't mean to say by this
that I flee from here.
Gee, what a member you have, Vicky!
Not bad, is it?
Sure enough, mate...
Watch out, Karda.
Come in!
Excuse me.
Oh, excuse me, excuse me, Miss,
I'm terribly sorry.
We thought it was Mr Karda.
You're not in bed?
There's a terrible smell here.
What's smelling so awful?
Well, it's probably onions.
Onions are good for you, onions contain
a lot of...
You've been drinking, haven't you?
No, Miss.
How could you have thought of a thing
like this?
Just you wait till...
- Why us?
...Mr Karda sees this.
But, Miss, men have a sense of smell
seven times less developed than women.
Well, yes, maybe, but we used to use
perfume in such cases.
Yes, but then you might think that we
had girls here.
What are you reading?
Francois de la Rochefoucald -
A Cruel Book
with Light-Hearted Reflections
on the Hardship of Life.
Whose is this?
- Mine.
I don't know it.
- Borrow it if you like.
Thanks.
So go to sleep now.
Don't overdo it with those vitamins.
Good night.
Those who will not admit that they may
be wrong are those
who are most often wrong.
What?
- Nothing.
Radek underlined this.
And Karda wants to treat them like
little children.
Hm.
I can't really blame him.
I'm always very happy to be back home
with nobody missing and no additions.
That's the way things are.
Once after a ski course I had to take
a student for a pregnancy test.
Hm.
Still.
I'd trust them more.
Quiet.
My little ducklings, open the door for
your Mother Goose...
Let's go have that coffee.
But hurry up and quiet!
Close it shut!
Gosh, Charlie, what's that you're
wearing?
What's the fuss?
Haven t you ever seen
a man wearing pyjamas?
- A man yes, but not Charlie.
Psst!
Be quiet!
I've inherited it from my Granddad.
It would be a waste to throw it away.
I've got my Granny's nightshirt.
I've got frozen feet for a change.
Agreed.
It's freezing here.
What are you reading?
You can borrow my socks.
They're in the cupboard.
Thanks. Up here?
- Yeah.
Charlie boy, come sit by us.
C'mon.
Well, thank you,
may I?
And I thought we were going to have
a party under blankets.
Aaaaa...
I think I can hear somebody walking
about.
I'll go have a look.
I never thought I'd have to be
a maintenance man...
Put it down.
...here tonight.
Come, I'll warm you up, Vicky.
Hm. In I go.
Mind the feet.
In bed with the girls again.
But look, you could at least take off
your shoes, you pig!
Okay.
What about you two?
You'll catch a cold!
Hey, boys, you can get into my bed.
This is just fine,
but who'll make the coffee now?
That I don't know.
- Neither do I.
It seems to me that the ladies
are having visitors.
Karda here.
Open the door, will you?
I insist that you open the door!
What is it, sir.
We are asleep.
I won't have this.
Where are they?
I wouldn't smile in your place.
I know everything.
What does he want?
Marika, where are they?
But who, Daddy?
You know very well what I'm asking,
Marika.
I don't know.
Ouch!
Careful.
Watch out!
What's going on here?
What is it, mate?
- What!
Oh, excuse me, sir...
- At last.
Look, boys, stop horsing around,
I know that you ve been
in the girls' room.
I don't know about anything, sir.
You don't, do you?
Gee, that tickles!
Of course, ice-cold.
But that's because the heat's not on.
That's because you're letting too much
fresh air in.
Boys, I'm warning you.
I won't tolerate such behaviour.
Looks like this trip's all fouled up.
Don't cross your bridges before you've
come to them.
Yupee! Hop! Hop! Hey!
Gosh, what a long line!
I thought it was a workday.
It's vacation time in the G.D.R.
Gentlemen,
I don't like jumping the queue,
but in this case we can't help it.
Let's go.
- It's not fair, but necessary.
Watch out, watch out, d'you hear me?
Be careful, these are new skis, don't
step on them.
This winter leaves a lot to be desired.
Folks, will you please line up and
everybody will be happy.
Marika, come here!
Here we are.
Look!
This is crazy.
Going downhill is executed from
the basic downhill posture,
which means the knees are slightly bent,
the body is inclined forward
and its weight is shifted onto the lower
ski.
How does it go, Miss?
- Very well, thank you.
May I dust the snow off your back?
- Thanks.
It might lower your authority.
Could we come along on the lift
with you?
My girls're doing quite well.
- Help!
Sure.
Where d'you think you're going...
Get back in line...
Look, wise guy,
get back or I'll put you back.
We're the national ski team.
- Just a moment.
National ski team, my eye!
Get back in line.
Did you hear me?
Get back in line!
Why us again?
Everybody back in line!
But we're going to stand here for ever.
I'm sure you'll survive.
Look, they're jumping the queue too.
Get back!
Don't jump the queue.
Did you hear me?
- We're training for the Olympics, Jack!
Olympics, my eye!
You're the one to teach me about skiing,
you upstart.
Please make way here.
Why don't you maintain order here?
It's your business, not mine.
Don't you understand Czech?
Was? Ich verstehe nicht.
Aaaa... You...
Don't jump the queue, damn!
But he was holding a place for me.
- To the end of the queue with you!
Go bugger your own students.
- Don't be fresh, young man!
What's going on?
- They're jumping the queue.
Are we here to stand in line or to ski?
- Theoretically the latter, friend.
And we're supposed to educate them.
How the hell long are we supposed
to stand here.
I'm giving up.
Snowdrops, girls, follow me,
we're going up on foot.
Whaaat?
- We're walking.
Everyone's using the lift only we can't.
- Didn't you hear what I said?
That's unfair, Miss.
- Come on, girls.
Take off your skis and come on.
- It makes me mad, too.
We can reconcile ourselves to what
others do unto us.
It is in what we do unto ourselves that
the difficulty lies.
Excuse me.
You underlined that in Rochefoucauld,
didn't you?
We haven't advance too much,
have we, sir?
Nobody's keeping you from going up
on foot.
In these boots?
- The boots are not the problem.
Let's go!
Radek!
- Gee, look!
Vicky's going up.
What's going on?
- C'mon! C'mon!
Yeah.
I thought you also disagreed
with jumping the queue.
Yes, I do disagree,
but then people hold you for a sucker.
Are you angry?
- No.
Arrivederci!
And Bob's your uncle!
For this evening I've prepared
an amusing game for you.
Here on these pieces of paper,
everybody quiet please,
here on these pieces of paper,
are written the names of famous pairs
of lovers.
For instances Romeo and Juliet,
Tatyana and Onegin...
Michalíková and Vanìk!
What are they in?
- Why, they're in 2B Form.
And the pair must seek each other out
with the aid of some quotation.
Meet you by the john at break time,
Michalíková!
But you mustn't use the name of one of
the pair.
You must use a quotation.
For example:
I cast my brimmer far away.
Or something like that.
- What does he cast away?
Cyrano, you nitwit.
- And what happens when I find my lover?
Then you'll dance together.
- That's stupid...
And what happens if I don't know any
quotation?
Can I be Don Juan?
Well, I really don't know...
I think that's a very nice game.
And when you don't know something your
literature teacher here'll advise you.
Come and get your pieces of paper.
Come on Sir, let's play.
Who doesn't have their piece of paper.
Come on, boys.
The wolf and the little Red Riding Hood,
that's beautiful...
Little Red Riding Hood!
- Desdemona!
Desdemo... Oh no!
Hynek, Vilém, Jarmila...
How come that I, Manon,
have all that good luck?
Sultán!
Well now, where are you,
you bastard of a dog?
Bow-wow, that's me, your Tyrl.
- What, you?
I refuse to dance with you, you creep!
- Why?
Sir, take a piece of paper too.
- What?
All right...
Punch and Judy.
And they have killed our Ferdinand.
How come that I, Manon,
have all that good luck?
And feet in warmth, Miss Müller.
So they killed our Ferdinand.
- I'm *vejk, Miss.
For the better to see you,
little Red Riding Hood.
I'm writing to you, what can I say,
what can I further add.
You wrote to me, do not deny.
I read Your trustful lines.
That love expression, pure and sweet...
Oh, Ophelia, oh hell, she's supposed to
be a young girl.
Hynek, Vilém...
Judy...
Jarmila...
- My god, what a stupid game!
How come that everybody likes me, Manon?
Judy!
Has anybody seen Judy?
Look here.
- Oh sorry, I forgot.
That's all right.
Have you lost Punch?
We're short of hands, Judy!
Would you be good enough to show me your
piece of paper?
Why?
I see... Since when do wolves try to
pass off as Onegin?
Since now.
I see you've been watching Arabella
on TV.
May I?
Sorry, Radek, we have to follow
the rules of the game.
What an idiotic game.
Sorry!
Lights out!
How about a game?
- I'm broke.
We can play for matchsticks.
What a sorry state of affairs!
Well, we could also play for
who's going to clean up the room.
Who'd bother with cleaning?
Let's play for something worthwhile.
Well, for instance, like for
who's going to offer Karda a drink.
No.
I've a better idea.
Let's play for Marika.
You've a filthy mind, Vicky.
So what?
Wouldn't it be great to make it
with Karda's daughter?
What's wrong with the idea?
That we're all running after her
is clear.
But if we step on each other's toes,
none of us will get anywhere.
Yeah,
but that's a thing you can't play for.
If we can't then we can't.
But in that case that nincompoop
of an instructor'll get her.
Okay, I'm game.
Fine.
The lowest deals.
Looks like they're playing cards.
I've always said the boys in our class
are absolutely impossible.
This is crazy.
- Absolutely impossible.
But the B Form is a different cup
of tea.
Another one.
Enough.
No ace.
Girls, di you know that Vicky wears
one pair of socks a whole months,
then he throws them away
and buys a new pair.
Who put them there?
Charles.
If you want to know I think Charles is
quite nice.
C'mon, he's always got a silly
expression...
Girls, go to sleep.
Marika, did you hear what I said?
Sleep!
Marika isn't here.
- And where's she?
Well, we thought she was with you...
Yes of course.
That's all right.
Now go to sleep.
- Yes!
Tell me, Vladimír,
where is it you live in Prague?
At Pankrác.
- I live in Krè.
That's fine, it's quite near.
What are you doing here?
I went to get a drink.
What are you wearing?
A sweater.
- So I see.
Whose sweater?
Vladimír's.
- How come Vladimír's?
I was cold so he lent it to me.
I see.
Well the next time you're cold,
come and borrow my sweater!
Yes, sir.
And its after lights out!
Okay, I'm going.
- I thought we had agreed
that you'd follow the rules
just like everybody else.
Yeah.
And what about you?
Me... I was also thirsty and...
I see.
- Well, good night.
Night...
Another one.
Enough.
No ace.
So I've won, gentlemen.
It's been my pleasure.
Mr. Hrouda!
Hello!
- What is it?
You're not heating the rooms enough.
What do'you mean?
- There's not enough heat.
We're out of coal.
What are you trying to tell me, man?
There's a big pile of coal in front of
the house.
I said we're out of coal.
There s no coal in the boiler room.
And is it such a big problem to get it
down here?
What d'you mean down here.
Who's going to get it down here?
Well, who.
You!
But I'm a stoker, not a porter.
Stoker you say?
So you'll let us freeze, right?
Sir, you're an educated person.
You must know very well that coal
doesn't have little feet.
Some beginning.
Yes, is that you?
Vladimír, there's a telephone call
for you.
For me?
- For you.
And who's calling?
I don't know.
It's a long distance call.
Hello... hello.
This is Titch.
Who's calling?
Titch speaking.
This is Prague.
One moment, please.
I'll put you through right away.
Hold the line...
May we join you?
- Why not.
We'll put Vladimír a bit to the side...
He'll be gone for a while anyway.
Some broad from Prague's calling him.
Are you speaking, *pindl?
One moment... please,
I'll make the connection immediately.
Hold on, hold on...
Mr Tits?
Not Tits, Titch...
Yes, Mr Tits.
Mr Tits, please hold onto the receiver.
One moment, I'll make the connection.
- Yes, hold on, Tits, hold on.
I don't seem to hear... hello!
Hello!
Who is it you're calling?
Will you have some tea?
Yes.
Thank you.
Careful.
It s a bit hot.
This is Prague, an urgent call.
I'll put you through.
One moment, please.
Thank you, sir.
- Not at all.
Hello, where's the call...
Hello... Hello...
Quiet!
Will everybody please listen to me.
As far as your grievances about heating
are concerned, we have a problem here.
What is it?
Karda said you're to sit with
the teachers.
Whose lousy idea's that?
- I'll wait till you've done, Vladimír.
The pile of coal which is in the yard
needs to be taken down to the boiler
room.
What d'you say boys?
But what do they have a paid stoker here
for?
Well he can't he's got a bad back.
Yeah, I know.
- No comments.
You're moaning like an old woman for
a few shovelfuls of coal.
Shovelfuls of coal are not the issue.
I just don't understand why we should
do the work someone else is paid for.
And anyway, it was not in the order
of the day.
Just what d'you mean?
Leave them alone.
Betty and I will do it if it s such
a big problem for them.
Hm.
- Listen, shouldn't we...
They're playing upon our emotions.
This is a question of principle.
Today we'll shovel some coal and
tomorrow we can cook our own breakfast
because the cooks'd like to lie in.
Aren't they cavaliers?
I think they d let us freeze to death.
Who was it called you from Prague?
You'll be surprised - Radek.
Radek?
Oh I see.
That creep of an instructor has no idea
that I won her in the card game.
This is crazy.
What the hell!
- Just look at them.
I think he's capable of chatting her up
on that lift.
If you like I can ditch the boys this
afternoon
and we can go and have some ice-cream.
An ice-cream sundae?
Sure.
Now watch hour I'm going to get that
creep down.
Just watch.
Vladimír, mind the ski pole!
What's going on?
That was elegant!
Watch out!
- Marika, watch out!
Your ski!
- My ski!
Vladimír, my ski's gone!
Gosh, what were you doing?
- Catch it!
Vicky, go!
Sure thing.
Vladimír, ouch!
Vladimír, come and have a look!
- I've done something to my leg.
Come here!
- What's wrong with it?
Ouch...!
Try to stand up.
Come on!
Ouch!
That hurts terribly.
Where?
I don't know.
I can't bend it.
Here?
- Yes, there.
It's a good think you've not lost your
boot too.
I don't see how you can think this is
funny.
Don't worry, we'll find, it.
Yes, but in three pieces.
Well at least you can screw off your
binding.
Yeah. But
what if I m not able to get new ones?
This was an original Austrian ski
for five hundred.
I was making milk deliveries all summer
to earn the money.
I hope you're not going to cry for such
a silly reason.
At least we're alone, aren't we?
- I really like that.
I lose skis costing a hell of a lot of
money
and all you're interested in is us
being here alone.
Don't get excited, Marika, I know the
ski's over there.
Oh yes, there it is.
And it's whole!
There you see.
I told you it'd turn out all right.
Well, what do I get in return?
What do I get?
Whatcher doing?
Leave me alone.
Wait, Marika, wait.
But, Marika... Marika... Marika...
- Leave me alone!
Who d'you think you are, you creep!
Every good deed must be justly punished.
Leave that sledge alone.
You should've been downstairs long ago!
Am I supposed to break my back, or what?
Those boys'll really never learn.
Just look, Betty.
I'm sure they've been shopping and have
a rucksackful of beer
and now they're
trying to get in through the back door.
As if this hadn't happened at least
twenty times during my teaching career.
But these are in a class by themselves.
The three of your, here!
- What is it?
Don't ask me what it is and come here.
What shall I do with them Betty?
What is it you have behind you?
- A rucksak.
And what d'you have in the rucksack?
Nothing.
- I see.
And why does this nothing clink like
a bottle?
Sir, that's probably because I've milk
in there.
Look, boys, I can take a lot,
but you needn't make an idiot of me.
But we're not making a... sir... of you.
- But really, sir.
An idiot... we'd never dare to make
an idiot of you.
Well then, let's see.
I'd really like to have a drink of that
milk of yours.
I'm thirsty after lunch...
- Well, as you like, sir.
Down the hatch!
Okay, girls, okay... Okay... Okay...
I liked that stunt with the milk, boys!
- Come here!
Let's make a deal.
You have trouble laying, your hands
on booze
and I have trouble with that
pile of coal under the snow there.
Why not.
Well?
It's a deal.
Hey, wait a minute.
I thought I heard somebody talk
about principles this morning.
But a bar in the boiler room that's not
a bad principle, is it?
Excuse me, sir.
Could you test my physics like you
promised?
Hm.
Oh yes.
Well, tell me... sit down...
- Thank you.
Tell me something about Newton's laws.
Yes.
Force is a basic physical quantity.
And, yes...
When Newton slept under a tree...
Come on!
And what's the definition of the first
law?
The first law?
Gosh, is that the law of action
and reaction?
Er... that is when one body acts on
another
and then as this body acts,
like the first...
...well, that's the action and this
again provokes,
in return-like and then it acts...
- Well, d'you know what?
Come again when you really know
the stuff.
The legs are in the basic downhill
posture, the knees slightly bent,
the body inclined forward and weight is
shifted onto the lower ski.
Vladimír, what is it?
I'll follow you in a moment.
- Just leave him with us.
We also want to learn, don't we?
- Of course we do.
I'm going on.
Gee, look, Marika fell!
Marika fell!
As if it'd never happened to you!
Are you all right?
Yes.
Hey, would you like to come and have
some ice-cream with me?
Who, me?
- Yes, you.
Sure...
D'you see what I see?
- Yeah.
Well, I'll be...
All right, Vladimír.
Where's your team, Vladimír?
Practising the long radius turn.
Just make sure it's not too long,
will you?
Follow me, girls!
Sir, if you're looking for the boys,
they went down there.
You know I normally take a pill,
but it always makes me sleepy.
You didn't take any sugar.
- Aha.
As I was saying it was only this time
I didn't take one
because I wanted to have a good time
and you saw what happened.
I really felt terribly sorry for you in
the bus.
I often feel terrible, Marika.
It seems to me someone here has a very
short memory.
So what?
In that case you shouldn't have played
last night.
What?
- Nothing, nothing.
Will you have a sundae?
- Just a minute.
It's my turn.
Two cups of tea and four glasses of rum.
Quiet water runs deep.
Or are you trying to tell me you're
helping me here?
What are you talking about?
- Nothing.
It's only that Mr Mácha here thinks
that winning's the same thing as losing.
Nothing really, it's only that the
gentleman here thinks
that when he draws a trumph card,
he's got it made.
The three of you again and Kardov*...
of course.
May I?
Certainly.
Well.
- Here's your order, gentlemen...
There must be some mistake,
this isn't ours.
Ts, ts, ts...
So it's one to one.
Is that clear?
Come on!
- But, Daddy, I...
I said come on!
Hurry up!
- I have to get my anorak, don't I?
As far as I'm concerned, you're a son of
a bitch.
But Vicky, I couldn't help it.
She herself...
...try to understand,
she really wants me,
you're not going to ruin everything
for me.
Let's forget about it.
This is something you can't play cards
for anyway.
Well, thank you very much.
How could you dare to do a thing like
that.
I'm listening.
- It's no use.
What's no use?
- To talk about it with you.
What d'you mean?
Because you don't intend to discuss
anything with anybody anyway.
Like with Vicky.
- Well, okay.
But I do intend to discuss things
with you.
D'you understand the situation
you've got me into, Marika?
But, Daddy, what about my situation?
- What?
D'you know what it is to be your
daughter?
Nobody here likes you,
they all make fun of you.
When I go into my room all the girls
stop talking.
Look here, Marika.
To be popular is very simple.
All you want to do is to be on equal
footing with me, but we're not equals,
because I'm responsible for you,
while you're not responsible for me.
But what makes you so sure that you're
right all the time.
Thirty years of practices experience.
But what makes you so sure
of yourselves?
I reprimand Cabadaj, Pfievrátil and Mácha
for their arbitrary absence from
the training area and the consumation
of alcoholic beverages.
This means suspended expulsion till
the end of the course.
Well.
I have to go on a trip tomorrow.
Any transgressions reported to me by
the teacher on duty
will be strictly punished.
Set the table for dinner.
Vicky, what happened there?
- Nothing worth mentioning...
Vladimír!
- Yes?
I'm not satisfied with you either.
What happened today, that was in fact
neglect of mandatory supervision.
Well, I...
- Come off it...
And would you please save all your
affections towards girl students
for a later date.
- But perhaps...
I know, I know, I know.
But I mean it, Vladimír.
And don't forget I must write
a characteristic of you.
And sweat them out on the trip tomorrow
so they blow off some steam.
Vladimír, I didn't want you to get into
trouble because of me.
That's okay.
Not to worry.
And you know, going to that tea-room was
my idea too.
You were showing off in front of
the Snowdrops as if I didn't exist.
But I didn't...
And I also wanted that sundae.
It's no use getting under his skin.
- I know.
Sulking?
Not really.
It's only that upstairs they're
preparing some idiotic programme
like last night.
You know what's interesting?
What at sixteen seems to a person
idiotic
can later apperar to be quite nice.
And vice versa.
In how many years?
- What?
Well, in how many years does this
turn-around come about?
Have a guess.
Well, you're... twenty-six?
Careful.
You must always guess less for a woman.
Under all circumstances.
Okay, eighteen?
Twenty-four.
But for that matter, it wasn't so long
ago that boys would climb
into my window to see me.
- Yeah?
But from an educational point of view
I'm strictly against it, of course.
So it's not all roses for you, either.
- Why?
You have to keep pretending...
You mean to say you don't pretend?
I'd always like to be my own person.
Really?
Then how came you're standing here just
like Vicky?
Our trail today will take us from
the Pine Chalet
through the Devil's Valley to
the Mountain Goat Chalet,
from there along the green markers
to the Crossroads Chalet,
from there up to the Shepard's Chalet
and down the downhill course
and back home along the green markers.
"I'm glad you said,, will" because that "
makes it sort of conditional.
Yes?
Is this the Big Brains' idea?
- No. I planned the trail.
So I think we should learn it by rote
in case the Big Brains wants to test us
and we can go have a drink somewhere,
can't we?
Vicky, I'm not at all interested in your
ideas.
And I also think that by the evening
you'll know the trail pretty well.
So first team, follow me!
Along the green marker?
- Along the green!
Stick to the track!
- Shit!
The track... track...
I just don't understand.
Why do such pricks always get
the best girls?
Refreshments... refreshments...
You had me thinking for a while
you were not one of us.
If anybody wants to use the bathroom,
then do so quickly...
...We're carrying on along the green
markers.
You don't mean it, do you?
- Vladimír...
We're taking a short-cut.
It's a longer route,
but the trail's much worse.
He's crazy.
- Vladimír, please
can we have at least a cup of tea?
You're soft.
That's what he's waiting for.
Hell, he wants to wear us out in front
of Marika.
Well, gentlemen, we'll have to get our
own back later.
Let's go.
At the double.
Hey, Vicky, look...
It's just the two of us here,
it's no good.
I'm not game.
Ouch!
Let me see, Marika.
- Leave me alone.
Just what d'you think you're doing?
Does it hurt, Marika?
- It's all right.
Wise guys, aren't you?
Let's get going.
We can't go down this hill!
- Yes, you can.
With cross-country skis we'll all break
our damn legs.
You've got to be kidding.
- We're not out of our minds.
I'd like to point out to you that you've
been conditionally
expeled from the course.
This is crazy,
I m not going to break my neck.
You need downhill skis for this.
- How about tobogganing it?
But I've got a bad knee!
- So let's go!
He's crazy.
- His type is worse than the Big Brains.
All chummy...
Let's go,
Marika come on!
Marika...
- Don't be silly, boys, c'mon!
This really is a tricky place,
but you did very well.
What's the matter, Charlie,
did anything happen to you?
Don't be silly.
- Are you all right?
I don't know.
- Does anything hurt?
I can't...
I simply can't...
Charlie, don't lie on the ground,
you'll catch a cold!
Fuck you!
- Come off it, Charlie!
I hate her!
I hate her so, that swollen-headed cow!
Don't be silly and get up!
- Leave me alone.
I said get up!
- I said leave me here.
Wait for me!
I've lost my cable.
Does anybody have a spare one?
- But, Vladimír,
we could've by-passed
that hill along the green markers.
It won't harm them, the wise guys!
Excuse me, Miss, we'd like to pass onto
you our complaint.
Complaint?
What about?
About instructor Tits,
excuse me Titch.
Read it out!
In the course of today's ski programme
instructor Titch purposely overestimated
the endurance and skiing skills
of the first team.
Too intensive a pace without rest caused
Vicky Cabadaj to catch a cold,
Moravec to lose his cable,
Charlie Mácha to suffer a nervous shock
and Radek Pfievrátil to break his
cross-country ski.
We therefore demand replacement
of the broken ski
and handing over the complaint
to the head of the course.
Well, Betty?
I don't know what happened there.
- But I know.
The gentlemen here expected to spend
to spend the whole trip in a bar-room
as they're accustomed to.
So they can't forgive me now
for having made it a bit rough for them,
isn't that so, Vicky?
- Don't touch me!
Vicky, stop carrying on like that,
this is asking for trouble.
Just as I thought!
When we want justice,
you say we're asking for trouble.
It's no use, nobody'll listen.
Who's for dancing?
Gee...
Make room!
What now?
Only for minimum stakes today.
Careful!
Come in!
What are you doing here,
apart from the others?
After he did this to us?
You're being silly.
Don't you really see that if you give
that complaint to Karda,
he'll consider it a provocation
and will side with Vladimír anyway.
I thought as much that it would end this
way.
But why doesn't anybody believe us?
- Yes, why?
The Big Brains is not coming back
tonight.
Oh, excuse me, Miss,
we didn't know that...
It's all right.
Come in...
May we?
- Sure.
Come in and sit down.
- Can I sit here?
Whose is it?
- Why d'you wonder that nobody
believes you?
Can't you do without booze
at least for
a little while?
It's not a question of booze.
It's the feeling of being able
to take a drink, of the -
of the freedom.
Don't you think it funny?
To speak in one breath about freedom
and booze?
Why all this fuss about booze?
We just think it's humiliating
when Karda carries on
because of one glass as if we were
little children.
But Karda can't give you permission
anyway and besides,
and besides,
you never know when to stop.
You have some opinion of us, Miss...
What d'you really think of us, Miss?
You mean seriously?
Yes.
I don't know just how to put it,
but...
...it seems to me that...
you're more interested in appearances
than in what you re actually doing.
That you're never enthusiastic about
anything
and you're not willing to put up
a fight.
Except...
maybe to jump the line for the ski lift.
But that's because we don't want
to waste time standing in a queue.
Do we?
Yes,
you want to be lifted quickly up to
the top of the hill
and then everybody goes downhill along
the beaten track.
That's not much, is it?
- Yes, but adults are no different.
I agree, but you seem to be too much
like them too soon.
This is all wrong.
You hold it against us that we are like
adults too soon.
And when we behave differently,
you simply forbid us to do so.
You hold it against us that we're not
willing to put up a fight,
but when we want to give Karda our
complaint, you're against it.
You say we wouldn't know when to stop
boozing
and so you rather won't alow allow us
to even begin.
So will you have one with us?
Just a drop?
Miss, don't be afraid we won t tell
anyone.
You know everything, anyway.
- Miss?
All right, but on condition that
there'll be no carrying on after lights
out.
Okay, it's a deal.
A little toothpaste can't harm you.
- Well, what are we going to drink to?
To have Miss be the head of the course.
- Don't wish that on me!
That would be really great.
Let's drink to this ski course!
D'you really think your father can't
return tonight?
Of course not.
He's got a friend at the Eagle Chalet
he went to see.
I'm taking a toboggan!
I've got a toboggan!
Let's go!
Everybody look at me.
This is the way they go down a glacier.
Miss, d'you want to try it too?
- Why not?
Vladimír, come too!
- Yes, coming.
Look out for the snowman!
- Marika!
What is it?
I wanted to apologize
for this afternoon.
I just don't understand how I could've...
hit you so hard...
It was nothing really.
No, I, I know that I've done it
all wrong.
I... I only want you to know that...
whenever you want you can call upon me
because I'll always be there.
Gee, it's freezing!
Let's race!
- Okay, but we start up here.
Here, quick!
- We could later...
We should be getting ready for lights
out.
Does it make so much difference?
Look here, I don't intend to go chasing
students all over the place at midnight.
Sonia, go on!
All right, let's drive them indoors.
Drive them in yourself.
You're the teacher on duty.
And I'm not going to be the bad 'un
who's always forbidding them things.
Kids!
Let's go to bed!
Lights out in a few minutes.
Stop it, you promised me you'd observe
lights out.
Radek, why don't you say something?
Let's go to bed!
Stop it!
You promised so come on!
Folks, come off it,
we have to get bed
so that our teachers get their beauty
sleep, otherwise we re in for it!
Let's get to bed!
We promised!
We'll have that race tomorrow, okay?
We're going, we're going.
- You see it can be done.
Since we made a deal...
And what about you two?
D'you intend to stay outdoors all night?
We're coming in right away.
- Well, don't forget to lock the door.
It was a lost battle from the beginning,
anyway.
I've also given up on her.
Don't be sore, but that was a silly idea
that card game of yours.
What was silly?
It was only a joke,
from the very beginning.
Sure.
- What was silly?
It was a joke.
Come in.
So boys, good night.
And I'm relying on our agreement.
- Certainly.
Sure, we're coming.
So.
Gee...
Here we are...
Wait for us.
- Sonia, hurry up!
Be quiet, Hanka's not asleep yet.
You know what they're writing in this
textbook, Betty?
No, I do not.
The ski course can best be terminated by
an optimistic yell.
And d'you know what I thought of?
Betty and I will be happy to say
good-bye!
Don't frown, d'you hear me?
There's not a creak to be heard from
them tonight.
So let's play for forfeits.
And here we have a cardigan.
Let's get going.
And who's next in line?
Sonia!
Sonia, you'll now tell us when you last
kissed a boy.
No, I won't... no, no, I won't.
In that case you have to get up and kiss
the stoker.
What?
The stoker?
No, no, not the stoker!
- Stoker! Stoker!
Does anybody want more to drink?
- No, that's okay.
The stoker in no case.
- No, no, no...
Then you have to forfeit something.
- Don't be silly.
I'm almost naked.
- C'mon, take it off!
I also had to!
- So give us the blouse!
Don't be fresh!
- Give it to me!
Just a bit more...
I've got it!
She's given up.
Not voluntarily, but she's given up.
And let's go on!
Who's next in line?
Eugen!
Stop pawing her!
I've got an excellent task for you.
Get up and stoke the boiler.
You're cold again, aren't you?
Come, I'll make you a cup of tea.
- No, no.
Why not?
We can have coffee.
I don't think I should...
- What's wrong with it?
But we don't know each other well
enough...
What d'you mean, enough?
All I want to do is make you a cup
of tea.
You'll drink it and then go to bed,
that's all.
No, Vladimír, really not.
The girls'd notice.
Good night.
- Good night.
Why don't we get on with the damned
game?
Are you listening to me?
I think I've had enough.
Look, he's spilt it all over me?
Look, Marika!
- Gee, Marika!
Hi, Marika!
- What's she doing here?
And where were you and what did you do
there?
And how is he, tell us.
- Weren't you cold outside doing it?
Girls, give me the key to our room.
I want to go to bed.
Alone?
- You want the key?
And what do we get in return?
- Have a drink, it'll soften you up.
Look here, Marika, Marika, look here,
Marika.
Wait a minute.
We're playing the truth game.
Look, either you tell us the truth...
Give me that key,
I really want to go to bed!
Don't be ashamed, tell us how it was!
Catch!
- Or you forfeit something.
Give me that key!
- Would you like...
Leave her alone.
Sex is exhausting.
I really want to go to bed.
C'mon!
Try at least a little!
She's stupid.
- Where's she going?
Let her be.
- Give it to me.
What's got into you?
- Give it to me!
Wait a minute!
Where are you going!
Wait!
D'you hear me?
Just one moment.
I hope you don't
want to give it to her free.
What is it?
It makes your mind boggle.
Vladimír, I think I'd like that cup
of tea.
Well, come in.
Come in.
What is it?
Come on!
Be quiet!
Can you hear anything?
C'mon, let's leave here.
What is it?
I'm defending the honour of fallen
women, aren't I?
Look here, Vicky, leave it alone.
That would be filthy, let it be.
Look here, I mean.
The girl's seventeen,
her father goes away and leaves her
on her own.
I won't have this on my conscience.
- You're right, Vicky, we're with you.
No, Vladimír, don't please...
- Don't be afraid.
No...
Marika...
What is it?
Bastards!
Creeps!
Novák, are you all right?
Yes, you twit!
- All right there?
He's an idiot.
Because of him I've swallowed
my chewing gum.
So get out.
What is it?
Look, somebody's lying over there.
Girls, come over here!
Hurry up!
My god, it's Charlie.
Charlie, wake up!
What's wrong with him?
But he's drunk!
Everybody be quiet!
I'm dizzy too.
He's terribly cold.
- I think we should carry him inside.
Let him be.
I don't think we should move him.
We don't know what's wrong with him.
- Shut up and take hold of him.
Stop making a racket please.
Put the light out, you idiot!
- Let's call Hanka.
Are you out of your mind?
- Well then, let's call Vladimír.
He'll only squeak to Karda.
If the teacher finds us here we'll all
get thrown out of school.
He's breathing.
What if he s really dying?
We'll have to call the mountain
emergency service or a doctor...
For chrissake, calm down!
Be quiet!
Charlie, come on, Charlie.
How much did he have to drink?
- He rank rum.
And how much?
Does anybody know how much?
That could be alcohol poisoning.
He could die of that.
My parents'll kill me for this.
They'll just kill me.
As far as I can tell all the rum's gone.
- But I only had one glass.
Save him, somebody.
- D'you hear me, Vicky, save him!
I'm going to get Hanka.
- Don't be silly, Radek.
D'you hear me, don't be silly.
- I'm going, Vicky, it's no good.
I'm telling you, don't do it.
Who knows how much Novák's had
out of that bottle.
What if it really is poisoning.
We can't help him ourselves.
- Just wait till we're clear.
Wait!
The idiot went for her.
- What?
What a nitwit!
But he's drunk!
- No, that's not possible.
And you too, aren't you?
I... I really didn't drink anything...
Well, well...
Can you explain this?
What in god's name were you doing?
How could he get into such a state?
Who's there?
Look here, young man.
I maybe pissed,
but I'm not that drunk for you to run
away without paying.
Well, Radek?
We'II... we'll pay you,
we'll really will...
"Why,, we", young man? "
You ordered, you pay up!
Five hundred and fifty net.
Service inclusive, Miss.
Who was here?
Vicky, Charlie, who else?
- Nobody.
All right, as you like.
What's the meaning of this?
- What?
Stop play-acting!
- Has anything happened?
You know that yourself best, don't you?
Why me?
Why always me?
Stop making believe that you're asleep.
You too.
Fast asleep, aren't you?
Well, everybody's fast asleep...
- What is it?
I don't know.
- What's going on?
We're normally asleep.
- Nobody knows anything.
I want to get some sleep and can't.
- Isn't that so?
Has anything happened, Miss?
- All at once, everybody was asleep.
I really don't know what's going on.
- What's the matter?
This is terrible.
They wake you up after midnight.
Isn't that so, Vicky?
- So.
And now tell me who was downstairs.
And where downstairs?
- You don't know?
What?
I'm waiting.
Am I supposed to smell your breath...?
...or d'you think I should take
fingerprints?
Don't you think this is disgusting?
Why all this fuss?
- Yes?
So all those bottles downstairs
were drunk by Radek.
Alone.
And you don't care a fig.
You agree with it?
Yes.
Okay.
In that case you pack your things
and leave for home tomorrow morning.
What's going on here?
- Nothing.
Come and help me.
- He's really going home?
Let's go to sleep.
Wait a minute.
That stoker wants
five hundred and fifty.
- What?
We don't have that much.
What is this?
A four-star hotel?
This must be at least five stars.
Am I right?
But look here I had a maximum of two
glasses.
But folks, we're not going to pay for
it all
when we've left half of it untouched.
Wait a minute,
I've got some money in my room.
This is for both of us.
Here, I'll give you this.
Is it enough?
I'm sorry I don't have any more.
Look here, Radek,
I've only got ten crowns.
Girls, what about you?
Look, Novák, poured my drinks
so let him pay for me.
I've only got twenty.
- Me too.
Let's go to sleep, everybody.
I see trouble ahead.
He has to sleep it off.
How could he have got himself into such
a state.
I don't know, but we have to put him on
his feet again, don't we?
Yes, indeed.
I'll help you with him.
Please go to bed.
And make sure you're quiet upstairs.
Didn't you hear me?
C'mon, Charlie, wake up, do'you hear me?
- How much are you short?
About two hundred.
No, that's...
- Are you sick...?
Here.
Thank you.
Marika, what is it?
Nothing,
I don't feel well.
Karda...
- Hello!
Good morning, good morning.
Hi!
- Hello!
What is it?
- Please don't ask.
- Come on, what's happened?
But the kids got hold of some booze
and Mácha got drunk.
Mácha?
In the end, Radek took all the blame
on himself and I sent him home.
These things can be dealt with in other
ways, can't they?
I've aged terribly overnight.
I've always dealt with such problems
on my own.
All right,
but what was I supposed to do?
But Betty, don't be naive.
- I know, but what d'you want to do?
Miss?
- Yes?
Miss, may I speak to you?
What is it, Mácha?
- Radek is...
What's happened?
It's just that Radek's gone.
What?
- What d'you mean, he s gone?
What nonsense is this?
I don't know.
When we woke up this morning,
we thought that he was somewhere
...and then we found that he'd packed
all his things.
He's left this for you.
We can reconcile ourselves to
what others do unto us.
It is in what we do unto ourselves
that the difficulty lies.
Attention!
- Students!
Before we begin our daily programme,
allow me a few words.
The fourth day tends to be critical
and, therefore,
please be careful of falls.
And Bob's your uncle!
Dismissed!