Èeskoslovenskı Filmexport
THREE WISHES FOR
CINDERELLA
based on the version by
wri tten by
Starring
Featuring
You put that back!
Of course...
Cinderella!
And the King here
any minute!
Hurry up,
you slow-coaches!
Assistant Director
Cameraman
Continui ty
Assistants to Head
of Production
Assistant Set Designer
Wai t!
Costume Designs
Wardrobe
Make-up
Properties
Let go!
Music by
Played by
Conducted
Song sing by
Lyrics
Come on,
get a move on...
Film Edi tor
Sound Edi tor
Everything at the last minute.
Set Designer
Special Adviser
Head of Production Team
Don' t soil your slippers,
and mind
you don' t catch cold!
Director of Photography
Come along...
Pick i t up and get out!
I don' t know why I keep you!
Directed by
Had a feast, Silly-Billy?
Made by the Barrandov Film Studios
in co-production wi th
the DEFA Acted Film Studios,
Postdam - Babelsberg
Processed at
the Prague Film Laboratories
I ' ve brought you something
for your sveet tooth.
English sub-ti tles by
Doris Koíšková
It ' s only three years
since daddy gave you to me!
I ' d just love to take you
on a ride again,
but you know ve mustn' t.
Such goings-on,
they ' re expecting the King...
I ' II come again
when I ' ve finished my work.
Bailiff!
Are they coming?
Not a soul to be seen, madam!
Come and tell me as soon as
they appear below the forest!
Cinderella again, I bet!
You' II be the death of me,
silly fool!
Pick i t up, quick...
Who did i t?
The dish was cracked anyway, m ' am...
You' re not answering
my question!
It was I, mother,
please forgive me!
Yes, m ' am?
Everything ready?
The meat, yes...
Chicken, wine, frui t...
Yes, madam, everything.
To please such guests
is qui te a problem.
So see you don' t spoil
anything.
I really don' t know
if you' re so clumsy
or if you do i t on purpose.
Some legacy your father left
me in you...
Like father like...
You leave daddy alone!
He ' s left you the whole farm,
the forest and the mill
How dare you speak to me
like that!
Did you hear?
Kindly remember:
Gone are the times your father
took you to the forest,
riding and shooting
like a boy!
I am the mistress here now...
And keep away from that horse!
Here!
Pick them apart by lunch-time
and then come and apologize!
I ' II bring you down
a peg or two!
And woe betide you
if I catch sight of you
when the King is here!
Don' t get all upset,
that ' s just grimy Cinderella!
Thanks, Cinderella...
I ' II help you!
And leave me here alone?
Well, my girl, a step-mother is
always a step-mother...
But her Dora wasn' t Daddy ' s,
and he loved her!
Dear friends...
The peas onto the basket,
the ashes into the pail...
...how good of you!
Looking for a lick, Pussy?
No, you can' t go in now!
Can you manage than much?
Of cour_rrr_rse you can!
The gentry not arrived yet, Cinderella?
How did you know i t is I?
I didn' t, but Jurášek did.
Knows you a mile off...
Why aren' t you watching out
for royalty wi th the others?
I ' m not to...
And I prefer being here anyway.
Not even curious to see the Prince?
I saw him last year...
When they stopped on the way
to the castle.
And did you like him?
Jurášek is my favouri te...
They ' re coming!
Here they are!
Be good, children!
Everything all right, Dora dear?
Mind you show me the Prince!
Where are you off to, Silly-Billy?
You li ttle poacher!
Go and welcome the King!
You know ve can' t go hunting any more!
Jurášek and I ' II be right
back, sorun along!
Rosie!
Looking after my treasures?!
Jurášek is calling me...
We have so li ttle time, you see!
Quickly...
Bow low, and don' t forget-smile!
All the time!
Where is the Prince, tutor?
And Kamil and Ví tek?
I don' t know, your Highness.
I was giving them a lecture
on elegant manners,
and in the forest
the gentleman disappeared...
Find them!
A strict reprimand!
No, l"ll see to that myself!
Wai t!
But you' re such
a renowned shot, Prince?!
Look...
Follow her...
This way...
Where ' s the trail?
There!
Highness, you from the left,
and you from the right!
Look, we ' ve got her!
Is that her?
There ' s none other here!
This is just a bi t of a girl!
A mere kid!
A fluffy chicken...
A purring ki tten...
But I say, It ' s got claws!
Need a spanking, if you ask me!
Or whipping wi th a nettle!
When the cows come home
...ni twi ts!
I say... now we ' II show you,
you cheeky kid!
You' d fight a bi t of a girl?
You, such a he-man?!
What are you up to?
Jump off, he ' II throw you!
She ' II break her neck!
She ' II come to a bad end.
Even your stable-boy ' s
scared of your Dapples!
Crazy girl...
We must find her...
Go back to your master!
He obeyed like a lamb!
The wildcat!
She ' d deserve...
A medal, gentlemen!
For putting one over on us!
Your Highness...
Don' t do this to me!
Your studies, Highness!
I can hardly express
how we looked forward
to your coming -
and her Highness the Queen
and also his Highness, the Prince...
and the whole entourage, and so on.
We thank you.
Dear Dora her could hardly sleep...
The Prince is not wi th you this time?
Oh yes...
Nature studies have detained
him on the way...
Pi ty...
All year we looked forward
to your stopping here
on the way to the castle.
I even had a dream...
that your royal Highness
invi ted us to the ball...
Dora and myself...
That your Highness smiled
at Dora and said:
Do come, my dear,
we shall be pleased to see you.
We shall be pleased to see you.
Our pleasure...
Thank you for the refreshment.
Yes, yes...
On our way!
This is an inexpressible honour for us!
That ' s in the bag...
And who knows, amongst all
those noblemen
someone might notice you...
Maybe even the Prince himself!
Why not?
Carrying on like a li ttle boy!
At your age I was...
...carrying the burdens
of a ruler!
You' II come down a peg or two
when we get you married!
That ' s tamed other rebels!
I honour your experience...
Hadn' t we better talk this over at home?
I hoped you would devote yourselves
to the study of diplomacy and
court etiquette...
We try not to waste a minute!
But studies are a demanding business!
Where have you left your tutor?
He must have wandered off again...
The frivolous...
Stop!
Are those just threats
or does he really want me to marry?
This time he really means i t.
A roll of fine line, gold thread,
velvet, thirty ells, in dark blue...
I don' t want velvet,
I want satin!
The velvet is for me, Dora.
And forty ells of the best
satin in sky blue.
That ' s not enough.
Get fifty, then.
Oh, and wide gold braid.
And silver buckles for my
slippers!
Tell the dressmaker you' II
fetch her day after tomorrow.
Don' t forget anything!
Yes... no...
Cinderella, you' II freeze!
Did the mistress make you...
Who else?
And what shall I get you in town?
A tiara and pearls and
a robe wi th a train!
I can just see them both persuading me
to go to the ball wi th them...
Surely you wouldn' t cry for that...
If I could, I ' d bring you
whatever you wished...
Honestly, I would...
Well then bring me the first thing,
that hi ts you on the nose!
All right, then!
The Lady at emlov accepted
our invi tation?
Indeed, the messenger has just arrived!
And the Princess of Romberk?
Defini tely coming wi th both daughters,
Miss Liza and Miss Loulou.
The younger one ' s
at least thirty!
She is a year younger
than you, and very sweet!
Which you are not!
And the Baron' s widow
from Krásná H rka?
_
She promised to bring
all three daughters.
I thought It was to be a ball,
but this looks more like a man-hunt!
Your impertinence is unseemly!
I apologize for my frankness,
but I was brought up to speak
the truth.
May I leave?
You' II first hear me out!
I had no idea the family
council would take so long.
The tutor and my friends
are wai ting,
may I dismiss them?
What was so important...?
We were to study history...
then I was to have suffered
a lesson in etiquette and
wi tty conversation...
History? Conversation?
Aren' t you shooting fun of me?
Shoot-fun-how could I?
Here you are...
Horses away...!
Why the cross-bows, then?
Call that study?
Of course he doesn' t want to
marry,
fooling round on a horse
all day wi th cross bows!
Horse and cross-bows?
How' s that?
Come and see!
Gentlemen, I ' m responsible
for you,
your studies,
state interests
I don' t understand...
Don' t forget to practice
dance-steps,
so you don' t
cut a sorry figure!
Remember, I at your age...
...danced through three pairs
of slippers at a ball!
Really?
Before we mer, of course...
But you apologized that
i t was the first time
you were dancing,
when you trod on my feet.
That is nothing to brag of to a son...
My dear, he takes after you...
in all the important things!
No!
Yes!
After the dancing lesson,
some conversation!
Ah, conversation...
Your Highness,
I have decided, that you will ask for
my hand in marriage.
Do you agree?
No, my beautiful Countess.
I honour your ancien family
and your great beauty,
but my heart belongs forever
to hunting, shooting and riding.
So the wedding-is no go.
Or as the poet says:
No rain from that cloud!
Or as that kid said:
When the cows come home!
Look...
Gentlemen!
We ' re off!
What about your studies?!
My dear girl,
I nearly forgot!
Like a spider ' s web...
Stand back...
turn round!
And you hurry!
Look, Cinderella,
they hi t the tip of my nose
just as I dreamt
I was off to your wedding...
What did you give her?
Show me!
Some present!
For a squirrel!
The bodice...
Mummy, you forgot the lace!
And a new necklace!
And rings!
Mumy, you can' t send
a man-servant for jewellery!
That ' s true...
We ' II go to town ourselves.
Yes, M' am.
Have the horse put to
the buggy!
Would you like to come to
town wi th us, Cinderella?
You' d only scare people off!
Stop staring!
Sveep up properly!
I said properly, understand?
Stop that at once!
Be a good boy...
Wai t here, I ' II go and see Rosie...
You lucky thing,
flying where you want to...
I ' d so like to see where he goes...
But how can I, like this?
All this is mine?
Don' t be afraid of me!
This was all inside the nut!
Ho do I look, Silly-Billy?
The first shot!
There, now a bird of prey
and your Highness is
the King of the Hunt!
The King awards this
precious ring
to the huntsman who first
shoots down a bird of prey!
First shot!
Second shot!
Third!
Your turn, Prince!
Too high
Whose arrow is ti?
Highness!
Forgive me...
Who are you?
I thought you do not want to fire...!
Qui te an ordinary one.
Do we continue wi th the hunt?
The best marksman has shown
us his art -
the ring!
It is yours by rights!
Or can you do better still?
I am sorry that you are cross...
Do you see those cones at the tip?
Would you dare?
Here any bi t of a girl can do that.
My horse!
Did a young hunter go this way?
Why?
Did he or did he not?
No, far and wide nothing but
a fluffy ki tten,
a cheeky kid!
Come on down!
You come up!
We ' ve met before, haven' t we?
You' d have to remind me where!
Here in the wood, you li ttle lizzard!
You won' t escape today!
Where is he?
Where?
She ' II tell us!
Where ' s she gone to?
Who?
That bi t of a girl,
I was talking to her just now...
Pass the buttons, Cinderella!
Cinderella, the silver thread!
Cinderella, the necklace!
Come on!
I want the carpet out,
right up to the sleigh!
Yes, m ' am.
Well?
Lovely...
Just beautiful, Dora dear...
My hat!
Would you like to come
wi th us to the ball?
Say, would you?
I know you wouldn' t take me inside.
But could I just have a peep...
through the window?
And who ' II do the cleaning here?
I ' d get i t all done by morning.
If you haven' t enough to do
...there!
I want i t all gone
when we ' re back!
The lentils picked
from the corn!
I ' II tell you
how many times I danced
wi th the Prince!
Hold my train!
You' d better hold i t yourself.
I could soil i t.
Don' t be sad,
I ' II dance wi th you after supper.
You go and get us something to eat!
Your word is my command, Highness!
You' re sorry you can' t go, aren' t you?
I know...
But I can' t help you.
It ' II take me a week to pick
these apart...
...you' ve come to help me?
The corn into the basket,
lentils into the bowl!
What would I have done wi thout you.
Thank you!
Daddy always laughed that
I ' d ride to my first ball
on Jurášek, like a Hussar.
And my mummy promised me
a pretty dress,
as pink as
the red evening sky...
And all that ' s left to me is
Jurášek...
No, I have lots of other things...
three magic hazel-nuts...
no, only two...
Rosie, do you think...?
How did you get here,
and who saddled you?
The noble Lady of the Black
Forest, wi th daughter...
Baroness of Shortwood
wi th grand-daughter...
Lady of emlov
wi th daughters...
Don' t look so sour!
Smile!
I ' d like to know which one
you' d be smiling at,
if you had to marry her.
Dad, let ' s postpone i t for a year...
Listen to him!
And this is to be my successor!
Do choose a more convenient
time for quarrelling!
Did you notice how he smiled at you?
I made no such fuss
when I got married!
But you married mummy...
and you force strange girls onto me...
The noble Lady of Gotham wi th niece...
You' d better give rein
to your temperament on the dance-floor.
I don' t care,
you point to one, I ' II ask her...
His Highness now asks you
to start the dance.
Music!
Come on, that ' s impoli te!
Look, that pretty blonde
wi th the blue train...
Or the brunette in yellow...
How can I choose!
I ' II choose blindly!
Clumsy girl, you' re so slow!
May I have the pleasure?
I knew nothing of
the Prince ' s taste, i t seems.
Li ttle bird,
where is your nest?
Beware of traps
where you rest...
Lean down, dear whi te birch,
enfold the scared li ttle bird,
so I can go in peace...
Did you come from afar?
The distance was no greater
than my longing to dance
wi th your Highness!
In spi te of my treading
on your toes?
That is an hour for me, Highness.
I would dance wi th you
till the end of the world.
What courage!
I can land you as much as you like!
I don' t make debts, young lady!
You think I should go in?
Shall I, shall I not,
shall I, shall I not...
I shall...
Well, I ' II give i t a try...
Don' t be cross, I ' m going!
Mind out!
Have pi ty on him!
Let him stew a bi t.
Out of breath?
I ' II have them play something faster.
Have them play what you like!
I ' ve finished dancing!
Go back and dance!
I ' d rather fell trees!
All right, start at once!
As you like!
Good evening, your Highness!
Thank you for a wonderful welcome!
I... you see...
I ' m sorry, you surprised me...
I thought you were
running out to meet me...
No, I was just running out...
In that case I shan' t keep you...
But I don' t want to any longer...
May I have the pleasure?
Wouldn' t i t go better wi th music?
Why aren' t they playing?
Who are you?
Do you want to question me,
or to dance?
Who can i t be?
Maybe she ' II tall...
Our boy forgot all about
the trees he wanted to fell!
Look how graceful she is!
Shall I ask her up?
Let her dance a while...
Wi th that clumsy boy of ours?
You may be surprised!
Do you know who i t is?
I don' t...
Why doesn' t she take that veil off?
Probably hiding a big nose!
Take off that veil, then!
Is this my son?
He is only doing what you asked...
But who is she?
You are more impatient than your son.
At least give me a hint!
Why do you want to know?
Because I have just chosen a bride
and I know not who she is...
Not so loud, they are listening!
Let them hear!
I ' II call right out into the world...
that I ' m in love...
and getting married...!
But you forgot something!
What?
To ask the bride if she wants you!
You' d give me the mi tten?
A bi t of cheek, what?
Will you have me, or not?
I ' II give you a riddle,
and if you guess...
First time: Face smuged wi th ashes,
but i t ' s no huntsman?
What on earth...
Calm down, you' II find out...
Third time:
A dress embroidered in silver,
but she ' s not a Princess!
Well, that...
Pi ty...
Until you know the answer
to my riddle -
Goodbye!
What happened?
Why did she run off?
What if he ' s fallen in love?
That was your wish.
Wi thout my permission?
I ' d like to see that!
You didn' t obey your parents ei ther,
and brought me home, my love...
Why aren' t they playing?
Play!
Music, please!
Get the horses, quickly!
Open up!
Come on, open up!
What ' s wrong?
Open up!
We have not come in enmi ty...
Why, then?
Who is the master of this house?
No master-a mistress!
But she ' s at the Palace ball
wi th her daughter!
Staring like an owl -
let him say what he wants!
That beautiful Princess!
Princess?
Here?
She rode in a moment before me!
Let him find his Princess, then!
I don' t know if she ' s a Princess,
but she is beautiful...
and somewhere here I lost her!
We have droves of beauties here Sir!
Just to choose the right one!
Come and make your choice,
you tenderfoot!
Or get out of here!
That ' s not bad advice, your Highness!
Let ' s wai t till daybreak!
Mornings make for wiser decisions!
What now-at night!
No, I must find her!
I want to see all the girls
of this farmstead!
By what right, Sir?
It ' s the Prince!
Oh, the Prince... Your Highness...
Every single girl!
Here they are, your Highness!
Now I wonder what you' II do!
She had a veil...
...a rose-pink dress!
Stop!
What ' s he doing here?
Looking for someone.
...you don' t know her face...
...nor her name...
I ' II recognize her by the slipper...
The girl whom this slipper fi ts
will be my wife!
Your foot!
Next!
That ' s too small even for a doll...
Leave off, you silly fool!
Have they all tried i t on?
There ' s one more here!
You dupe...
Is there really no one other here?
Of course there is,
your Highness - Cinderella!
Yes, Cinderella!
Why hasn' t she shown up?
Where can she be?
I haven' t seen her all evening!
Cinderella!
She had to pick the corn
from the lentils!
We must find her!
Cinderella!
Come!
Wai t here!
Take that rope!
What for?
Do you think she ' s in there?
Ah, here you are!
Cinderella!
She isn' t here, ei ther...
Cinderella, where are you?!
Unsaddle him and rub him down!
Your Highness!
Halt!
So i t wasn' t a vain search!
I shan' t let you go now!
Why did you come here?
To find her!
Why did you search for her?
To ask her to marry me!
What prevents you from doing so?
Unveil her face!
Why?
So I know her!
She is dressed just as at the ball...
the dress, tiara, veil...
Why does she not speak?
After you put a ring on her finger!
Let her try the slipper on!
Let her try the slipper!
Why won' t she try on
her own slipper?
She is shy!
Do you want to marry her or not?
After she ' s tried on the slipper!
Drive off!
He ' II follow us, you' II see.
In the end he ' II do as I want!
Help me!
Catch hold of my hand...
You are not my bride!
Help me out, Bailiff...
This will be my...
I ' m coming, m ' am!
Do you see anything?
There ' s something in there...
She can' t have disappeared...
Do you hear...?
Cinderella!
Rosie, where have you been?
But this is the last one...
But this is... a wedding dress...
Well?
We should go back...
They ' II be worried at the palace...
Your Highness, look!
That is she!
Go on, then...
Go on!
Have you brought my slipper?
I should return the ring
for the King of the Hunt...
But i t belongs to you!
So now you know the answer
to my riddle?
Face smudged wi th ashes,
but i t ' s no chimney-sweep?
That day in the wood,
that bi t of a girl!
Hat wi th a feather
and cross-bow, but i t ' s not hunstman?
That li ttle sharpshooter
was you, too!
Dress embroidered in silver,
but she ' s no Princess
who is i t?
Our Cinderella!
And mine, too...
If you want me?
And there ' II be a wedding...
Li ttle bird, where is your nest?
Where is your nest?
Beware of traps
where you rest...
Lean down, dear whi te birch,
enfold the scared li ttle bird,
so I can go in peace...
Your Highness,
history lesson is about to begin!
Li ttle bird, where is your nest?
Where tonight will you rest?
When snow covers the fields, my maid -
alone I would be afraid!
Lean down, dear whi te birch,
enfold the li ttle bird,
so I can go in peace...
The End