MY SWEET LITTLE VILLAGE
Directed by
Written by Scrip Editor
Starring
English subtitle by Eva Roubalova
You're trotting about like goat.
Missed it up again, doctor?
- Like hell I have.
- Finished - start her up.
- Thanks.
Good morning.
Let's start feet together,
arms extended,
palms up.
Raise you arms...
- Washed your feet?
I can tell.
Makes a difference for the driver.
What about the ears?
You always forget something.
Those sails must not be neglected.
Yesterday's load was cement.
If it rains,
concrete'll set behind you ears.
They'll have to chisel it off.
You should've been born a horse.
But the Lord changed his mind.
Beneath him the beautiful distant places
lie,
round which the mountains darkly rise.
By woods encircled all around.
Amidst the flower-spattered ground.
The bright lake sleeps in slumber sound.
The waters rippling
to its shores're striving to meet.
Until at last
they marge in one luminous sheet.
Only the turtle-dove does not coo forth
its call to love anymore.
Don't shit yourself, cardboard dude!
Take these for your ears.
If you wear them, the ears'll stick
to your head beautifully.
A pine grove rustles on the lake's
still shore,
Whence glorious psalm of speckled thrush
ascends.
A portly tree stands on the rock -
an old eak.
Through the green vale scattering
the blossoms white,
Guding the wild geese over the woods
in flight.
Aren't you cold?
- I am, but nobody wants to warm me up.
- Why dodn't you say something?
- You're a right one, eh?
You're all smoke and no fire.
See you.
Living it up, eh?
- I wish!
My wife had a boy yesterday.
We celebrated a little.
- Are redheads celebrated too?
I'm surprised.
- What's up?
- A little celebration.
Celebrate, with your work!
- Your mate!
- I didn't see him over there.
- Look at him!
Look at the nitwit!
That... that...
If it was stone, you'd've been dead!
You...
An animal has more brains!
You oaf!
Gone's the furor of that Age
which Time bore far away.
Far-far off even its dream -
as a shadow did it fade,
As the image of white citiens
in the waters'depths arrayed,
As the last thoughts of the dead,
The names that once they bore,
The roll and roar of battle...
That's all I remember.
Feasting on the beauty again, eh?
- I wonder of she has brakes at all?
- Get the rope.
The rope!
You'll come to a bad end, doctor.
- We all will.
The gate-post was one week old.
It cost me 500.
I'm through with Rakosnik.
Take it from me -
Iet someone else have the pleasure.
- I know it's not easy for you.
But who should I entrust him to?
- I don't care!
I've had this millstone around my neck
for 5 years!
A saint youldn't put up with it!
- I know how you feel.
But who should I entrust him to?
Duda's too young.
Can I entrust him
to your husband?
- He'd kill him.
He's terribly badtempered.
- It'd serve him right!
- Have you really
flattened the Prague weekender'fence?
- Come on...
You know that...
The boy needs a father's touch.
You've got it.
You can handle him
and he listens to you.
- Nothing doing -
let me have Sestak back.
A moron too, but at least he can sing.
Nobody's truck's as clean as yours.
You can't take that away from Otik.
- Till the hervest's over,
not a minute longer.
There you are.
Here I am.
Been waiting long?
They delivered the meat.
- Who gave them to you?
- Mr. Pavek.
They say he was mad with rage.
He doesn't want you anymore.
The'll hand you over to someone else.
He was fuming.
You'll be Turek's mate - I guess.
You' Il have a hard time!
I've brought you some shirts and socks.
You've nothing to wear.
And don't think,
Turek's not going to baby you.
You know.
I'll bring the rest tomorrow -
was too busy to wash them.
Turek's been known to hit his mates.
What's this?
Where's it from?
Come here, Otik!
Did you have woman here?
Come on.
Come.
Swear -
by the picture of your poor late
parents: Did you have woman here?
Look into my eyes:
Yes or no?
O.K., let's go and wash up.
Don't go into the front parlour
too often - it gets untidy easily.
Clear the mess of the table yourself,
after we've washed up.
Why don't you take off this finery?
Let me do it for you.
That's better.
C'mon -
I haven't got much time.
Come on.
A man, and he can't break
a pigeon's neck.
And a pigeon breeder to boot!
Dash it, I forgot
what I wanted to tell you!
It can wait though, I'll tel you later.
The laundry's done.
I'll bring the bedclothes afterwards.
The rabbit and dumplings're in the oven.
Warm them up properly.
Otik!
A superb film - Rumanian.
Have you got a ticket?
No.
You must see it.
Where have I...?
Here.
Good thing I've bought it for you.
Don't miss the newsreel.
Put you suit on, quick.
Let's go.
It's partly travel,
partly erotic.
I'd like to see it once more,
but I must go to a lecture on livestock
instead.
My old box's out of order.
A bad tube, I guess.
Otas!
In no case leave before the film's over!
The end's the best.
Enjoy yourself.
Mrs. Hruskova!
What's it like?
- They nearly cancelled it.
All told, I sold six tickets.
- Jo?
Aha.
Bye then.
What am I picking?
- Nettles, for the Easter stuffing.
- But I don't use that much.
- Is the film showing?
- Yes, but it was nearly cancelled.
- How come?
I myself sent six people.
- They all came.
Vasku.
This'll give me herpes again.
- You beast!
- I couldn't wait to be with you...
Don't be scared, Sonia.
Don't worry.
Just have a bang, Eugene!
- Mind you graves, raven.
Driving forward's easy,
but you got to have a knack for backing.
- Dinner's ready, Dad.
Dad, they say
you bumped into Mr. Rumlena's gate-post.
It isn's true, is it?
- Just eat and mind your own business.
Can't eat with all this singing.
Isn't it enough
to live next to the cemetery?
Of you can't sing anything else,
at least cut it out while we eat.
It's like chewing wreaths.
- Actually,
it's quite a wreck.
We went to look.
- So what?
So what?
- Good evening -
night, rather.
- Goodbye.
Well, see you.
Tuesday at nine then.
- Yes.
Let's go!
- Good night.
- Bring the rum.
- Sure.
- Why the rush?
- It's a PTA meeting tonight.
You must go, I can't.
Didn't get my hair done.
- To school?
- You go...
- I don't mind going.
They should all have their own towels.
Keep an eye on their homework.
That's all for now, thank you.
Good-bye.
- Good-bye.
Make sure they dress properly.
Otherwise, I'm quite satisfied.
Good-bye.
- Good-bye.
What's the matter?
- What about her writing.
- All right.
It's neat.
- I see.
Gotta any problems?
- Got.
She has problems with pronouns.
Practise them with her.
Personal pronouns in particular.
- Pronouns in particular.
- I see.
Thanks then.
How d'you like it here?
- Quite, I hope I'll get used...
- What's keeping you?
- I'm just going.
- When'll the next PTA meeting be?
- In 3 months.
- Hm.
Good-bye then.
- Good-bye.
They say you ruined
the wekender's gate-post.
Is it true?
- Gate-post?
The whole shed, including the roof!
- Good Lord!
I've no mate, man.
He's either on strike,
or has hanged himself.
Shut up, you beast!
Otik, get up.
You_l have lovely ears, but no money.
Get up, we're going for cement.
Water levels:
Brandys nad Labem 146/60,
Melnik 252/115,
Usti nad Labem 180/144,
Decin 175/171,
Orlice-Tyniste nad Orlici 92/10.
Still waiting for you to warm me up.
- It'll happen one day.
Don't eavesdrop - you a spy or what?
Don't forget the meeting.
- Will you watch my back for me?
- What's your mate good for?
- Nothing.
- Put it here.
- No jo.
- You brought fodder?
- Yeah.
- From Kolin?
- A mix?
- Yeah.
NO SMOKING
That's not very clever.
- What?
- Putting used matches
back into the box.
- Why?
- You'll see one day.
Mr. Pavek,
I don't want to work with Turek.
- You didn't appreciate me.
When the harvest's over,
you'll join Turek.
- Me?
When the rake starts flowering.
- Take a look at it at home.
It may be budding.
- When the harvest's over, it's Turek.
What is it, Otik?
Look - Otik brought you this.
He likes you, poor thing.
He doesn't know how to tell you.
You should forgive him.
When the pressure falls before a storm,
I feel wiped out.
- So do I - what's next?
- Varicose veins.
- Look at mine.
- D'you wear elastic stockings?
- I do.
- D'you take Anavenol?
- That's it then.
Go on.
- I'm serving beer.
Someone asks for the bill.
I turn my head and it won't go back.
- Can you turn the whole body,
like this?
- Sure.
- Turn the whole body then.
Go on.
- I can't sleep.
I wake up at four
and I can't go back to sleep.
- Commonplace at this age.
I'm wakeful from half past three.
What's next?
- My joints.
Sometimes I can hardly get up.
- But you do?
- In the end, because, I have to.
- Why complain then?
There're people who can't at all.
- Doctor, you make light of everything.
I know best how I feel.
I'm not going to be here much longer.
- D'you want spa treatment?
- No, it didn't do me any good.
- Close down the pub
and go to the sea then.
- I went the year before last.
It gives me the runs.
- Go to the High Tatra then.
- I can't stand heights.
- You know where to go then?
Go to Pelhrimov
and have a look at the cramtorium -
so you know what it's like there.
Yeah?
Next!
Dear comrade, with reference
to the demanding plan targets...
- A lovely ship!
Where did you get if from?
- The boy made it.
...in the interest
of producer-end-user relations,
our organization needs a driver's mate.
- Your Honza?
- Ships're his hobby.
We'd like to make use of the extensive
experience of your employee,
comrade Rakosnik.
We have offered him a company flat
on a housing estate in Prague
and he has accepted.
METALWOOD, perschnel dept., Koutna.
- Expect Otik going to Prague
to save the producer-end-user-relations?
- Something like it.
What have you to say?
- Me - I'm through with him.
What is there for me to say?
- That's just it.
- What's just it?
- Can you imagine the boy
going to Prague?
Can you just imagine it?
He gets lost in the streets.
All the houses're the same
on the housing estate.
No one to turn to.
That match's not a good idea, Jaromir!
Terrible to think of our Otik stopping
Prague traffic.
to let a truck back in somewhere.
- I prefer not to.
- This letter...
This is the last time you to this!
tohle bylo naposledy.
What's the big idea?
That I'd be carrying on with her,
at my age?
Another raid like this and you're fired!
This'll give me a stroke!
Co je?
- Just came in to ask who'll pick
the kid up from kindergarten.
- Granny, as always.
- That's what I wanted to know.
- He needs treatment.
That's not normal.
- Sorry.
- This letter did not write itself.
Sure - someone must've written it.
- That's just it.
- You look as if I'd written it myself.
- You didn't - some Koutna woman
wrote it, personnel dept.
But someone must've told them
about Otik, eh?
With my common sense,
it's easy to work out
- Now I see,
- who in this village'd benefit...
- I see.
You think then I fixed it up in Prague...
- I didn't say that.
I'm just asking.
- For 5 years, I've been chained to him.
Taught him to use knife and fork,
to wash, so that he wouldn't fall
under my wheels.
...Iike he was my own son...
...now they'll suspect me!
Don't take it too seriously, dad.
- Cut it out!
Dancing - when a funeral's on!
Get down!
- Silence please - a funeral's on!
- Mind your business - graveyrad bully!
You're behaving like a ruffion.
Good morning, doctor.
How convenient
to live by the burial pit, eh?
- 'morning.
- Shine on me the sun...
- And music as well!
The boy'll perish in Prague
within a week.
It's either a crazy idea, or a set-up.
What's it look like on the 7th step?
- They're there.
- How are you?
- Fine, but from the dizziness.
- As you get up?
- Yes.
In the morning, sit up in bed first,
stay like that for some time,
get up carefully.
- Ano.
- Have you still fot the pills?
- Yes.
- Fajn.
What gave you the idea that
the 7th step'd give it
the right temperature?
- Longterm trials.
It's warm on the 6th,
too cold on the 8th.
- I see.
- Karel likes experimenting, eh?
He's fond of trials.
- Good morning, doctor.
- 'morning.
- How did it go for him?
- He had a beautiful funeral.
Give me a drink, just a drop.
What a lovely day!
- It's so fresh!
Such moments should be remembered,
to fall back on.
To warm you up in winter.
- Look!
Such beauties're becoming rarer,
but there's still something left.
Some woodland, beer's good...
...sometimes...
- I'll fetch the plates.
- And the girls, Karel,
our girls're the most beautiful
in the world.
The Spanish or Italian women can't match
up - they mostly have goat-like legs.
Did you notice how many girls
walk about braless?
- I did.
- Nice fashion, eh?
- Yeah.
- I'm glad it's spread
as far as our village.
- This gravestone artist's a pain.
Fanda -
your diligence's getting on my nerves.
- Tool busy, doctor.
Many cadavers, few engravers.
- Come and wash away the dust.
Where did we leave off?
- That they walk about braless.
- Yeah, looks like
we're not going to conclude it.
- Anything special you're busy with?
- An interesting gravestone -
with no inscription.
It'll be added on when the person dies.
- Did he place an advance order
for a tomb?
- Yeah.
- Who is it?
- I mustn't tell.
- People don't know what to do
with money.
He's got a house, TV, car.
What is there I haven't got, he asks?
A tomb.
Hi.
- Hi.
Your guardian angel's having
a hell of a job.
- The madguard needs replacing, I guess?
- No use, unless you got a rubber one.
Jesus!
In days past,
Czechs were strong and steadfast,
"they were, for the eyes, a repast."
Missing your old school?
- I've come to ask
how my sister's doing.
- I see. Going to sit
for your finals, aren't you?
- Yes.
- What'll you do afterwards?
- Go to a dung college, er -
School of Agriculture.
- I'll keep my fingers crossed for you -
don't let the side down!
- I drilled the pronouns with her -
was it any good, I wonder?
Like she din't botch up her dictation
again?
Shal I carry your bag?
- Yes.
Unusual - a brother so interested
in his sister's progress.
- Our parents're too busy.
It's up to me then.
- Hm.
- It's excercise-books, eh?
- Yes, exercise-books.
- What're you laughing at?
- Nothing.
How you're chatting me up through
your sister.
- I'm a nuisance, eh?
- Why?
You should concentrate on your studies
now -
and don't try to sweep older girls
off their feet.
Aunt, are there rooms to let?
- Are you my nephew?
Funny thing, I don't know you!
- Okay,
so how about some accommodation?
- The village's changed, young man.
We don't address each other
as Aunt and Uncle.
We use our first names
and 'comrade'instead.
I wouldn't insist on that.
The customs have changed, though.
Like when a man addresses a lady:
he stands up first and greets her.
- Okay then.
I wish you good morning.
Permit me to ask you:
what about some abode, ma'am?
- C'mon then.
- Do your customs allow a man to walk
behind a lady, or next to her?
- He may walk next to her,
of he can keep up.
Hi.
- Ahoj.
- How's life?
- Not bad.
- Yeah.
Oh, well.
Look where you're going,
or you'll trip up.
- Take it easy.
- Shut up and clear off!
Why're you out here with next
to nothing on?
- It's warm, isn't it?
- How come that milkso's so familiar?
- We've always been on first name terms!
- Interesting!
Where's the kid?
- With Granny.
- Interesting!
- You find everything interesting.
- I'm not a moron.
- She always goes to Granny
from kindergarten.
You never found that interesting before.
If this goes on, I'll do the same.
That'll make it even more interesting.
- Let's go for a swim.
It'll be empty now.
- I can't go into the water today.
- You can watch me then.
You time me.
Now!
- Jesus Vasek, don't be a fool!
Don't, Pepik's here!
Thirty-three!
- Too bad.
Go on!
- How long?
- About half a minute.
Please, go away.
- We've plenty of time.
- Just a carp.
Thirty-seven!
- Not bad, eh?
D'you know how long Sestak can hold out?
Twenty-six, a non-smoker!
- I was wrong - thirty-one!
- Impossible!
- Thirty-one!
- Watch it, then!
- Otik's place tonight, right?
- Forty-two!
- No!
Fine!
I've changed the bedclothes for you.
It'll be like in a hotel.
- Thanks, lady.
- He'll stay with Otik.
At least Otik'll not be so lonely.
It'll be for the better.
D'you have to paint the fence so shabby?
- You find it shabby?
- I told you
I was going to put in new planks.
This way, they look as if they were
in pieces.
- I paint them the way the are.
- Can't you imagine a repired fence?
- It looks better this way, doesn't it?
- What about the pealing plaster?
Is that supposed to look better?
- Don't meddle with it, Hrabetova!
What d'you charge for such a painting?
- Want to buy it?
- No,
I want you to paint my house.
- Which one is it?
- Over there.
- I couldn't cope with that one.
- If you can cope with an old ruin.
Why not with a decent house?
If you want to paint the eaves true to
life,
I've got some green paint left over.
- I simply couldn't.
If I don't like something,
there's no way I can paint it.
- He likes our old ruins, doesn't he?
- There're many things to my liking.
I'm not in charge of animals,
but paperwork.
I'm a personnel manager for livestock.
I've a file on each calf:
its family background,
what sort of stud its father was,
what sort of cow its mother was.
- It was not our idea.
If they want it, just fill it in.
- I've been wandering about it -
I see it's yours.
- Thanks, where did you find it?
- You'd better not ask.
- Let's see about the letter
and go home.
- Tell them to get stuffed -
it's nonsense.
- Let's hear from Rakosnik.
- That means staying here till midnight.
- Fetch him, please.
- Before she drags him
out of the cinema...
- How d'you know he's there?
This game is more cheaty
than the others.
- But, Mister, it was just fun,
I've found more clever game.
Wanna know which one?
How about playing humans
going for a sunday swim?
- But how they'll get to the riverside?
You won't tell us who it was?
- He knows nothing.
He was from Prague, wasn't he?
What did he tell you?
To go to work in Prague?
What else did he tell you?
- Fifty-seven.
- What d'you mean?
- Cinemas - they have.
- Listen, Otik -
would you like to go to Prague?
You don't like your village -
so small, so beautiful?
And the little house you were born in?
The won't let you keep you pigeons -
they shit on their statues.
You don't mind that?
Go now.
- Bye.
- You're making a big mistake -
you'll pay for it.
- What's that again?
- Putting used matches back
into the box.
- There's no doubt -
someone from Prague
wants Rakosnik's house.
I can tell you who -
this dauber sho's moved in there.
- D'you ever watch detective films
on TV?
- Yeah.
- I don't think so.
Otherwise you couldn't say such a thing.
This noted painter got here
after the letter.
I fixed him up at Otik's place.
It was completely my doing.
Why I did this is another story.
I think someone else wants the house.
Maybe he's among us here.
But you work it out yourselves.
- Thank you, Super, for your, analysis.
I suggest we reply the following:
Comrade Rakosnik is a moron.
He has to be supervised
by an experienced worker.
His mental make-up's not up to living
in town.
Also, he keeps pigeons,
which he couldn't in Prague.
Full stop.
- You can't write 'moron'.
I'd write 'half-wit'
- The doctor said
he was momentally backward.
- Mentally.
- Not bad - write it up.
C'mon, it's starting.
- Have they had the mirror yet?
- Not yet.
- I'll join you when the mirror
comes on.
- The American film Harpoon mirrors
that we offer you,
the bourgeois society
where the dollar's
the alpha and omega of life.
It was made
by Francis S. Jones in 1962.
Manhattan, 27th September.
- Watching?
So, I won't bother you.
I'll come later then.
- Come on in.
- Where's your sister's body - tell us!
- If I don't tell you, I can't sleep.
- Say it and you'll sleep.
- Could he leave, or shall we?
- Go and do some gluing.
He didn't want to watch anyway.
- Don't shoot until I tell you.
- They're meeting there - I saw them.
- Jana Turkovic?
- Yes, Jana Turkova.
- It's all over New York.
Photographs in the newspapers.
- If it gets back to Turek,
he'll kill her.
- Don't yell, idiot.
- Kaspar's a fool, too.
She's the mother of a young child.
- Where's Bradley?
Where is he?
He should've been here long ago.
- Don't wait for Bradley.
I'll take care of him.
- How long have they been at it?
- God knows.
- What's this got to do with his house?
- Of you no gotta dollars,
man, you're in trouble.
- Exactly.
I think
he wants to pack him off to Prague
to fornicate in his house.
Or -
he wants it for a friend from Prague
who's only spend the weekends here
and the mice could play during the week.
- This woman's stoned.
- I don't think so.
It was his suggestion
not to let him go.
- It's a cover-up.
- I'm sorry for the kid,
if it comes to light.
- Don't tell anybody!
- Like the tomb!
- They killed Bradley!
Hey, wait, Charlie!
He's been invited
by our comrade director.
Follow me, please.
Thanks, Karel, you're very kind.
You'll like it here.
Nothing to be afraid of.
All is managed.
Here's the personnel department.
But we'll go there later.
Let'go, there...
Good morning.
We'll go there afterwards.
Wait.
Well, go on.
Comrade director,
it's comrade Rakosnik -
the one with the house.
Will you take coffee or something
stronger?
- A vodka?
What?
- A roll.
- Welcome, comrade Rakosnik.
I hope...
...you'll like it here.
I'm pressed for time,
you'll have to see to it yourself.
- Sure.
- Want the car?
- Yes.
- Take the car!
- Yes, thank's.
- See you then.
- C'mon, Otik.
Good-bye.
- Bad habit, hand-shaking.
They've long given it up in the West.
No wonder we have epidemics of flu here.
A shower - that's something, eh?
Watch it now...
All right...
They haven't turned it on yet...
Cold water, hot water.
Now something you haven't seen yet.
It's no like in your place.
Wait till you see the kitchen:
hot and cold water, a sink,
an elektric or gas cooker...
C'mon, Otik.
A modern kitchen, what a marvel!
Otiku, Otiku,
C'mon then.
Come on.
This is...
Come here.
the latest fittings...
hot and cold water,
extractor fan...
electric cooker...
oven with grill!
What a height, eh?
What's the matter?
What?
Pigeons?
Plenty of them - in the Old Town Square.
It's not so bad, Frantisek.
- The moment he's better,
he'll smoke and drink again.
You should tell him not to.
He's more likely to listen to you.
- If he gave it up all at once,
it'd do no good.
The grave should receive
a decrepit body.
You'll cut down, eh?
A cuddly little thing, eh?
Very.
What's his name?
- He doesn't even have a name.
Dad found him at the railway station.
He adopted him and followed him
all the way home.
- That's a good doggy.
- If you like him, take him.
- I would't mind.
- Such a mongral?
- They're the best.
Come here.
An accident with the combine harvester -
they've run over Drapalik.
Have a look, doctor, what a sight!
He went uder the harvester -
- Yeah.
to have a look at the transmission box.
Turek backed into him...
We shouted:
"""There's a man there, you oaf!"","
but he rolled him over once more.
You must see it, doctor...
You will see something, let's go.
- Where's he?
- Here.
- What's your opinion, doctor?
- Stand up.
Walk about a bit.
- Surprised, eh?
- How steely our people are, eh?
- Impossible.
If you poured plaster into those,
he'd have a statue.
That'il do.
Bend over.
Does it hurt?
- No.
- And this?
What's so funny?
- It tickles.
- Look, go home and come back tomorrow.
Come.
Turn up the sleeve.
Hold this.
- Is it necessary?
- If it weren't,
I wouldn't be doing it.
You think I enjoy it?
You had a few, eh?
Keep still then.
All right, that's it.
What the hell's all this?
IMMORTAL DRAPALIK /PLASTER/
Keep shooting your mouths off
and we'll have the safety officer
breathing down our necks!
No beer out in the fields anymore!
Turek, is that clear?
- Sure.
- How come I was not called
in on the accident?
- I guess they didn't want
to wake you up -
if nothing actually happened.
- They say Turek was under
the influence.
You were suppposed to take a blood test.
- I did.
He was not under the influence.
He was lucky,
for I expect he'll lose his wife soon.
If he lost his licence -
that's be
too many blows at once.
- I've got my opinion of the matter.
- Suit yourself.
This is the surest sign of progress.
- What is?
- The tinker always came
this time of year -
from Slovakia.
Today - we have Stefan!
- Perhaps it will not be Stefan.
Maybe they'll send someone else.
- Hardly - but even if:
but even if:
it's a sure sign of progress.
- Can Stefan drink?
We've a bottle for him.
- You're crazy!
- He'll get plastered and do a spiral.
- Who did this?
You...
You lout!
- Let him go,
or I'll take you to pieces!
Let him be!
- Come off it!
- You me?
- Ouch, you oaf!
- Come off it, boys!
There's no point in it!
Calling yourselves cooperative farmers?
What is it?
- Stefan.
- Beat it, boys!
Stefan!
Hi, boys, how's life?
- Fine.
Reserved for redheands!
You can cover up adultery in town.
Not here.
Unfortunately.
- Does it affect the milk yield?
- What d'you mean?
- If not,
then it's my private business.
- It is and it isn't.
The morals of the village're
totally different.
- And what are they?
- Unspoilt.
- Aha.
Whose dog is it, doctor?
- Mine -
it was strandel at the railway station.
- A mixed bread, eh?
- What's its name?
- Lord Charles of the Railway Station.
You drinking?
That's all right then.
Leave it at that, or you'll be sick.
Going to live in Prague?
- When the harvest's over.
- You're a great guy.
I like you.
No.
Try that again and we'll have it out
in the backyard.
Don't pour the beer out the window!
Look at me now!
What fun,
pouring beer out the window!
Hi, Stefan.
You've a lovely face,
but I like your -
er, the bottom of your pan the best
- Aren't you a lecher, doctor!
- A pan's a frying utensil.
You should know that.
But the other one's lovely too.
D'you like being taken over by him?
- Your sister wrote the best dictation.
What?
- Red cabbage!
- I can't hear you!
- A cabbage head...
Thinks if he's an artist
he can mess around.
Tell him your foot hurts.
- What?
What?
- To tell him,
your leg aches!
He'll leave you alone, the scum.
- Her behaviour's excellent, too.
Much better than her brother's.
She doesn't say 'mess around'or acum'.
When he clears off,
you'll come crawling.
I may not be interested then.
- And she doesn't use blackmail.
I won it for you.
- How nice!
- Cherish it -
it cost me fifty-two crowns.
- Good evening, Mr. Kalina.
- Good evening.
My wife told me your son wants to go
to the naval college.
- He's set on it.
- Just say,
if you need a good word put in.
Our director could be quite helpful.
- That's be fine -
there seems to be a rush of applicants.
- Let's have a word with him
when he comes.
I discovered a house for him here, see?
- In our village?
- Rakosnik's place.
- Otik's?
- Otik.
- I see.
Where from?
- From Zvolen.
I got married here and settled down.
- Were Slovak girls no good?
- The usual story:
I did my National Service here.
No the marrying type, I got involved,
couldn't back put.
- He seems to have problems
with backing, eh?
- Not a good idea, that match.
It'll backfire one day.
- Take it easy.
All right?
Don't go to Prague, it's better here.
- I must, when the harvest's over.
- Why -
what's wrong with this place?
- Mr. Pavek said
when the harvest was over.
That's it!
Where you been?
- What's that to do with you?
- Shut up and come here!
- Boys - leave me in peace
on Sunday at least.
- No decent pub without a decent brawl!
No.
Have a drink, Vaclav.
- I'm afraid he'll do something to her.
- Looks like it.
You've two options now:
keep your hands off
or marry her.
You don't mind the patients urinating
into it?
- Have you had a divorce here?
- This achievement's got as far
as our village.
- How d'you go about it?
- An application is filed,
There's an application form.
- What about Vasek, er -
the engineer -
hope he won't lose his eye?
- You wouldn't like him one-eyed?
Take this to the police.
It says
how you hubby's knocked you about.
- Do I have to?
- Yeah.
Tell him I must speak to him.
- Which one?
- Turek.
He'll be supervised
by an experienced worker
He'll also be in the care
of the works doctor.
We hereby request you
to release him asap.
Hail Peace! Koutna.
- What's your opinion?
- I'll tell you something.
I'd let him go.
He himself wants to go.
Pavek's through with him.
We actually don't know
what to do with him.
I'd let him go.
- You'd let Otik...
...go to Prague?
- Let our Otik...
...go to Prague.
- Fancy them being so set
on this nitwit.
I don't get it.
I bet it's because of the house.
- Let's comme clean, comrades.
It is because of the house.
The director of METALWOOD likes it here.
We'd like to adapt his house
for recreational purposes.
- What did I say?
- I wouldn't be against it.
The farm'd benefit as well.
The'd help us -
with spare parts, he said.
That's the way I see it.
- You've not come completely clean,
have you?
There is some dirt, eh?
- I've told you what I know.
The house's involved,
there's no denying it.
- You told me the morality
of the village was different.
Unspoilt, eh?
Now you want to make a scapegoat
of a village simpleton.
Even as a city slicker,
I find it too strong a cuppa.
- He's right.
- No moralizing
from a destroyer of family life!
- He's right.
- Talk to the point.
It's Rakosnik we're discussing now!
I'm waiting for you to say
what's behind it,
so I don't have to stop recpecting you.
- Look at her!
You stop recpecting yourself!
- You're a miserable village bumkin!
- What did you say, comrade?
- You shouldn't take liberties
with the chairman.
- Vaclav, I ask you...
I told you so, Jaromir.
- I think I've burnt it.
- Show me.
Leave the room, women.
- Don't, auch!
- That's all right.
You're lucky - a near miss.
You will continue to function.
- You mean as an agronomist.
- That'll not be affected in the least.
The Alps overwhelm you, Charles.
But this here moves you.
Just look at it - see?
It's not a country, it's a garden.
If you have heart, you must feel it.
Go to hell with those chemicals.
A beautiful day, eh,
Charles?
The blue haze ascande
with the morning lark,
Till there,
on the breast of the blushing sky,
The carolling and the vapours die...
Over the still lake the mist doth away...
Messing about with in again, doctor?
- Come here!
My back's in two halves.
Jau.
Tell you something.
If you touch her again,
I won't be your friend anymore.
- She's still my wife.
- Sure, but you're not going...
But you're not gonna
knock her about!
Plump up the pillow for me.
Jau.
When you ran Drapalik over, d'you know
what level you had in your blood?
I'll tell them.
I'll be mean - make no mistake.
Hell, it hurts.
Forget driving then.
- She's a bitch.
- A pity there aren't shots
for jealousy.
I'd give you a horse dose.
Jau, je, joj.
The aftermath of the Brussels match
is clearly reflected
in the governmental crisis.
- Good Lord!
Karel! Ruzenka!
Come here!
C'mon, help me.
Ooj, jej.
- We need an ambulance.
Brug poisoning.
Pavek.
You're crazy!
- Hush!
The gear... the tube.
I'm a Lazarus.
Don't, you'll break me in two.
Karel, can you carry me?
- Yeah.
- Slowly!
Jej, jej.
- Careful.
- My slippers - dash!
- Wait!
- Where is he?
Over there.
- Help him.
- Get him here!
Jarda, c'mon!
So, what is it?
What did you gobble up?
- It's all right.
- What's all right?
- Medrin.
- Medrin? How many?
- Yeah, it has remained not much.
Can you hear me?
Who am I?
Look at me.
Well?
What're you mumbling?
What? Hallo!
- What?
Here they are.
Get up then!
- Come on.
- Where's he?
- I'm all right.
- Rot.
He gobbled up a little medrin.
- I'd...
- Cut it out, caveman.
Why, it's eased off.
You've put me right.
Look!
From the seventh?
- I don't drink from anywhere else.
- You've put up with him for years.
- That's it -
he's a life risk.
He'll say 1 word per 100 kilometres.
We're going to fetch cement
from Hradec Kralove.
In Beroun, he'll say: Beroun.
That's it -
he's done his bit.
I'll fall asleep at the wheel one day.
- But otherwise he's a grafter, eh?
- He loads the truck O.K.
I've trained him.
He's not reliable though.
Where're you off to?
- To a pond.
- Okay.
- He's mentally backward,
but no lunatic.
He's moving to Prague
because you don't want him.
You know that's the reason.
You're the only one who can stop him.
If someone's the only one who can,
he must do it.
- I said when the harvest was over.
The harvest is over.
Tomorrow's the last day.
I'm through.
Good morning, comrade director.
I think it's not bad...
- Quiet, Spot.
It's only some gentleman from Prague.
They're going to renovate the place.
Imported plastic thatching
from West Germany.
Tear down the W.C.
They'll put in a flush toilet.
What about the doorstep?
Concrete - that's it!
What about an English lawn?
Yes, we will have an english lawn.
A swimming pool to take 3 strokes in...
- Is it drinking water?
- It is.
Only now we have the mouth disease
around.
- Here we are...
We'll see you about the paperwork later.
Sold the house?
They delivered a new car -
trying it out.
Boys - it drives of its own accord!
The Cast
Production Staff
Assistant Film Editor
Microphone Operator
Photographer
Production Assistant
Assistants to Production Manager
Assistant to director of Photography
Assistant Cameraman
Continuity
Assistant Director
Il. Assistant Director
Assistant Art Director
Set Design
Costume Design
Wardrobe
Make-up
Music by
Played by
Conducted by
Sound Recordist
Film Editor
Art Director
Production
director of Photography
Directed by
Produced at
Production manager
Distribution copis made at
THE END